Fārūq, this is a nice one.
Wow. Look at this!
Good evening. Reservations?
Move your little hands.
Do your job. Thanks.
Good. I've given you
a nice discount, okay?
The acrobatic pizza king!
No little acrobatic games.
I'm watching you.
Mom.
I have a live show tonight.
What if I…
I say your dad's right.
You're untrustworthy.
-Here. Don't let your dad see you!
-Thanks.
WRIT OF EXECUTION
PRECAUTIONARY SEIZURE
Sweetheart.
Okay. I'll tell him.
No worries at all.
Tomorrow, make her
a wire transfer of 3,000 euros.
3,000 euros?!
What has she done?
She's late with her rent, poor girl.
The Dutch are strict.
Look at this.
A little black dress. Chic.
A classic. Do you like it?
Honey, we're going to an exclusive place.
We need to stand out.
Come on. Raise the bar.
My goodness. What is it the Oscars night?
I thought it was a birthday.
It isn't just a birthday.
Dario's also become a manager.
There. Precisely.
A 1,700-euro watch
sounds very oafish to me.
You'll embarrass people.
Not this again? It's an investment.
I give him a big present,
and he does us
a big favor on our mortgage.
Yes?
Tell me.
A lawyer?
Which lawyer?
No. It's not me.
No. I don't know any Rosario.
Okay, it's me. I'm Rosario. What's up?
You've become a lawyer? I'm happy for you.
Tell me.
When did it happen?
No. I'm not interested in the inheritance.
Bye.
Who was it?
A call center.
You're emotional
because a call center called.
No, it's… the menthol shaving cream.
Yeah.
I knew it.
-I'm going home and changing.
-Honey, don't exaggerate.
You're making it bigger than it is.
Nobody looks at our clothes.
Where's the restroom?
We've just…
Usually, it's at the far right.
Thanks.
See? You should be friendly too
and make new friends. Let's go.
Come on.
What's wrong? Shall I drag you?
I am a guest.
Darione! Great to see you.
-Ramona, let me hug you.
-Hi.
Dario. Listen.
I could use a little breathing space.
I've received a writ of execution.
Now that
you are a manager,
you could stop it, right?
No, because the head office
has confirmed the securitization.
-Meaning?
-Meaning that…
The most I can do is give you two weeks,
but if you don't cover at least 25%
of mortgage arrears,
then it's bye to Gelso.
But that's 50,000 euros.
I know, but I told you
not to buy the space next door.
-Dario.
-Hey there.
-Listen, Dario.
-Yeah.
-Can you not say anything to Teresa?
-Okay.
-Don't worry. Come on.
-Thanks.
Excuse me? Some Prosecco, please?
Not this again…
Olé!
A mug with a skull!
I really wanted it. It's too cool.
-Olé!
-You're crazy. You are!
I love them.
Attention. "Happy birthday,
Dario, from Salvo and Teresa."
Thank you.
Olé!
Did he buy him a watch?
-It's not real. Is it?
-A watch?
Come on.
-Not at all. Are you joking? It's a fake.
-It's fake.
I really thought he went for
a kitschy, Southern-style gift.
-It looks fucking real though.
-Well, yeah.
-It looks real to me.
-What the fuck are you saying?
Can't you tell it's a fake? If you throw
it in the sangria, it won't even float.
You're crazy!
What's here?
I am not the waiter--
Attention. No card here.
Olé!
Put it away.
Put it away. Take it.
Olé!
Good morning.
You got up early this morning.
Yeah.
-Early start.
-And how was last night?
Good. We worked our ass off, but…
-Good.
-Good boy.
-Thanks.
-I know Fārūq did everything, you fool.
Who did you take after?
Your sister never lied to me. Never.
-Are you sure?
-Did she tell you she's feeling down?
That's why I want to go and see her.
Now you worry about your sister.
I have to…
-I have to give a demo to a label.
-Who's this?
A label means a record label.
They're not replying to my emails,
so I wanna go there and bring my tracks.
Look how proactive he can be
when it comes to playing
the deejay.
Producer sound designer.
You're opening today.
Tidy up your thoughts, Freddy Mercury.
Freddy Mercury's got
jack shit to do with it.
-You don't even know what music I play.
-Do you call that music?
Oh my goodness, this sucks.
You twist and turn and pull the blankets.
A bed is made for sleeping.
-Not just for sleeping.
-Get off, will you?
If you don't want to treat insomnia,
do whatever you want.
Go out. Go for a walk.
Take the usual walk. As long as you go.
So at least one of us will sleep.
God willing.
Have you tried sleeping pills?
That's for bumpkins.
I solve problems without any help.
But if La Zia is still there,
it means you could do with a little help.
A good debt always drives away a bad one.
It's the trap of neoliberalism.
Too much culture is bad for you.
So.
So you know the conditions.
Increased by 10% since this time,
the amount is pretty high.
Do we have to do this?
Don't lean on that. You're a jinx.
Darione! Big news!
We have the 50,000 euros,
but you'll let me defer the rest, right?
Talk soon. See you tomorrow.
I'll drop by tomorrow.
I knew you wouldn't have come
to my funeral.
You are a dissolute son.
Everyone was there.
Even Uncle Cicco from Canicattì
was there, and he's 95! You weren't.
Well done.
Where are we?
It's a hiatus, which separates us
from the living and the dead.
And since when do you use
words such as "hiatus"
when the most difficult word you used
when alive was sausage?
Help me unload the tractor, or will you
just stand there and look pretty?
Salvo, stop! Thank you.
Pretend I have accepted your help.
Stop it. I'll take care.
You're a useless thing. Useless.
Why don't you give me lotto numbers
and save me
from this postmortem lecturing?
Remember one thing. I came in peace,
and you're upsetting me
even now that I'm dead.
Do you know that saying?
"Blessed is the bird
who builds its nest in its own village."
I leave you with that.
Don't worry.
You've only got a few bruises.
I'll discharge you
as soon as the report's ready.
By the way, looking at your scooter,
you've been blessed by a miracle.
-Someone up there must love you.
-Curse me, more than anything.
From the hiatus.
You seem to be a little stressed out,
Mr. Macaluso. I suggest you get some rest.
-See you later.
-Thank you, Doctor.
What happened?
-My father has died.
-No!
Honey, I am so sorry,
but when did it happen?
-Help me get down. I want to take a walk.
-Yes, come on. Easy.
Listen. Is there anything that…
Some water?
-No, a plum cake.
-You idiot. Hop off.
What a villain.
Instead of giving me lotto numbers,
he told me about
an old Sicilian saying, Verga style.
He who could hardly read a shampoo label.
Which saying?
Like, "The happy bird makes its nest
in its own village." Something like that.
Well, it's a very clear sign
that you must go down south.
You wanna be like rednecks
who believe in this crap?
Come on. Give me a coin.
I'll get a coffee.
You're his only child.
He deserves a farewell.
Don't be a shithead as usual. Come on.
-How does this work?
-Up. That's for coins. Here.
He said I'm a useless thing.
So, keep calm. Stay cool.
Didn't you hear what the doctor said?
You're stressed out, okay?
Why don't you go down south a few days?
Say your last farewell to your dad, rest…
-It'd be good for you. You can relax.
-Don't you dare. I'm not going back there.
And I am not…
I'm not…
I am not stressed out!
What's your problem?!
Dad hasn't been sleeping
since things have gone bad at work.
-So he nags me at night too.
-I told him not to expand his business.
Mom gives in to him all the time. Always.
I can't wait to move out, honestly.
A friend of mine will have
a room available soon.
Enzo, it's been three years that
your friend's meant to have a free room.
It's now available.
Anyway, how did it go
with that record label?
-Good.
-Did they listen to your demo?
Yes. They said they'll let me know soon.
Why didn't you give it to them?
I knew it already.
Enzo, why don't you tell me things?
I'm not Dad.
-You can talk to me.
-You're worse.
-He doesn't rummage in my pockets.
-You asked for money for this trip.
And you haven't got the guts
to go and give a fucking envelope?
I come to see you to get a break,
and I get a lecture here too?
You love lectures, Enzo.
You love being the baby of the family.
Otherwise, look, keep staying
in your nice little bedroom,
with the Dragon Ball poster on the wall,
moaning all day long
about wanting to move out,
and nobody will say anything.
I've got an idea. Let's get up,
walk in that coffee shop,
and smoke a big joint,
so you can chill a bit, okay?
-See how you are?
-Seriously, Emma.
I mean it. So you can chill
and stop criticizing.
If I may, it's easy
to criticize from here.
Who's the one home with Dad in Milan? Me.
Are you coming?
Whatever. I'm going.
Moro speaking from Via Venezia, 26 red…
POLICE
Okay, copy that.
We're arriving at the police station
with the loan shark from Via Sala Bar.
We're leaving now.
Received.
-I bet you're from here.
-You lost the bet. I'm from Milan.
I'm here on business.
-I have a cousin in Milan who owns a bar.
-Could you look ahead, please?
You know, it was a dump. Then he expanded,
and my cousin has made real money.
Look ahead now, please!
What a bad temper.
Lillo! Is that really you?
You've grown a lot.
Have you been eating wild boars?
Come give me a hug.
Rosario called me.
My goodness, what a tragedy.
That was so unexpected.
A real blow.
He mentioned inheritance,
as if I am interested in that.
But how much would we inherit exactly?
How much?
I mean, not that I…
am interested.
Thank you for the warm welcome.
-Where are you running to, Napoli?
-Napoli, come here!
Where are you going? Come here.
Where are you going?
-What do you do now?
-You can't run away now.
Where did you want to go?
-What did you want to do?
-Neapolitan, you can't run now.
I'd spit in your mouth.
-Yes?
-Rosario, it's Salvo.
Mazzacana!
Here it is.
-Why are you touching it?
-You were giving it, and I was taking it.
I mean, clearly,
that's what you were doing.
Are you putting it away? You called me.
I've traveled 2,000 kilometers.
I came from Milan.
-Your brother needs to be here too.
-He's not even talking to me.
I get it, but we can't do it otherwise.
Do you remember when we were kids?
Those two waiting for you
outside the school because they wanted
to beat you up?
Just because you were
the smartest in the class.
But I cared about you.
And if you are where you are today,
I'm not saying you owe me a bit.
No, I don't, but...
It won't leave this room. It won't.
So.
"Last will."
"I, the undersigned, Nunzio Macaluso,
being of sound mind,
appoint my sons, Calogero and Salvatore,
co-heirs of the family home
and its attached plots."
"Yours sincerely, Nunzio Macaluso."
Well, I can sell and monetize.
By the way, this reminds me
that the mayor would like to welcome you.
Don't tell me it's still Beppe Randazzo?
No way. It's his son.
Mimmo U' Catarrusu. I used to beat him up
one day yes and the other one too.
See, I ask about you.
I've done my research and was told
that you make the best pizza in Milan.
The best in Lombardy.
Your father, how is he?
He passed away.
-Really? I'm sorry.
-Yes.
Sure, he's with Nunzio.
He cared about your dad.
Because he was the only one who supported
him in that damned business with snails.
Do you remember? The snails business.
You did some bullshit, Dad.
Listen up.
I wanted to meet with you because…
Salvo, let's be clear.
I'm interested in your family house.
-What's wrong with that?
-Nothing wrong. I want to retire there.
And I also want
to make peace with the ecosystem.
Good.
So I thought about an amount,
which I might be embarrassed to say.
Salvo,
considering its abandoned state,
the unbuildable state of the lot,
and the devaluation
of the very old property,
this is my figure.
-Salvuccio.
-It's--
What do you think?
I mean, it sounds good. I don't know…
-Salvo.
-It can be done.
-Tell me where to sign.
-Slow down.
There's one little thing. Very little…
What little thing?
Salvuccio, you need to convince
your brother to give up his share too.
A piece of cake.
A piece of cake? When was the last time
you saw your brother?
No. Keep this.
It helps lubricate the gears.
My love. All good. I'll tell you later.
I was right.
I knew I had to come back down south.
-Salvo!
-No. Sure.
-But I called. The line's always busy.
-Salvo.
-Or there's no connection. I don't know…
-Is that you?
Is that you? Sa'!
Salvo, dude!
No, they're not robbing me.
They're old friends.
Honey, I'll call you later
when I have more time.
-Salvo, come on.
-Bye.
The new Aci Fontana Stadium, Salvo,
with 15,000 covered seating.
You won't get 15,000 people
even if you invite the whole province.
The president promised
to take us to Serie B in three years.
He's a builder
and lives in Milan, like you.
-Maybe you know him too.
-Of course I do!
Three million people, and I know them all.
What the hell, Castagna?
-Take it easy.
-He's right.
Let's show respect
to the Schillaci of pizza.
He's made some good money up there!
Don Angelo, another round
on the uncle from America!
-You still like her, right?
-Excuse me.
Salvo, where are you going? Salvo!
Pussy is pussy.
-Good morning.
So, Bettina, what are we doing?
My usual. Brazilian waxing.
He doesn't want to go,
then he buys the ticket.
Then he doesn't want to go anymore.
Then he packs last minute
and nearly misses his flight.
Teresa, you don't have to be so paranoid.
If a man wants to cheat on you,
he'll do it anyway.
And if you want to get hurt,
go and rummage in his bedside table.
Yeah. His bedside table.
Yeah, that's ingenious. They put it
under your nose where you'll never look.
And if you find out, they say,
"You think if I wanted to hide something,
I'd put it in the bedside table?"
Breathe in the scent of salt. Breathe in.
Breathe in.
Hey.
Enzo.
-How did it go?
-No one knocks in this house.
-Did you give them your demo?
-Yes. I did.
-Good. You must be happy.
-Yes, I'm happy.
Listen, I was just curious,
if you had to hide something,
where would you put it?
-What do you need to hide?
-Forget about "what."
If you have to hide it,
without thinking, where would you put it?
I don't know, Mom,
in the bedside table?
"I'm waiting for you, Carme'."
"Carme',
with your hand, you messed up my head."
"You messed up my heart too."
"My heart burns and steals my thoughts,
then it moves away and goes down…"
I'm gonna kill you, you son of a bitch.
-The number you have di…
-Fuck you.
You're awake?
I thought that you farmers
went to bed with the sun.
You don't talk to me
because you're angry with me?
I've invited you to Milan many times,
but you never came.
You're leaving me
in the disused part of the house?
You're taking the bathroom, and if I need
to pee, do I do it in the fireplace?
Why don't we talk about
the mayor's proposal?
Hey, look at this. Look.
Let's lubricate your rusty gears.
Check this out.
Screw this.
See, I managed to make you talk.
Lillo?
Do not enter my part of the house.
I have a pizzeria in Milan
and I am drowning in debt.
I need that money.
Do you want me to go broke?
Where were you when Dad went broke?
I was here, among snails
and promissory notes,
while you were enjoying
your nice pizzeria up north!
You didn't even come to the funeral, Cain!
Are you playing the jaw harp?
Can you play me "Wish You Were Here"?
Salvo.
Do you know who he is?
It's Mazzacana.
Mazzacana!
If he finds out that you stole his shoes,
he'll kill you.
No, he can't find out.
Lillo? Can you see the pizzeria?
They opened it last week.
People come here from Aci Fontana.
They must be making a lot of money.
Look at that. It never ends!
Close your eyes and make a wish.
Can you teach me how to make pizza?
Of course, I will.
Do you think I'd leave you here
slaving with Dad and his snails?
I can't work alone in our pizzeria, can I?
Can you see the damage these snails do?
With those antennas, they move big stones
-Swear.
-I swear.
Do we have to do this?
Give me your hand.
Son of a bitch!
Selling our family's house
is a sacrifice for me too,
but I have to protect my pizzeria.
Actually, you said
we'd open the pizzeria together.
What did you call it?
Sciuri Sciuri.
That's original.
Dad's will is for us to scatter his ashes.
If we don't do it,
the house won't be ours.
Easy. Get them and we'll scatter them.
Plenty of room here.
He said we should do it
with this and with this.
On top of the mountain,
and when the wind is mungibiddisi.
Is he giving orders even when dead?
What does he care
if the wind is or isn't mungibiddisi?
And your family must be present too.
But he's never even met them!
That's what he said.
I have no family anymore, Lillo.
My wife left me, and she took my house.
I swap alimony
with vouchers at the pizzeria.
I basically live and sleep there.
My son
got lost in music and drugs.
Crack, purple, Special K,
CBD, THC, TNT,
and my wife says it's all my fault.
My daughter ran away and she's missing.
-And my wife--
-Says it's your fault.
You haven't changed, Salvo.
Lillo.
Okay. Let's see now.
Did you say "sell"?
I said "see."
How long has it been since you washed?
Since you haven't let me
use your bathroom.
Shall we go and scatter the ashes
on the top of the mountain?
Can't you see the wind isn't mungibiddisi?
-Tomorrow.
I love you, Lillo.
Salvo.
Do you know what Geronimo said?
That you can't give in.
You must fight.
Until you're the last.
Have you ever seen Dad cry?
He doesn't have a heart.
Damn slimesucker.
What's this?
Here's the tree.
We place the tables near the oven,
and in the summer, we install a pergola.
I like it.
But the name sucks.
Il Gelso?
We need something more original.
Sciuri Sciuri.
I don't like Sciuri Sciuri.
Shouldn't the majority decide?
Yeah, the majority.
But I'm the eldest.
-The number you have…
-I don't know why he doesn't pick up.
Ma'am, even if he answers,
I'll have to put the locks on.
-The pizzeria is going on auction--
-What auction?
-You never gave us a warning.
-Not even the army can drag me out!
Come on, guys. Don't you start too.
Be good, guys.
Now open the locks and we'll go. Okay?
Come on.
-What?
-The key.
-The key--
-I ate it.
-We're done.
-Ma'am, have a good day.
-Goodbye.
Mom.
What's happening?
Sweetheart, what are you doing here?
Are you sure all the money
from the auction goes to the bank?
Yes. Anyway, we couldn't buy it back.
I mean, we're not allowed at the auction.
Good.
Get rid of that stupid face.
Who are you, and mainly, what do you want?
Nice to meet you. I'm Alfonsino,
but everybody calls me Fofò.
You're a master to me.
I made a cover of your song
and launched it on the Internet.
-I wanted you to hear it.
-What makes you think I'm interested?
Come on. Piss off.
Redneck, go back home.
Wait.
I'll listen to it.
Only if you let me make a phone call.
Swear.
I swear.
I'M WAITING FOR YOU, CARME'
I miss you tonight…
So? What do you think?
That you gotta get your ass kicked a lot
before you can do something good.
-Too bad that I have almost 5,000 views.
-What?
-5,000 views.
-I mean…
You're trying to find long-term success
off of someone else's career?
What are you talking about?
I only made this song.
Wind is mungibiddisi.
-Good.
-We can go.
I'll get the stick and we'll go.
Fofò. Get lost. We gotta do
something important.
What are you doing here?
Emma.
-You're here too? Why?
-Thanks to you, they kicked me out, Dad.
What's it got to do with me?
I'll call the bank
and they'll remember
my sermon till Christmas…
Pray to God you have a valid reason
why this fucking phone is always off.
Did you want to leave me in the shit?
Do you know they seized Il Gelso?
Jackass!
-What do you think you'll do now?
-Teresa, can't you let me explain? I mean…
It's the trap of neoliberalism.
It's a thing…
While we're at it!
Please, tell me who this whore is?
Hey, watch your tongue. That's my mom.
-Carmela is your mom?
-You have an illegitimate son too?
-No.
-And didn't say anything?
What the-- Ouch!
-Are you crazy?
-You hid it in the bedside table!
I'll kill you.
I'll take your life away. I swear to God!
Bloody hell, Teresa. It's just a song!
There's nothing wrong with it!
I wouldn't hide
it in the bedside table otherwise!
I knew you'd say that, coward!
Enzo.
Talk some sense into your mother.
Please, help me.
You used to sing Sceneggiate Napoletane,
with that hairdo,
and you criticize my music?
Tidy up your thoughts.
Guys, let's go find a hotel.
Enough. Let's go.
Salvo. You found your missing daughter,
and you didn't tell me?
It's wonderful. We should celebrate.
And who's this young man?
Your son,
the drug addict, DBC, THC, SPA…
The lady, of course…
She's your wife, isn't she?
The one who divorced you
and left you broke.
Excuse the interference. I'm Lillo.
Salvo's brother.
-His…
-Your brother, Dad?
You have a brother?
Yes, but he didn't tell you
because I don't exist for him.
Hi, pleased to meet you.
I'm Teresa, Salvo's ex-wife.
Hi Lillo. Have you seen Fofò?
I don't know where to look anymore.
Yes, he's here.
Look who came to see me, Salvo's family.
-Salvo.
-She's Teresa, my sister-in-law.
Nice to meet you. Carmela.
Salvo. My God, it's been ages!
Hello.
-I'm sorry about your dad.
-These things happen.
Carmela is a nice person.
She raised her son alone in Naples.
-Nice to meet you. Carmela.
-Fofò's father was an asshole.
He abandoned her when she was…
-And she came back here about a year ago.
-Okay.
Let's go home to do your homework
or I'll break your neck.
-Mom, let's stay here.
-Why?
I promised Enzo I'll show him
the video clip of Salvo's original song.
-That video clip…
-Still around.
I'd be glad if you stayed.
Yeah, so you can tell us some things.
Dad told us nothing about you.
-He didn't even tell us he had a brother.
-You didn't?
-No.
-Maybe he wanted to surprise us.
I don't like talking about myself.
I'm not that self-centered.
Okay, then.
Stay here, everyone. Refresh yourselves.
-We'll eat something. No hotels, Teresa.
-Thanks.
-There's room for everyone in this house.
-Thank you so much.
-I'll deal with you later.
-The luggage.
-You can leave it. No thieves here.
-Okay.
When I said everyone,
I meant everyone but you.
Stay in your part of the house.
Dad, if there are any leftovers,
I'll make you a doggy bag.
Be my guests.
Stay all squeezed like sardines
while I enjoy my entire space for myself.
In harmony with nature.
What the fuck do you want? Hey!
No way.
Oh my God.
I miss you tonight…
He's really into it. Marvelous.
See how good he is?
This can't be real.
-Anyway, the song is nice.
-Yes, it's nice.
-Not exactly joyful, let's say.
-There she is.
-You were beautiful.
-Thanks. I had long hair…
Your brother is shocked. Look.
-And I lay awake…
-I feel emotional.
-Here comes the instrumental bit.
-Thank God.
A bit of a break from your dad singing.
I miss you
Carmela--
You need to show pain. That's not enough.
I miss you, Carmela, tonight
What an awful thing.
I miss you tonight
You, Christmas Star
And I lay awake, Carmela
But for you, I'm a betrayal
An enemy during war
I'm a door that you lock
Carmela
When he heard that I was in Naples,
he moved there, using pizza as an excuse.
And he insisted on making this video.
I didn't mind the song, so I said yes.
I don't know, maybe because of this,
he deluded himself a bit.
Let's say it was a kind
of unrequited love.
But then this song was a flop.
-Really?
-Strange, really.
So then, he went to Milan,
and I never saw him again.
Alfonsino's been listening to it
since he was little.
Sweetheart, I'm sorry.
When I was younger,
I thought Salvo was my dad.
Consider yourself lucky he isn't.
You died without any bell ringing
And trallaleru lalleru lalleru lalleru
Lalleru lalleru lallà
-Two more beers, Don Angelo.
-Yes.
Thanks.
Your father was a good man.
Then he was caught by the evil eye.
And his path crossed
with some really mean people.
Who are these very mean people?
Ask your brother.
I also know
that he once went to Milan,
but he didn't have the guts
to go to your pizzeria.
Salvo.
Lallaleru lalleru lalleru
Lalleru lalleru lallà!
"Carme',
with your hand, you messed up my head,
which burns and steals my thoughts."
"Then it moves away and goes down."
"It doesn't know
whether to beat or sing anymore."
"I have no voice now, Carme'."
"All I have left of you
is the spring, a big breath,
a jump from the sky."
-It's awful.
-Beautiful.
It'll be hell divorcing at my age.
Dad, why didn't you tell her
you were risking seizure?
I tried,
but she always has something to do.
-Sugar?
-No. Bitter like life.
To me, you're a betrayal
An enemy during…
Night.
You're a door opening
Carmela
Finished.
That's enough.
So, I'll explain it once more. I write
to the bank and ask for new installments.
While Dad calls Dario
and pledges to give 50,000 in arrears,
mortgaging our house in Milan.
This is the only way to stop the auction.
No, honey, you can forget about it.
Half of the house's mine.
Without my signature, he can do nothing.
Calm down. There are always two options.
-One is this.
-And the other one?
I inherited half of the family house.
The mayor fell in love with this place
and wants to retire here.
I worked hard on him,
and I got a huge figure.
I almost convinced Lillo to sell.
But then you arrived,
and everything has gone to hell.
-You nearly convinced him?
-I opened up his heart.
You go and talk to that grumpy man.
Shall we take a step at a time? Shall we?
The mayor has given me till San Procopio.
Little step? We need an elephant step.
Exactly. Thus, you have to apologize.
What for?
For crossing him out,
stealing his name for the pizzeria
and the idea of the pizzeria.
Shall I go on?
I refuse to regress to adolescence
because my brother's stuck there
and my wife dropped to his level.
Look, you know what? Do as you please.
-You're leaving already?
-We made some progress since this morning.
Five minutes ago we were about to divorce.
You didn't even teach
that poor man how to make pizza.
Did he tell you
all my fucking business in just one night?
Come on, Dad. It's easy. Repeat after me,
"I wanted to say I'm sorry."
Listen, Lillo.
I wanted to say… You know that
with the money from the house,
you could reopen the pizzeria?
Go on. Roll the dough.
You want to teach me
how to make pizza now after 40 years?
Jeez, you're so fussy!
Come on. Come here.
Do what I do.
Widen the dough, thoroughly, okay?
Then with your fingertips…
Loosen up, soft on your legs. That's it.
See, you're good at it.
You're a born pizza maker.
I'll give you the franchise.
Il Gelso 2.
It would be like realizing
our old project from afar.
-From 1,500 kilometers?
-Jeez! You're still so fussy.
All right, you are Il Gelso,
and I'll be Il Gelso 2.
Lay the tomato.
Add a bit of basil,
a handful of mozzarella,
then you add a bit of olive oil,
if you like. Now you try.
Now take a handful of mozzarella.
-Put it on, that's too much, but…
-I'll put it on the edges.
-You'll eat this one.
-What's wrong with it?
Take the peel. Wait. It's not--
Come closer. Well done.
Perfect. Let's make a calzone with this,
which is better.
Let's make a calzone.
This is yours. Put it in the oven.
I had a look, and there are only
a few competitors in such a wide area.
-Who?
-"Competitor."
She got a master's degree in economics
and now she speaks like this.
-I mean, there isn't a pizzeria nearby?
-Tell me about it.
To eat a pizza with Fofò,
I end up spending more on gas.
Because there are no competitors.
And as a business administrator,
you know about this…
Who wants a beer?
Wait. Give it one more minute.
Mozzarella took off its clothes
And a hug melts into your chest
And you forget all your suffering!
Lillo helped me too.
A round of applause for Lillo.
Wow, Uncle.
Some guys have all the luck.
A little trim maybe…
I'd like to make a toast.
I drink to you,
long-lost brother,
in the hope of becoming business partners
at a distance.
-He made a rhyme.
-Of course. Without it, it's not a toast.
-Cheers.
-Cheers, sweetheart.
To this family.
So,
tomorrow, we fulfill
our old man's will
on the top of the hill,
all together, okay?
All together.
-Enjoy your meal, or it'll get cold.
-Enjoy your meal.
Damn. Where is he?
This farce will never end.
-Did you apologize to him?
-Sure.
I mean, I didn't use those exact words.
-But it was implied.
-Because you are still shitty like always.
Oh well. That's an improvement.
From shithead to shitty.
-Now it's my fault, is it?
-It's not mine.
Grandpa, this is Enzo.
Enzo, this is Grandpa.
Here. Do something.
Lillo!
Lillo. We're waiting for you.
Impressive how much our uncle reads.
I've always said too much culture is bad.
Maybe he's there already?
He always gets up at dawn.
Blessed is he who sleeps. Let's go.
I miss you tonight
Indiana Jones, are you sure?
You asking me every two minutes isn't fun!
Are you sure?
My dear, I grew up here.
This way.
Okay. If he grew up here…
I didn't think it was so urgent.
You should have explained it better.
-If you hide things from me…
-I remind you, you hid your brother.
You didn't ask me
if I had a brother, did you?
Did you ask me
if I quit my master's studies?
-No, I didn't.
-Exactly.
-What the fuck did you do?
-Why do you act like this?
You intimidate me. I was opening up
with you. I won't talk to you anymore.
Is there more?
It's a boar. I know it's a boar!
But it's Lillo.
Lillo, where are you going? It's us.
Thank God the head
of the family's protecting us.
I was watching your back.
Let's follow him. Come on.
He's playing cowboys
and Indians, silly man. Lillo!
Lillo!
Little brother, I saw you.
Come out.
I know that you want me to sweat for it.
That's fine, but a prank isn't funny
if it goes on for too long.
I didn't forget. You stole my shoes.
Mazzacana.
Have you been barefoot for 40 years?
-Good afternoon.
-Hello.
-Did you really steal his shoes?
-He's confusing me with your uncle.
How will you manage without shoes now?
He managed for 40 years.
I will make it for 40 minutes.
See?
Lillo?
-I miss you, Uncle Lillo
-Uncle?
Lillo?
See?
I added a stage too.
So you can sing Neapolitan songs,
how you like it.
Good idea. And we could also host
Communions, confirmations, weddings…
And give me this poison
Don't wait until tomorrow
Regardless
Whether you kill me or not
I won't tell you anything
Wow! This pizza is delicious!
Can I order one more?
I'll give you a nice "pizza" in your face.
How is this then?
I work hard, spitting blood,
and you're here dicking around?
What's this?
Pizzeria
Il Gelso.
Whose idea is this? Yours?
You just say it to protect your brother,
aka "useless thing."
Salvo, I tell you something,
and write it here.
"He who lives upon hope
will die fasting."
Tonight you'll suck snails' slime.
And with this…
With this,
you can wipe your ass!
The engineer.
We have an engineer at home, an architect,
a singer. "And give me this poison."
He wants to do everything!
Get to work!
What's that, a treasure map?
Hey, Dad.
Don't blame yourself.
Some years ago,
I also wrote on the wall in the cellar,
"Salvo, shit pizza."
Little brother,
see how I fulfill our old man's wishes!
Now, slimesucker, you're free to nag
all the microfauna you'll meet.
I knew I shouldn't have come back
to this shitty place.
When was the last time you slept?
A whole life criticizing your dad,
then you do the same things.
Proud, touchy.
Constantly dwelling on the past.
-You know what my mom used to say?
-What?
"If you walk looking back,
you'll bang your head."
Luckily, I listened to her.
Or else I'd still be in Naples
getting abused by Fofò's father.
I'm glad you listened to her,
or you wouldn't be here.
Then you should listen to her too.
That's why I decided to go "all in."
"All in"?
What's that, like "coming out"?
-Jeez, I didn't know.
-What are you talking about?
-That's why you get waxed. You're gay!
-What are you saying?
What nice news.
Cut it out, Carmela.
"All in" is a poker thing,
when you risk all you have.
If you lose, you're screwed,
but if you win, you really win.
If I don't do it now,
I won't ever be able to.
Well done, Lillo. Thank God.
Once in a while, a bit of bravery
in life is good for you.
What are those?
Who knows. Since I've been back,
nearly every morning,
I find one outside the door.
-Why don't you open them?
-No.
I'll open them when whoever leaves them
has the guts to show himself.
Come on.
On the count of three. One,
two!
-Didn't you say three?
-I forgot.
Do you know what your son calls me?
"Shit pizza."
Really?
Did you know that?
You too?
I'm sorry. Could you stop a moment?
I'd like to tell you something.
Me too.
I miss you, Carmela
Caress me
-Dad!
-No! What are you doing?
-Stop it! Let go of him!
Have you gone mad?
He's taking the piss.
You think I have an illegitimate son.
She quit her master's,
and I'm the one who's gone mad?
You're all with Lillo.
You brought me here
to make me dwell on my past.
Bravo. Always blaming others!
Gosh.
Did you quit your master's?
Sorry, Lillo.
Can I ask you
how did your brother convince you?
Sure.
Beautiful.
Emma! It's not that way.
It's this way. We're almost there!
You'll have to find your way back!
I won't call the forest ranger!
I'm going!
Bye!
You too? But I'm barefoot.
I'm going!
Did you see Mazzacana?
Where were you?
We've been looking for you all day.
The wind isn't mungibiddisi.
I went for a walk.
But what's this wind blowing mungibuddisi?
Wind is mungibiddisi when it's
a wind coming from the mountain.
A wind that gets into your bones,
a wind of change.
Are you playing games with me?
Did you plan everything
so that I'd find it there? Did you?
Dad ripped this up
because he didn't want to admit
that you were right and the idea was good.
Then he patched it up.
Because he hoped you'd come back.
And I buried it.
Let's go and fetch some oil.
Will you cut some bread?
Snails ate Dad up.
He asked Peppu Sinnaco for money.
And that bastard usurer
took advantage of that.
Here. Try it.
Dad was proud of you.
His pride zipped his mouth.
And I trusted you.
Does your ass hurt?
Shut up.
Idiot. You're lucky
I'm the only one who gets blamed.
-Shall we write him a few words, Salvo?
-Write what?
"Dear Father,
without 'dear'."
"We ran away because any other place
is better than here."
"But don't worry, the belts you gave us
will be paid back with interest."
He took all the gas.
Damn slimesucker. Lillo, let's go.
Lillo! Let's go!
I wrote to Dad, also on your behalf,
that he shouldn't be angry with us,
and that we'll come back when we're rich.
Salvo, are you sure
it's the right night to run away?
Are you shitting yourself?
If you say you wanna do something,
you gotta go till the end.
You said it, didn't you?
Lillo!
-Salvo, help me!
-Lillo, did you hurt yourself?
-Help me!
-Lillo! Salvo!
-How am I gonna get you out of there?
-Help me!
-Come here.
-I can't reach it!
-Come! Jump!
-You come down here.
No, I can't come down in the hole.
We'll both be stuck! Jump. Find a way.
-Salvo! Lillo!
-Almost there.
-Is it you two?
-Reach down.
Lillo, quick! Your hand, quick!
Where are you going?
-Give me your hand!
-I can't reach!
-Your hand, quick, Lillo. He's coming.
-Come down. Lift me up.
Lillo. I fought.
-No, Salvo.
-I'm the last one standing.
-If I catch you! I'll deal with you later!
-I'm sorry. I swear.
-I'll be in touch.
-No, Salvo! Don't leave me! Salvo!
Salvo.
The night we ran away,
I knew you fell in the hole on purpose.
You didn't want to leave.
You hoped the old man would catch us,
so I couldn't run away either.
This is what you tell yourself.
The truth is you abandoned me.
-You threw me like an anchor with no rope.
-Are you saying I betrayed you?
You are just jealous.
It's not my fault
if your life went the way it did.
But now that you can change it,
only because I'll gain something,
you cling to everything to avoid selling.
Why are you saying this?
-I went to the mayor's and signed.
-I'm telling--
The cards are on the table.
Now it's your turn.
My dear Salvo, you have to decide
whether to save our family's house
or save your own pale ass.
Like you always have.
Get the bread and shut the door.
So? What do you think?
Excuse my honesty,
but this "stomp" is not my thing.
-No way. I can't believe it.
-No, trust me. I really don't like it.
My stupid sister sent
my demo to the producer in Amsterdam.
-Aren't you happy?
-No, I'm not happy. He says it sucks.
And he's right.
This "stomp" without a bit
of Neapolitan ain't worth shit.
As if that's a way
to break up with a girl!
-He disappeared into thin air.
-Stop it. You sound like you've been left.
Jerk. Coward.
-Yokel.
-Yokel!
I'll find him. I swear to God
I'll take a flight to Amsterdam
and have him arrested! Bastard.
Cuckold.
-Cuckold.
-Mom! It's my fault. I messed up.
Honey? What's up? Are you sick?
Hey. Breathe.
There. She got upset. See?
Bloody scoundrel.
Honey, I think
it could have been your uncle's salami.
It's very tasty,
but the food here is very rich so…
-Here. You'll feel better now, lighter.
-Here. Drink some water.
How's that? Better?
I remember when I was pregnant.
The first months, I lived in the bathroom.
Oh my God. Of course.
How did I not get it?
Sweetheart.
-Have you seen a gynecologist?
-Never.
Never? How come?
It's bad you've never been.
-No.
-Can you do it now?
-Yes.
-Is it too late?
-No.
-I don't remember.
-God. She's sick…
-What's wrong? Come here.
-Come and sit down.
-I can't breathe.
No. Take a deep breath. Deep.
Again. There. Yes, have some water.
I miss you tonight
A faraway caress
You, in my heart, and it hurts
I miss you tonight
You, Christmas Star
And I lay awake
Carmela
To you, I am a betrayal
An enemy during war
A door that you lock
Carmela
People would do anything for power.
I'm not interested in that.
A busy life and lethargic sex
haven't allowed me to have heirs.
For this reason, I wanted to leave a mark.
Can you keep a secret?
The new stadium for Aci Fontana.
At least the tree stayed. I'm glad.
It'll be cut down
and it will be commemorated
by a more stylish mulberry tree
in Swedish fiberboard.
Placed at the entrance to the VIP Area.
I insisted on this
to honor your father's memory.
Thanks.
I'm sorry, but weren't you against it?
Didn't you say you liked the ecosystem?
Yes. But there's one thing
I like more than the ecosystem.
-Football?
-Money.
Damn it, how much I love
the beautiful money.
I knew right away
you're not moralistic like your brother.
You're an entrepreneur.
I'm enchanted every time I look at it.
A watched pot never boils.
Shall we let this pot boil?
An entrepreneur.
What are you doing?
Don't pull that face.
-You went to the Town Hall. You signed.
-What are you doing?
I won't give that jerk the satisfaction
of cutting down my mulberry. I'll do it.
You wanna cut down the mulberry?
What are you thinking?
He wants to demolish our whole property.
Don't you get it?
Ah! I know it all! I don't sign,
then I sign, then he passes the ball.
Then he gets angry if I sign.
What the fuck is in your head?
I had a doubt in my head but not anymore.
Give me the urn back
and get the fuck out of here.
-The urn?
-That's right.
-That vase with inside…
-Precisely.
That-- That box?
That… We went to the top of the mountain…
-But we didn't intend--
-What are you saying?
-I was saying--
-Salvo, what?
-Do you want it to end badly?
-No. The wind blew.
And Dad is now in the microfauna.
-He's happy--
-Cain!
-What Cain? You Cain.
-Easy!
Cain. You sold
your family for 4,000 Lira. Cain!
-You signed!
-Suck.
How are you, Mayor?
-Don't touch me! Go away!
-Are you all right?
Everyone get out!
Suck. I signed "Suck."
"Suck."
S-U-C-K.
Which is also an anagram for "Sorry."
It's not an anagram.
It's alliterative because of the "S."
Yeah, S as in the shithead that you are.
-Were you fighting?
-No. We were talking.
Just an intense discussion.
Honey, please, enough.
You're too old for this. Come on.
Also because you'll be a grandpa soon.
Enzo. Have you knocked up a girl?
Did I?
Have you knocked up a girl?!
Did you know it?
Emma.
Is it a boy?
-I'm joking.
-It's a girl.
Six of one and half a dozen of the other.
You said it. To save the pizzeria,
we need to mortgage our house in Milan.
-But there are always two options.
-That's right.
-You mentioned one now.
-What's the other one?
It's that you stay here.
Doing what?
There are a lot of European funds
available for things like these.
And you could sell the house in Milan
instead of mortgaging it.
-You could make money.
-Your mom doesn't want to.
Your mom may have changed her mind.
-When?
-Just now.
And I could help you
to start off the business
until we go back to Amsterdam.
"We" who?
-Didn't I tell you?
-No.
-I decided she'll be born here.
-She'll call her Carmela.
-Joking.
-Yes. Maybe the next one.
There's even a music stage?
Hey.
Dad…
I have to tell you something too.
I don't want to be a pizza maker.
And what do you want to be,
a sound designer?
Yes. I want to be a sound designer.
Maybe I won't succeed, but I'll try.
And I want to live on my own.
Oh my God. I miss you a lot already.
-How will you pay the rent?
-I'll find a job.
Maybe at the beginning,
only at the beginning,
I could help you here.
In the beginning. Until I become an uncle.
Whereas I'd like to sleep
until I become a grandpa.
Get out of here, Salvo. God help us.
You want to live on your own?
-Dad saw that.
-Sweetheart.
Guys, soon…
Music!
Good party.
What's up?
Do you want to smoke?
Do you want to dance?
It was you then.
I made it myself.
Do you like it?
Yes. It's not really my style,
but it's pretty.
I'll put it on.
Sorry, Carmela, don't be offended,
but I wanted to ask you
if I could kiss you.
But I'm out of practice.
It's just like swimming.
But I can't swim.
You start with a dive…
On the count of three.
One…
Can I ask you something?
Hurry up. I've got things to do.
Why didn't you ever tell me anything nice?
What should I have told you?
If you encouraged me, I could have become
a rock star, the king of pizza.
The inventor of the pillow to sleep
with your arm under your head.
Just anything.
Maybe because I'm a useless thing.
No.
I am a useless thing.
That means that we're two useless things.
As they say, I passed you the gene.
I'm sorry I got it too late.
But it's not too late for you.
Dad.
We'll open a pizzeria
on our family estate.
As they say,
"Blessed is the bird
that makes its nest in its own village."
You remembered it.
Good job, Salvo.
My dear son.
Dad, since we made peace,
can you give me the lotto numbers?
I need them like oxygen.
Now more than ever.
Forty-seven.
Forty-seven?
Sixty-eight.
-Can you turn off the tractor?
-Eighty-eight.
I didn't get that.
Can you spell it, please?
Speak up. Spell it.
Fuck off.
Did you get this white wine?
Subtitle translation by: Angelica Lacetera