Are those red leaves under
the summer sunshine...
The same that hung
weakly on the day I left?
At that time it seemed that every leaf
the Autumn took away...
Took away a piece of my life.
I don't know if it's been a long time
or not since I left this house.
Or what I've been doing. Or where.
Or why my husband
decided that I had to leave.
Be strong.
You have to look normal for your husband.
It was me who insisted on your return.
And I know it's not gonna be easy, martine.
But you have to fight so everything
can be as you and I planned.
So everything can be as you and I planned.
That everything goes as wished.
Good fortune be with us.
To be good and honest,
worship god.
Paradise is waiting for us.
Paradise.
Which one is your cardinal point?
Earth?
Which is your hell?
Who made the lists of the forbidden?
Who took the role of judgment?
At what moment does the
day end and the night begin?
At what moment do
pride, ambition and desire
begin to be flowers of sin?
We're almost there.
Keep taking your
medication like at the clinic.
If you need me, tell Wanda to call me.
Miss, miss martine!
Miss martine has arrived.
Good morning, miss.
Did you have a good journey?
We're so happy to see you.
This is your house. This is where we'll
live happily ever after.
My father carried my mother
and they lived happy together
until death took them apart.
I love you, Armando.
I pray to god you'll never stop loving me.
Never, ever.
What are you doing there?
I was waiting for you.
- Where have you been?
- That's none of your business.
Dear god! What's wrong with you?
I barely see you, and even
when you're home
I feel you're so distant.
Miss martine, I'm so
happy to see you again.
Miss martine. We've missed you
so much all these months.
Goodbye, doctor.
You're coming to visit next week, right?
I didn't allow anyone to enter your room.
Everything is still like the day you left.
Hydrangeas. Thank you, Wanda.
Is the Marquis at home?
No, ma'am, he's out with that
young man he's been seeing lately.
Who is he?
I don't really know, ma'am.
I only know his name is flor.
He's undoubtedly a distinguished young man,
although neither his character
or manners are those of a good person.
I don't know what's wrong with the Marquis.
Since you left, he's been seeing
some people of questionable morality.
So what! You've seen me, so what? It's
not the first time you've seen me naked.
Or are you disturbed to see
my young friend naked?
He has a beautiful body, don't you think?
Wouldn't you like to touch it?
I like his mouth wide open like a pussy.
Inviting me to unknown pleasures.
Martine! Martine!
I like your mouth wide open like a pussy.
Inviting me to unknown pleasures.
Martine! Martine!
Wait! Wait!
Don't make me run. Don't make me run
anymore, darling. Wait!
Flor! Flor!
Wait, flor!
Darling! Flor, darling. Wait.
Don't run away again, my darling.
Flor! Wait, wait.
Wait. Flor, wait for me.
Flor.
Wait for me. Wait for me.
Don't run so fast.
- You can't get me!
- Wait.
You can't get me.
I will get you in the end.
No, you won't.
You rascal! Rascal!
You won't get me.
I'll get you! I promise.
You cannot get me!
Rascal! You're killing me!
Wait a second! Stop for a moment!
- Don't be a rascal.
- You can't get me! No!
Got you! Got you! Almost got you!
Come here, rascal.
Come here flor, wait. I can't keep
going, wait. Wait, flor!
Armando! Armando!
There's a woman lying on the road.
It's a nun.
What bad taste to come here
and die on my land.
She isn't dead.
- Just passed out.
- What happened to her?
I don't know.
It's just a kid, a novice.
George! George!
She's hurt.
Maybe she's been raped, she's bleeding.
What do we do with her?
We'll take her home.
Let's do it. Let's do it.
How long has that young man been here?
Afew months, and god forgive me...
But I think that young man flor...
Has been sent from hell.
He is very young, pale, and attractive.
His beauty is so feminine.
I don't know where he came from.
One morning, I found
him in your husband's bed.
He was completely naked. I asked him
who he was and what did he say?
Tell me, Wanda.
What did he say?
That he was the lover of the Marquis.
His lover? My husband never
had a sex drive.
Then he laughed without
even covering himself.
Do you like her, flor?
She has soft and smooth skin.
This little nun is a temptation.
My lady, I think it's true what flor said.
That young man and your husband are lovers.
I'm sorry to tell you,
I'm sorry to cause you sorrow.
That perverted young man has possessed...
Mr. Armando's will.
Who are you? Where am I?
You are at seteais palace.
Property of the Marquis of bressac.
And I am the Marquis, a great fanatic of
hunting young slaves with smooth skin.
Let me go! Let me go!
- What were you doing on my property?
- I don't know.
You escaped from the convent, right?
With a young boy that dumped
you after having a good time with you?
- Do you want me to get you back to the convent?
- No, please, no!
Or do you prefer to stay with us?
I prefer to stay with you.
The little nun has good taste.
Let's try her.
A little rough tasting.
A peasant, without a doubt.
C'mon Armando, it seems you like her.
That young man has dragged the Marquis to the most
spiteful scandals and most sinful indulgences.
Give me some!
You must talk to him.
This cannot be, ma'am.
What can I do?
He has not even greeted
me since my arrival.
- Enough!
- My turn.
You have to stop those scandals
in your own house.
And stop him from wasting money.
Do it for the respect of your ancestors.
Martine, I have a few
minutes left. I can't hide
the truth from you.
Since past generations...
Our family has been suffering from
a shameful congenital disease.
All have died from it.
And you will too.
I can't fight anymore.
I don't even have self respect.
And I can't feel anything else
for him but love.
A hopeless love.
Without illusions.
Blind, I feel a savage desire.
I'm filled with his scent.
When somebody talks to me,
I only hear his voice.
Do you understand me?
What can I do?
I'm in love.
Do you understand me?
What can I do?
I love you, Armando.
Why have you left me alone all this time?
I know it was you who wanted...
Me to be in that horrible place.
Not for having an incurable illness,
but to get rid of me.
Why?
I gave you everything.
I let you drive me through turbulent roads.
Now you leave me with
my body soaked in desire.
After a long time dreaming of my return.
To feel your skin against mine.
Why, lord?
Lord, bring him back to me.
May he desire me like I desire him.
Our father! Bring him to me.
Our father.
May his wet cock moisten my dry pussy.
His cock, inside me...
Forgive me, oh lord,
for talking to you like that.
But I can't take it anymore.
Have mercy on your daughter,
for she is consumed
by love and desire. You understand
everything, oh lord! I need him.
It's him, I need to meet him.
I will knee! To him.
I will beg him. I need love,
or I will go truly crazy.
Martine! I know you're there.
Don't hide, come here!
Watch and learn from my friend.
He really knows how to please me.
Well, leave then!
If you're in heat, go and look for
the maid. She consents to everything.
Keep going, like that, like that...
- Who are you?
- My name is Norma.
The Marquis brought me here.
Are you his wife? The Marquis?
You're so pretty, Norma.
Have you ever made love?
Tell me the truth.
Yes, ma'am.
But it hurt me so much.
It doesn't always hurt.
It doesn't hurt when a woman does it.
Please, my lady.
I love that sound.
Like a scared birdie.
And that little girl's
skin. And these tights.
No, my lady, no.
Relax.
What do you feel?
I feel a lot of heat.
It's a great sin, please lady.
Get out of here! Skank!
Armando!
Do it to me!
Make love to me, Armando.
Make love to me.
I can't take it anymore.
Get out of this room! You whore!
Get out! Get out of here! Get out!
Don't lock me up! No!
I can't take it anymore.
Do what you please with me,
but don't leave me alone again.
- Good morning, my lady.
- Good morning, Norma.
Did you sleep well? You look tired.
I didn't sleep at all.
Last night was horrible.
What are you talking about?
I wasn't myself, I was so mean to you.
You have to forgive me.
Why are you apologizing?
I was deeply asleep.
I don't know what happened.
I don't understand your apologies.
I've been sick.
I have an illness.
I am very sick.
Will you be patient?
A pleasure to serve you, my lady. And I
don't see why I should change my mind.
I am at your service, Marquis.
Your wishes are my commands.
- We'll have our secrets, nobody will ever know it.
- Yes, ma'am.
- You can leave now.
Good morning, my lady.
Your husband called me, urgently.
He said you had a nervous
breakdown last night.
What happened?
Aren't you feeling well?
Are you noticing some hostility around?
You must relax, darling.
Reality is sometimes hard,
difficult to manage.
If you have another breakdown, the Marquis
will send you back to my clinic.
Perhaps that's what he wants, right?
- But that is not what we want.
- Do you think he wants to send me back?
Of course. I'm sure.
You have to be strong,
keep taking the medication.
Follow my plan, step by step.
I don't know, doctor.
You have to fight! Fight, my lady!
If I only knew how.
Hold on to the idea of a better future.
You still love him, right?
You have to defeat that feeling.
Otherwise, we have little to do.
Goodbye.
George! Come here.
- Yes, Marquis.
- Get the doctor.
- Doctor, please come.
- What's going on?
The Marquis wants to talk to you.
He is waiting in the main hall.
- Yes, Marquis.
- I have some questions for you.
In the new diagnosis you gave me,
besides the proper medication,
there are some notes.
Like martine can't experience
sociological
and physical emotions.
- Otherwise, any excitement could be fatal?
- That's right.
- So, any strong emotion could kill her?
- Exactly.
Also, sexual activity is not allowed?
Correct.
If by any reason I can't control her behavior,
and we have to face the fatal outcome,
would I be charged with negligence?
That's right.
My father, the Marquis of bressac,
took your father out of ruin.
That's why his unfortunate son was able
to make a career, open a clinic,
and be embraced by high society.
I suppose you haven't forgotten all that.
No, Marquis, that's why
I took care of your wife,
kept her at my clinic for 8 months,
and I refused to accept any payment.
That's very honorable,
but it doesn't matter to me.
If I have to remind you of the things the
bressac family did for yours,
it's because after my
wife's breakdown last night,
it's probable she'll die some time soon.
In that case, I expect you can extend
a certificate to exonerate me of all
negligence that can affect me.
These are hard times, doctor.
Lots of corrupt public servants would be
so happy to denigrate the aristocracy.
I hope that isn't your case, doctor.
And that you will keep
the diagnosis between us.
Otherwise, it will look like I caused her
death to seize her father's great fortune.
And don't forget, the bressacs still have enough
power to ruin you. Do you understand, doctor?
Yes, sir.
- Miss, please, calm down.
- I can't, Wanda.
Armando, Armando, listen to me.
Why don't you come in?
Why are you evading me?
Why don't you talk to me? Don't forget
I'm your wife. Can't you remember?
Unfortunately, I haven't
been able to forget it.
A dried Rose in a buttonhole.
The last page of an old, unfinished diary.
A guitar missing strings. A clock without a
pendulum. A weather vane without an arrow.
I am all that without you, martine.
Do you like it? Tell me.
Here is my dear wife. We are honored
to have her presence.
Thank you.
Today it's a very special date.
It's the 3rd anniversary of
her first mental breakdown.
Cheers!
Martine is a very unique woman,
as is her madness, schizophrenia.
Produced by congenital syphilis.
Hush Armando, please.
I will not shut up. I want my friends to be
aware of all your attributes, darling.
That's the reason you stayed tonight?
To use me as the target of your cynicism.
Not at all, darling.
Correct me if I'm wrong. She's a model
for a married woman.
And almost the perfect lover.
Right, my love?
Delicate alabaster skin, like a
pale fruit ripped from a greenhouse.
A sweet soft fruit, but also one who
will be quickly filled with worms.
The most devoted painter would dream to
paint those two apples of temptation.
Thank you!
I'm afraid she got mad.
Cheers to the most stupid wife!
Norma, my little one. You must help me, help us.
Our lives will be a paradise when she's gone.
Also we'll be rich, the 3 of us.
What do you want me to do?
- She's very nice to me.
- Very nice to you, but very bad to your master.
She's a crazy bitch.
Maybe she has been nice in recent days, but she
can change suddenly, and turn into a cruel monster.
What do you want me to do?
You have to help us to get rid of her.
- Kill her?
- Yes.
I know it's an unpleasant word.
How?
It's very simple, she trusts you.
You always serve her food.
- Yes, but Wanda is the one who cooks it.
- You will hide this little box in her room.
Is this poison?
No, it's a stimulant, a strong one.
You will put it in her morning coffee
or in a glass of milk.
She will die peacefully.
Without evidence.
Nobody would accuse you of anything.
Will you do it? Tell me you will
do it, little one.
Say yes, beautiful.
It will be so easy and after...
It will be paradise for the 3 of us.
And love, and fortune.
My lady! Are you ok?
My lady!
My lady! Where are you?
- Let's go, Eros. To the clinic of doctor louys.
- Yes, madam.
- Where is Wanda going?
- To the house of doctor louys.
- How do you know?
- I heard her giving instructions to the rider.
And she thinks he is going to help?
- The Marquis knows you're here?
- No, doctor.
You know those are
very serious accusations.
You are telling me the
Marquis is a murderer.
Yes, doctor.
And what proof do you have of it?
Besides overhearing through a door,
and assuming you're not mistaken?
I'm sure of it.
The bressacs have always
been a role model couple.
Just appearances.
I live there and if you don't
help her, she could die.
The Marquis is an honorable man.
And very powerful. I should have known
you would never confront him.
Excuse me for wasting your time, doctor.
- Good afternoon, Norma.
- Good afternoon.
- Do you mind if I sit here?
- I don't mind at all.
Sometimes it's much better to be alone.
At those times the presence of
anyone disturbs me.
- But sometimes it's better to vent our feelings.
- I regret some things.
That's a sincere feeling.
I stopped caring about
others a long time ago.
When I was a little kid and my father
started to call me flor just for fun.
And he dressed me like a girl to
expose me to his friends.
I used to hate him for a while,
but then I enjoyed it.
Now I'm so confused.
- I think I'm in love with you.
- Me too.
Thank you for telling me. But if that's the
case you have to put sentimentality aside.
If that woman dies, we win.
And maybe one day we could run away.
You and I, together without
Armando de bressac.
Deep inside, we both hate him to death.
I love you, Armando.
Tonight I will look for you,
and I will be as you wish,
more indecent than ever.
You will take me in your arms.
You will take me to the bed.
Uncover my breasts.
You have always loved 'em.
You will caress them.
First softly and gently.
Then your hands will turn
violent against my flesh.
Then you'll descend slowly...
To my pussy, and you will touch it
with uncontrollable desire.
The first Marquis of bressac.
What an idiot! What an idiot!
The Marquis of the idiots!
Poor bressac.
Hated by everybody.
Even by his stupid housekeeper.
Open the door, Wanda.
- Good evening, Wanda.
- Good evening, Marquis. What do you want?
You still have a hideous body...
Like the last time we fucked.
Don't worry, I'm not here to make love,
but to kill you.
Bitch!
You thought the doctor wouldn't tell me?
Everybody hates me, but
at the end I step on them.
Like I'm stepping on you right now, Wanda.
- Good morning, martine. How are you?
- Same, doctor.
It seems you had a relapse yesterday.
Yes, I did.
We don't have much time.
Besides, they could be listening.
Your husband told me that you have
imagined seeing Wanda strangled.
But the truth is, she has vanished after
a few hours of visiting my clinic
and accusing him of trying to kill you.
- Martine, are you ready to follow my plans?
- Yes.
Calm down, rest and avoid excitement.
And of course keep taking the medication.
It seems your condition hasn't worsened.
I'll read your document carefully, martine.
I hope you agree to my ideas.
Have a nice day.
Martine, listen to me. That bastard
doesn't deserve to live.
He has destroyed your life, like everything
that crosses his path. Don't you want revenge?
Here my lady, your glass of milk.
It's hot.
Leave it there. Norma, tell me.
- Do you love me?
- Yes, ma'am.
Don't you like me instead, martine?
Yes, Armando, come here my love.
Finally, finally.
Come here.
George, come here with us.
No! Why?
Poor thing. My sweet wife has died.
Ego te absolvo a peccatis tuis.
Poor martine! Poor martine!
- Poor martine!
- Poor martine.
Poor martine.
Poor martine, she's dead.
- Poor martine.
Poor martine.
Look at them Marquis, the two lovers.
What a romantic scene.
Did you imagine the young flor
being that enamored?
Yes, he is a kid, he doesn't have a
sense of honesty and loyalty.
And you have no right to be that nosy.
I love you! I love you! Yes! Yes!
You! You came back from hell!
Are you here to help me
or to drag me to my ruin?
- I've returned to see you die.
- Are you alive?
Or a ghost in my mind?
You're alive!
It's true.
Now you are going to pay once and for all.
What are you gonna do?
The blood is still fresh.
Yes, thank you for coming.
Do it, martine. Do it.
Do it. What are you waiting for?
Do it! Do it! Do it!
Louys.
My love, be brave.
It's a new beginning for you.
I'm scared.
I destroyed your death
certificate. Everything is in order.
They will not charge you.
I will write a certificate.
This is horrible.
Just for a few months.
Then we are heading far
away with all your money.
Until you forget these sad
walls and this sad story.