Now, blud.
Fuck that, yo!
Yeah! This is OSC,
all day, let's go!
♪ Shots in a club, shots inna car park
♪ Shots inna daylight
Shots in the dark
♪ Nigger, what's the aim like?
Better be sharp
♪ 'Cause we blow trees
and we're street smart
♪ Don't get cold feet
when the heat starts
♪ We let the heat bark
when the beef starts
♪ Big Nine put a nigger to his knees
Star
♪ And I will clap three
if you're fucking with me
♪ Coming at you from dangerous angles
♪ Foes will get mangled
Dough will get handled
♪ I'm blazing more than a candle
Damaging more than a vandal
♪ My energy blasts through the streets
and the roads and we speak inner codes
♪ Breaking barriers and bones
making you panic when I flow
♪ You can have it
Let me know what blows, hold dat
♪ 'Round my ways, it's all crap
Spitting it all phat lawless days
♪ Where mans creep and crawl to get paid
Caught up in bullets and blades, boring
♪ Spending my days in a maze
still rays will blaze
♪ Listen you're not ready
when I blast off
♪ Shooting niggers bare faced
Take my fucking mask off
♪ Have you walking in a straight line
like a mascot
♪ Said you blast shots
you could never blast what Zampa
♪ You will get bull
like the hydro man are dumping
♪ Let me have my go, I let loose
I go mad when the lights go
♪ Bullets might reach to your face
like nitro
♪ Come test OSC, I double dare you
♪ Come bang with us, I double dare ya
♪ Yo, Flash, pull that chain
I double dare ya
♪ And put two in his brains
♪ Come and test Zampa boys
I double dare ya
♪ Come and bang with us
♪ Go ahead, call the cops
I double dare ya
♪ Go ahead, bust them shots
I double dare you
♪ These niggas is all bitch style
Wearing flip flops
♪ Singing like Debra Cox
♪ I'm pulling up their skirts
like Dennis did to Sharon Watts
♪ Far from an EastEnder
I'm a Birmingham City representer
♪ Throwing hot darts
Getting right up in your centre
♪ Bullseye, run when de wolf cry
Some live, some die
♪ All for the devil pie
All for the devil pie
♪ Once again they're running their guns
Done knowing that we're run the roads
♪ Took all the guns up in the slums
♪ It's every day it nothing
it's Brum, straight running chumps
♪ Off the ends with the pumps we dump
dump, and we ain't no regular dudes
♪ Violate and we'll put you and
your bred in the boot, you bitches
♪ We'll roll up and put ten
in your womb
♪ When Z boys are in the place
you best be making us room
♪ It's like black tints face mask
Dead body in a car
♪ It makes me toss pass
I'm a boss chick bumba arse, hard
♪ With the hardest come and start large
I'm the tallest over all
♪ I'm a war chick come and war dis ain't
fe no bust up talk it it stops, pause
♪ Pussy has to park it
Come test Zampa boys, I double dare ya
♪ Come and bang with us
I double dare ya
♪ Go ahead, call the cops
♪ Go ahead bust them shots
I double dare you
♪ Come test OSC, I double dare ya
♪ Come bang with us
I double dare ya
♪ Yo, Flash, pull that chain
♪ And put two in his brains
I double dare ya ♪
Yo, Don.
I'm bouncing in an hour, you know.
Got early release.
- Yeah?
- Mmm-hmm.
So what you saying,
you ready to do that thing?
- I'm ready, blud. Ready.
- Yeah?
- Five hundred bags. Ten grand a pop.
- I got that on road, put down now.
You got a strong team?
- Team's strong, man, of course.
- Yeah?
What do you think?
- Think he's ready? Yeah?
- I'm ready, blud, man.
Hear what, blud.
If you fuck this up, you
taking bare food out of man's mouth,
understand what I'm saying?
- Look into my face.
- What you mean?
Soon you come around this table,
you behave yourself.
There's big men round here,
you understand?
What you think?
I'll put you onto this.
Come, make this call.
Go on.
You alright, Baby T?
Mmm? You cool?
Make this call, B.
- Yo.
- Yeah, yo, Don, what's gwanning?
- It's me, Levi.
- You cool?
Yeah, everything's as cool as it can be.
Listen, yeah, one of my soldiers
is coming out today, you know.
- Yeah? That's good.
- Yeah.
- When did you need that?
- Today!
- I want it today.
- Today?
Yeah. We can work with that still,
we can handle that, yeah.
- All, right, B.
- Later.
Make your call, B.
- 'Allo?
- Yo, Flash, it's Angel.
- You up and about?
- Yeah, blud, what's popping?
Yeah, link me in an hour
and bring all my money.
An hour?
I thought you was in the penner.
Yo, early release.
I'm coming out this morning.
Early release, cuzzie, lucky you.
Alright, boom.
Yo, listen carefully, blud.
Link me in an hour
and bring all my scrilla, blud.
Paper... All of the paper? I didn't know
you was coming out like today, rude boy.
- All of the paper, Don?
- Yo, you turn into a fucking parrot?
Bring all my papers, blud,
and link me outside the pen in an hour.
You got a fucking problem with that?
It's not a parrot thing, my parrot died
Alright, safe, we link up in a bit.
- Yeah, an hour.
- Coming in a minute.
An hour, we link up and talk properly.
Don't be late.
Fucking hell...
Alright, Baby T?
Daddy's in trouble, right now.
- I got that, you know. Mmm.
- Yeah?
Looked like you was put under
a bit of pressure over there.
- No pressure.
- No pressure?
Hear what. Don't be acting like a killer
just 'cause you got a ghost
under your belt.
Just remember a man like me got many.
You understand?
Funny boy.
- Oi, okay. I gotta make a move.
- I'm in the bath, man.
I know he lives around here somewhere.
- It's one of these...
- It's either this one or that one...
All these houses
are just the same to me.
- Flash!
- Daddy!
- Daddy! Daddy!
- Flash!
- Mummy, where did Daddy go?
- Dickhead!
Yo?
Yo, Flash, man. Where you, man?
- Yeah. I'm coming to you right now.
- I'm at the spot, still.
Yeah. I'm coming to you.
Just relax, Don.
Yo, Flash, where are you?
- Yo, Don.
- Hurry up. Hurry up, I beg you.
Blud, give me about ten, 15 minutes.
Hurry up. People,
they're bugging me on the road.
You trying to get me
sucked or something?
Where are you?
Give me about half an hour,
45 minutes and I'm with you.
You taking fucking long.
Bear with me, man, I'll soon come,
half an hour, 45 minutes.
- Yo, where are you?
- I'm coming straight to you right now.
- I'm jumping in my car.
- I've been waiting long.
- Like an hour and a half.
- Yeah.
Don't take the piss.
Make sure you're here, you know.
People are bugging me about the food.
Three bricks of yay in the bag.
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
- What the fuck are you doing to my car?
What the fuck are you doing in my car?
Thiefing out of my whip, rude boy?
- No, I'm not, man.
- You thiefing out of my fucking car?
- No. No. No. No.
- No? Look at me.
I know this face from somewhere,
your mum smokes the dope?
- Yeah.
- Pest, that's your name, Don.
That's what they call me.
Look at your fucking hat and
all of this. Look at this shit, blud.
You see, when I was your age
I was fucking licking raises,
I was fucking pop a tom or pull a bag.
You think I'd ever hit the road
looking like this?
You have to do something with yourself.
Can't be standing around
wastemanning it out.
- Hear this.
- I'm not a wasteman.
Yous look like a fucking wasteman.
Fucking hell. You better do
something with yourself, 'cause I know
your mum ain't got no money
to buy you no trainers.
- Yeah, I know.
- Right, now, listen to me.
- Lickle raise.
- What raise, what sort of raise?
What do I do? Rob a bank or something?
Nah, forget all of that.
You're not at that level now.
Listen. Don't get scared, get mad,
spot the victim, pop the bag
and run and don't get nabbed.
You understand that, blud?
- Yeah.
- Go and do your thing.
And listen to me. If I ever
catch you in my fucking car again
I'm going to kick your fucking face off.
Understand that?
Do your thing, Don. Fucking hell.
Yo, it's Flash, you need food?
Phone you back in a bit.
- Flash!
- Flash.
What's poppin'? What you saying, G?
Cool, cool.
Fuck all, man.
Angel's touching road, blud.
Hmm... that's kind of the problem
right now. I got 500 thou for the man.
- Serious, blud?
- I've only got 400 thousand of it.
I owe my man 100 grand, rude boy.
Bloodclot!
I got the food in the car
right now, blud.
Buoy, Don.
D'you need food?
I'm wounded right now, B,
I've got pure food, pure food.
I need to go out on the road
and lick two sales. You get me?
That's what I'm saying, blud, fucked up.
Fucking hell. Try Evil.
Evil, blud? Evil's a dodgy guy,
rude boy. I can't fuck with him, man.
Boy, he's been sticking up pure man
on the ends lately still,
but he's the man with the P's, blud.
Serious? Remember I told you,
the man's phat, get me?
♪ Yo, Kite, I ain't a battle rapper
♪ But my bars are bullets that
ratta tatta, blow a nigger brain matter
♪ Matter of fact I know the cat's a rat
You ain't a scrapper you a fanny flapper
♪ You rap amateur, whipper snapper
♪ Retaliate, tit for tat
swing a bat and cracker, head and back
♪ You don't deserve to rap
'cause you a slacker
♪ Fucking with a Don Dapper
that'll cap rappers
♪ Won't give a whore a bloody nose
but I slap slappers, follow code
♪ I'm on road like back packers
and we're like slave masters
♪ We all crackers
A bunch of mad hatters
♪ Cops mad they can't catch us
♪ They know it's petty cash
that I stash under the mattress ♪
♪ J.B., you're not
ready for the warring
♪ Cut back my nine in your face
like foreskin
♪ Draw from my gatt
I leave your blood pouring
♪ Merk, J.B., and leave no warning
♪ J.B., but your girl is a fat bitch
Girl got fucked three times
♪ That's a hat trick drove for the shank
a face like a mastiff
♪ Talk about B
but you could never match it
♪ You don't want it, you're not on it
♪ I'll bust your head
straight off a car bonnet
♪ You will get burn like chronic
and I'll bust you
♪ And make him run like Sonic ♪
Here he is, here he is. Here he is!
Angel!
The little convict.
Yes!
- What!
- Yes, nigga.
- El Prezzie's little cousin, ain't it?
- Little cousin.
Heard about you, blud.
Antics on the road.
- Yeah. You know.
- What you saying, big cuz?
- So you good?
- Yeah, man, I'm good.
- Yes, Flash.
- Boss man.
What you say, family?
- Are you good?
- Cool, good.
You know what I want right now?
You know what I need right now?
- Know what I need now?
- Some girl? Some pussy?
I need food, Don.
I'm hungry. Food. Right now.
Yo, blud, I need some food!
I'm feverish, Don. Need some food.
Hungry.
What you all grabbing at your bag for?
Like man are going to rob you and that.
Huh? Look at this geezer.
Sit down. Sit your ass down.
- Looking at man and that. Sit down.
- Sorry about that.
Chill out, man.
Sorry about that.
- Listen, listen.
- Going to jack them and that...
- Large fries, large fish burger.
No mayonnaise, no onions
and a large drink.
Cheeseburger, gaffer.
Give me
a chicken breast and fries.
- I want a cheeseburger and a Coke.
- I want some fries and salad.
- No lettuce.
- How come you're moving so slow?
Where's my Coke?
Haven't had good food for ages.
I hear that, I hear that.
You all know what day
it is today, innit?
- Hmm?
- The day El Prezzie died, innit, Don?
- That's what I'm saying...
- Year down the line already, you know.
You get me. Some joke thing. You get me.
Imagine my man phoned me a half hour
before he got popped, you know,
and told me to come and link him.
I was up in that dutty bloodclot girl,
Simone's yard. You get me.
I miss him, cuz.
Joke thing. Imagine my man,
like walked around the corner
or phoned me ten minutes earlier.
Or even bent down
to tie his shoelace or something.
- You know fate already. You get me.
- Life's just funny like that.
That's how it goes sometimes, man.
Trust me.
It's like a bullet had the
nigger's name on it or something, Don.
It's fate, blud.
That's what you get for being
pussy whipped, innit. You get me.
Yo! Shut your fucking mouth.
Shut your fucking mouth.
My bredrin you're talking about,
you know. It's not a joke.
This fate talk, man.
All this fate talk is fucking bullshit.
It's not about where you're from,
you know. It's how you do your thing.
♪ Oi! What you staring at?
♪ You don't like man
'cause I'm wearing black
♪ You don't like me
I don't want to be hearing that
♪ You don't like man
'cause I'm wearing black
♪ Like woman
I don't mean to be rude
♪ But you don't like me
'cause I'm eating food
♪ Huh, I don't mean to be rude
but you don't like man
♪ 'Cause I'm eating food
♪ Money isn't easy
doesn't grow on trees
♪ I got to help my family
get them off their knees
♪ Hustling every day I'm selling bare
cheese, I got locked up, interviewed
♪ Talking bare breeze, so then I went
to pen, my head was full of rage
♪ I felt like an animal
locked up in a cage
♪ Reading books every day
page after page, then I hit the road
♪ I was on the next stage
♪ I'm gonna flip and I hate to, but
trust me if you hate me then I hate you
♪ No point being fake, too
♪ 'Cause trust me
if you hate me then I hate you
♪ You better move or I'll make you
♪ 'Cause trust me
if you hate me then I hate you
♪ If you hate me then I hate you
Now you hate me and I hate you
♪ For real, though
Why do you look like that?
♪ It ain't my fault
I got you shook like that
♪ Thinking that I'm dirt
with your pennies in your purse
♪ Like I'm gonna rob you
I ain't a crook like that
♪ I'm in the queue like you
about to get two snacks
♪ 'Cause I'm black you feel
the urge to move back
♪ Man, I should give you two slaps, but
I ain't gonna go to jail for you prats
♪ 'Cause I came from the depths of hell
with these stats
♪ Rode with the gatt
to put clothes on my back
♪ 'Cause my Daddy wasn't there
he was doped off crack
♪ I was left all alone in a cold flat
This world don't owe me jack
♪ I was given this life
I never chose this path
♪ So have a good stare
when you're walking past
♪ 'Cause you can look
but can't hold me back
♪ I'm going to flip and I hate to, but
trust me if you hate me then I hate you
♪ No point being fake, too
♪ 'Cause trust me
if you hate me then I hate you
♪ You better move or I make you
♪ 'Cause trust me
if you hate me then I hate you
♪ If you hate me then I hate you
Now you hate me and I hate you ♪
Yo. Check it, gun, you know?
- Been taking care of business?
- Yeah, man. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Have you got the scrilla?
- It's in the car still.
What the fuck is that, blud?
That's fucking short, blud.
Don, it's a hundred bags light.
Truthfully, but I got three...
A hundred bags light, blud?
You lost your fucking mind?
I got, like, three boxes put down innit.
- Yo. I want my money today, blud.
- Today, rude boy.
- I can get it sorted by tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
Yo, you got two hours maximum.
Don't think I am fucking with you,
you know what happens.
- Don't act like you don't know.
- Two hours, Don, a hundred bags.
Yo, Don. Fucking hell, man.
I'm under pressure right now, blud.
I didn't know you was
coming out of jail today.
I'm going to lick off your fucking head.
I hear you, Don. Give me about...
Yeah, I'll have it ready for you.
- Where you want to go?
- Take me to your sister's yard.
I am going to phone Evil
and see what this geezer's saying.
He phoned me last week
talking about he wants food and all.
- Yo, yo, wagwan!
- Evil.
- Yo evil.
- What you sayin'?
So what are the mans under?
Chilling? Kicking back?
Hold on one sec.
- Hello?
- Yo, sir.
- Who's that?
- Yeah, it's Flash. Wagwan.
What you saying, G? What's happening?
I got that thing I was talking about.
Three boxes of it puzzule down.
Yours. Link me at DeZLidlel Gezet
that in the next 20 minutes.
- Fill me in, G. What you saying?
- Hundred bazags tzink wzup with it.
Yeah, lzink me in about
20 mzinutes at deLidlzel.
Strazake czash though.
I'm not into the dewzork tzing.
You got the three boxes of the food?
I can deal with that for you,
it's not a problem.
- Alright, then, cuz. Yeah, yeah.
- Cool, no problem.
Yeah, my man says he'll take it still.
- Evil's dodgy. One of us still, though.
- Mmm-hmm.
- Yo, Evil. Wagwan?
- Assassin.
- Wagwan, blud?
- What you saying?
- I got a move for you. You up for it?
- Yeah, no doubt, blud. No doubt.
Yeah... three boxes.
How much mans you got round here?
Yo, blud, I'm going to bring
the Twinz and Euro with me. Yeah?
Then safe. Cool, man.
Meet me at my baby mother's.
- Yo. I'm down by the ends.
- All right, say no more.
Make sure you got
the money by one.
- Definitely. One o'clock.
- One o'clock. Serious.
- I'll have that.
- Cool.
- Flash.
- What you saying, Evil?
- Mmm!
- Popping?
Wagwan, Don? Tell me.
- Tell me, cuzzie.
- Say you got the bricks for me, fam?
- You got them three B's for me?
- Yeah, I got them there for you.
- You got the scrilla?
- Scrilla?
No I ain't got the scrilla, fam. Na...
What do you mean "Na," blud?
That's what I said to you on the phone.
I didn't know you wanted
the money right now.
That's what I'm trying to tell you. That
back slam shallawa shallawa bullshit.
You have to talk a bit slower,
I don't really too understand it.
I thought you said "can I deal with it?"
- I can deal with it.
- It's not a thing like that.
It's not a work thing.
I need the scrilla now.
My man's talking. I need to link him
in an hour, you know how he goes on.
I'm not looking to wigged over
fucking this scrilla.
I can get it for you.
You got the yay, I got the paper.
We can go to my baby mother's,
pick it up.
- It's not long.
- Since when you got a baby mother?
What do you mean? Come on.
Have you got a baby mother?
Yeah, you know who my baby mother is.
- Who's your baby mother?
- You don't know her. She's...
She's not from around here,
but she's kind of close by.
- Close by, rude boy?
- You get me so...
A hundred thousand at your
baby mother's, rude boy?
Don, it's B you know, fam, Eves.
Look at what I am repping...
Yo, come on, behave yourself.
A hundred grand is nothing.
It's a minor. Understand? What you going
to say, you wanna go for the paper?
We can go for it now.
You wanna jump in my car?
You know something.
Better still we jump in this,
I jump in my cab you follow me in this.
- Yeah, that's not a problem, B.
- Cool.
Everything cool though differently?
Yeah, man. Yeah, blud.
Living and breathing.
- I can't complain. Doing my thing...
- That's the main thing.
If my man didn't come out of jail today
it'd have been a lily more easy.
It's a headache.
I wasn't expecting to see him.
Good to see him still, differently,
but wasn't expecting to see him.
- You get me?
- Rather you than me, B.
Take a right when you
get down the bottom there.
Yo, where the fuck you are
really bringing me, you know, Don?
- You worry too much. You're with me.
- With you. It's Zampa Boy ends.
So with you and the Zampa Boys
'round here. You mad.
Don't watch nothing. Everything's cool.
Yeah, so you think, rude boy.
Fuck, blud.
You worry too much, man.
I got it covered...
Frightened Friday all the time.
Just keep driving.
Now listen, man. Just remember you're
the only person to see me cry, you know.
When El Presidente died.
Don't watch nothing.
- I got your back.
- Say no more, cuz.
- That's real talk.
- Say no more.
- Yeah, but drive. Stop worrying.
- Don't watch nothing.
We're here.
My girl's is just over the grass.
- What you doing round here, Don?
- It's cool, man.
Know how long I been here,
you think the first time I brought you
round here I'm going to make anything
happen to ya? You on a nervous thing.
Yo, I got some bud upstairs,
you wanna draw?
Yeah, man.
Come then.
Go on, fam.
Yeah... I told you everything's kriss.
Don't worry about nothing. I'm going
to run upstairs and get those P's.
- Wait in there.
- Yeah, man.
Yeah. Soon come.
You a dead fucker!
♪ Look at you now all fucked up
♪ We had more than your new trainers
scuffed up
♪ Tried to play hard, in the end
You got fluffed up like a soft pillow
♪ We turn good wives to bad widows
♪ Take your pounds, your dollars
and your fucking Euros
♪ I got da kryptonite for superheroes
♪ Trying to get in my way
of getting that pay
♪ Don't talk about tomorrow
'cause the deadline's today
♪ Which means now, don't flinch
or it's "Bloa! Bloa!"
♪ Assassin style
No noise as you go down
no noise as you go down
♪ Hit 'em up, hit 'em up
Bullets pierce through guts
♪ It's either that or the gun butt
♪ We want the money right now
Give the funds up
♪ My crew rep to the death
so don't get plucked
♪ Hit 'em up, hit 'em up
♪ Bullets pierce through guts
♪ It's either that or the gun butt
♪ We want the money right now
give the funds up
♪ My crew rep to the death
so don't get plucked
♪ I don't play no games, I expose lames
♪ Strip you of the icy rings
and the gold chains
♪ Stray on my block, no love, boy
I cause pain
♪ Have your body wet up
like the cold rain
♪ Zampa boys too wild
and can't be tamed
♪ Something like an ape
♪ I want all the papes
and the fucking weed
♪ You better set speed
♪ Move now, boys
Slide like jet skis
♪ Now your boys wanna switch sides
♪ On your own in these hard times
You better duck when the slugs fly
♪ Other words you better run and hide
♪ Quick as a flash
'cause I'm about to duppy guys
♪ Kick back and smoke the sensei
after killing El Presidente
♪ We can go while it night and day
♪ I don't pet no powder or ramp or play
♪ Hit 'em up
Bullets pierce through the guts
♪ It's either that or the gun butt
♪ We want the money right now
Give the funds up
♪ My crew rep to the death
so don't get plucked
♪ Hit 'em up, hit 'em up ♪
Come on. Aah... fuck.
Fuck! Fuck!
- What you doing?
- I want your bag.
My bag? Are you dumb?
You ain't going to try and rob me.
- You got served, man.
- Yes, sir!
Bring that back!
My bag! My bag!
Hey! You fucking little shit.
Yo, blud.
Right now my man fucking just set me up.
I just got fucking robbed, rude boy.
Lost my fucking car.
I'm on da man dem endz right now.
- Yo, bring me my money.
- Blud, I got robbed, Don.
- Are you not hearing me?
- Bring my money.
- I'm trying to sort it out right now.
- Yo, you've got 20 minutes.
- Bring my 100 bags.
- I'm trying, blud. I'm trying.
Trying? Don't try, man. Do it!
I'll link you in a minute.
Who's he?
Yeah, what's cracking, fam?
- Fuck all.
- You cool.
- What you doing around here?
- I live around here.
- You live round here?
- I ain't seen your face before.
- I ain't seen your face neither.
In fact I don't even like
the look of you. Pussy hole.
Don't like the look of me?
You don't know me.
Forget the watch.
- What's with the yellow bandana?
- My yellow bandana
goes with my gold kick shoes.
I'm colour coordinated.
- Colour coordinated?
- Yeah.
What, you think man's small
you won't get touched pussy?
Fuck all of that.
- So where you off to?
- Right now I'm off to church.
Church?
Get off me! Get off me!
♪ What the fuck, what a rarse
♪ I should leave you with 16 scars
Bang you up, make you see 16 stars
♪ Stand in my yard
that's a instant war
♪ You want beating up price, let's brawl
♪ I've took your shit for far too long
Don't ramp, 'cause my head's all gone
♪ Mad sick and I ran out of medication
♪ You know, prat
Tell me what you think about that
♪ Skin a lickle more teeth
Smile with gap give a lickle more cheek
♪ Dislocate that make another fuss
You don't wanna do dat
♪ Don't think I'm idiot or I'm a prat
♪ That when you make a move
I won't swing back over yet
♪ I'm going to do you gonner
with a 14 pack
♪ Do you get that picture image flash
Wait! What you all do?
What kind of noise
you make inna God's church?
Wait. Now is me
grandpickney Terence is--
- Nanny, I'm going to church.
- Wait. You a go church?
Well, go on then!
What you no go. What you doing here?
Nothing. Nothing.
- Wanna come church?
- We don't wanna come to church.
- Come a church.
- Not today, not today.
Well, gwan you don't come in.
Gwan, you're momma yard.
Eh! Don't come back here again.
- What's he doing here?
- Know he ran over Twin, innit?
- You joking?
- He smashed her window as well.
- Seriously?
- Yeah. He's not going nowhere.
Know what, let's go in and get him out.
Let's go in and get him out.
This kid ain't going nowhere, come.
♪ So I'll cherish
♪ So I'll cherish the old rugged cross
Turn around.
Sing.
♪ Till my trophies
♪ At last I lay down
♪ I will cling to the old rugged cross
♪ And exchange it someday
♪ For a crown
- ♪ Oh, so I'll carry...
- Amen!
What a fitting hymn to bring
this wonderful service to its close.
Ahh, yes.
Indeed it is in the cross of Jesus,
that Old Rugged Cross...
- Yeah, man.
- ...that we find our identity.
- Amen.
- Go in peace.
Have a pleasant week.
God bless you. Goodbye.
Just have to go
and do a couple of things.
- Wait a little.
- I'm gonna go, Nanny.
You can go buy something
down the shops for me.
Go and buy two eggs for me,
one dozen eggs and two green bananas.
Me say come back here. Flash!
You no hear me, I call you.
- Flash!
- What brings you here today?
- It's nice to see you.
- My car's broken down.
Oh, yes, follow me this way.
Come this way with me.
Terence,
if we weren't meeting at church
where would you have gone?
I don't know. I was lucky.
I would have just had to
keep on running.
Terence, I think I can see Raymond
in the car behind me, you know.
- Let's see. What is it? A silver car.
- It's a silver car, man. Cover up.
Hi, Raymond, hi, Keisha. I ain't seen
you lot around here for a long time.
- You alright?
- Yeah, I'm fine y'know.
It's nice to see you. You must
pop into church one of them times
when you are in the area.
I need to see you there.
One day. I'm busy
dealing with life. You get me.
You're always saying that.
Look forward to seeing you.
You've been running, Terence,
for a long, long time.
The more you're running, the more
you're running into deeper trouble.
There comes a point, man,
you've got to stop.
Stop? How else am I meant
to support my five children, Big Man?
You've got five children and three
baby mothers, and you actually feel
that the way you're living your life,
they're going to be around to see you?
You're going to end up
six foot in a grave.
You're friends will mourn you
for a while, but they'll all walk away.
I know, Terence, that crime does pay.
Else people wouldn't get involved in it.
But it's the consequence
that crime brings,
you're constantly
looking over your shoulders.
- What kind of a lifestyle is that?
- I respect you, Big Man.
We need to sit down and
reason differently, one of these days...
- You walk tall.
- Yeah, man.
No doubt that police siren
is another incident
that's just gone off in the community.
Probably somebody else is dead.
That's what we're hearing every day,
man. You are causing it.
You and your friends are causing it.
You are taking away
the very sanctity of the neighbourhood
because of what you
are doing in the community.
And, sadly, you are killing each other.
You are exterminating your own race,
because of the stupidities
of your actions.
It's evil, Terence. It's evil.
I hear you, Big Man.
But, right now, if you give me
your number or something.
I beg you drop me
by town 'cause I need to,
I got one and two things I need to do.
♪ Ooh
♪ Bless our maker, heaven
♪ My
♪ Home ♪
- Yo.
- Yo, where are you?
Just hold tight for me.
Right now I'm coming to you.
You're really testing my patience now.
- If you don't...
- Hello?
Where are you?
I've already been here for four hours!
- It don't look good!
- Four hours!
How long you going to be?
Fuck, how long you going to be?
I'm sending someone
else out to get it.
No, look I'm coming to you right now,
bear with me.
Call that later... Yo.
Hello?
I know you've been there hours, I'm
coming to you. I can't move no quicker.
I'm under pressure.
If I ever told you I was going--
- I'm not joking.
- Relax yourself.
You said that about four, five
hours ago, you're on your way.
I know you're out, come out the heat,
sit down in the shade or something.
Dickhead. Prick.
- Hello.
- Yo, where's my money?
- ...a problem...
- What? Yo!
I'm waiting on you.
I've got people waiting on me.
I'm looking like a fucking prick
in front of them.
- That's your problem.
- Got it sorted. I'm there in a bit.
Fuck.
Yo! What you doing
in this part of town, blud?
Huh?
My mum brought me here
when I was younger.
What you saying?
Come here to do some shopping?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Been buying yourself some new shit,
I see. You got some new Airmax's
new trackie-b. Oh, God! And you got...
What's this patterns
and all sorts of shit?
Right now, blud. Listen to me.
You can't be in this part of town.
It's not our endz.
These youths are out here
looking for man right now.
I'm sure I can see them right there.
Come on, I can see them right there.
- Come. Come on!
- Yo, what!
There he is! There he is!
Got trousers that will match these?
This would look nice
with some baggy jeans.
That is a boom top...
What the hell?
- Oh, and it would be you.
- Daddy!
Mr Flash. What are you doing here?
- You alright?
- Hello, Daddy.
- What are yous lot doing in here?
- We found out already.
We know we're both your baby mothers.
You breeded us up at the same time.
- Think this is pimp thing?
- It's not.
- So what is it then?
- What is it?
- Think you're baller?
- Not a balling thing.
- Right now I love both of yous.
- You're a joker.
- You love both of us?
- You love her and you love me?
♪ To all the BM's
I know what you're going through
♪ You always have somebody's
baby dad approaching you
♪ Mine's a blag brother
and that's a bad shame
♪ So I give him a blag number
and a blag name
♪ Without a doubt
you're not fit to be a father
♪ I just found out
you got a third baby mother
♪ Got us fighting with each other
You're with me all the time
♪ He's a summertime man
Some of yours, some of mine
♪ Ladies if you see him
Don't look twice
♪ 'Cause he's nice from far
but far from nice
♪ She's holding his hand
he's happy and bruk
♪ She's pushing a pram
He's pushing his luck
♪ You're crazy, I'm not that lady
♪ And everyone can see
that Yout' is your baby
♪ Crying in my sleep
Sick of lying when you cheat
♪ Lie with me in the sheets
while you're lying through your teeth
- ♪ 'Cause men are from Mars
- ♪ And women are from Venus
- ♪ Women follow their hearts
- ♪ And men follow their...
- ♪ To raise my kids right
- ♪ Is the plan
- ♪ I'm never going to take
- ♪ No shite from a man
♪ Mr. F-L-A-S-H
Let's make sense
♪ Wait
I can see through you like an X-ray
♪ You remind me of my ex, Ray
♪ Explain why you are
never there for Ezray
♪ Always at ya best mate's
Well, that's what you tell me, anyway
♪ You're so broke
You're living off JSA
♪ Worst of all
you don't pay child support
♪ You might as well walk away
My mind's on pause
♪ Man, I loved ya
♪ I don't think I could put
nothing above ya
♪ Our relationship was great
but it's deflated into sacred bits
♪ Situations stinks 'cause you
cheated with her and what's-her-face
♪ Better watch I don't box your face
♪ Intoxicated love
I'm not the feisty one
♪ But just remember
that I'm your baby's mum first
I'm going to phone you in a bit.
- You idiot.
- Always running away.
Who's this? Your other youth?
- I'll talk to yous later.
- He's running away like a girl.
- He can't handle us.
- It's not like that.
Flash!
I'm not about to be
running in these heels.
Worst day of my life, rude boy.
You see the wickedest part of it,
I'm on the fucking bus,
like some wasteman, rude boy.
Late for El Prezzie's day as well. Shit.
There's Flash.
How are you?
What's popping, Don?
- Cool, cuz?
- Wagwan?
- Cool, cuzzie?
- Cool, cuz?
- Mmm.
- What's popping?
Yo, blud, Angel's looking for you, blud.
- He's on a mad thing, Don.
- Beating off his gums, blud?
Beating them off, blud. Watch out,
you get me. He's on a mad one.
If Prezzie was about still.
Streets ain't been the same
since he's gone.
Swear. In a mad way, I can still hear
the nigger's voice in my head.
All the tracks that we
did together and that, man.
Even down to the other day
I was listening to the CD still.
Mmm.
Blud, right now, my man
was there for me, you get me?
When my mum kicked me out my yard, Don,
he was the only one who took me in.
The geezer kept me out of trouble,
blud, you get me?
When I was on a mad thing,
he made sure that I didn't go jail.
I love him for that.
Blud, I feel it for you, Don.
Got kicked out of my house, too.
- Wish I knew him.
- My man was a Dads.
You get me? Straight Dads.
He had the streets boxed
when he was on road. D'you get me?
Serious.
We need to go do what we got to do,
blud. For our nigger.
- Don't want to hear nothing else.
- I hear what you're saying. I hear you,
but a certain time, that's not
always the way, you get me?
- It's not always the way.
- I don't care about the way.
It's about El Prezzie.
They killed our nigger.
There is a time
and a place for everything.
I knew you were going to come out
with that. I don't want to hear that,
Don't wanna hear about
no time and place.
Listen, listen.
- Just forget it.
- Shut your mouth.
Don't speak.
Know who you are speaking to.
- Don't speak.
- As long as a year down the line
I'm not here same place, same thing,
but at your graveside, you get me.
- That's all I'm sayin'.
- I don't care about me, blud.
What I care about is my nigger, blud.
El Prezzie, Don. This is for you.
Straight away. Till I die.
T-R-U.
Yo, I got one of El Prezzie's
tunes on my phone, you know, Don.
- Yeah. Play it.
- Yeah. Run that.
♪ This is the life that I've chosen
♪ This dog life has left
my mother's heart broken
♪ Yes
I've done everything imaginable
♪ I've influenced the ends
and made it fashionable
♪ I've learnt to live
with all of my regrets
♪ My enemies will celebrate
my untimely death
♪ Slewed by weapons
♪ The crew I am repping won't contribute
to my funeral expenses
♪ This is Birmingham
The place where some fear
♪ Gangs have run riot around here
for 15 years
♪ Hard if you aren't affiliated
♪ If you are then it's worse
The other side hate it
♪ 'Cause these streets are no joke thing
♪ I've got an army full of youths
that I've roped in
♪ Now witness the end of my lifeline
♪ Children of my crimes
is the legacy I leave behind
♪ My life is that raw
♪ I can see my world stumble
like I falling through a trap door
♪ You was one of the few that I'd
blast for, but now you're gone
♪ Don, I feel like it's the last straw
♪ It's been a year
and I can still remember that call
♪ "EP's dead, they shot him
outside the black store"
♪ And it's been on
and popping ever since
♪ But ever since I can't help
to wonder why we busting gatts for
♪ It's like my back's to the wall
There's no turning back for us all
♪ 'Cause they after us all
♪ And the only thing to do
is stay strapped for the war
♪ Anyone test they getting
clapped with the four
♪ But I don't wanna see
the cemetery no more
♪ See one of my boys
get buried no more
♪ But I'm ever ready till the day
that we fall, so it's forever
♪ We're true
so we're kicking in doors together
♪ They fucking killed my nigger
Yo, he's fucking gone
♪ Fuck this
I'm on a fucking mad thing
♪ Fucking Zampa nigger's face
I'll be stamping
♪ I got the nine in the
fucking waistline, I bust two shots
♪ Kite, man, I never waste time
♪ You take lice
you could never take mine
♪ You get merked by the bullet
and the tech nine
♪ Tek time 'cause I take mine
let the tech shine, let the tech shine
♪ Yo, you niggers better drop back
Four or five in the waist
♪ Nine in the rucksack
♪ Bust two shots at a nigger
like fuck dat
♪ I'm fucking hyphy
Yeah, you know I'm hyphy
♪ Run up in the fucking crib
kill your fucking mum and your wifey
♪ I'm a bad boy for lifey
♪ Zampa gets shanked
by the end of the knifey
Oi, they are there!
Yo Flash! We're watching ya!
Fuck that, man! Put that down!
Are you fucking dumb?
- We're in the graveyard, you know.
- I'm cutting loose, blud.
- I'm leaving.
- Hold on Angel's.
Come, blud.
- Hello?
- Flash!
Nanny, I'm coming for you.
Where are you?
♪ Someday
♪ Somebody will make you proud ♪
Wait.
Where do you think you a go?
Why did you bring him here?
He have nowhere else to go?
Me no want him in here, you know.
You better go in you momma house.
You better come in and wipe
your foot good before you come in.
Me no want him in here.
Quick though... Ah...
Don't take off your shoe,
don't take off your shoe!
- Listen!
- Nanny!
Wait. Leave him alone!
- How do you mean, Mum?
- Wait.
But, Mum, the little boy
was feisty with me.
Me never hear say no...
You no love him, but me love him.
But you wasn't here.
Me need to talk to you now.
Where do you want these?
Just put the bags down,
and come back here to me.
But, Mum, me can't have him
feisty with me so.
Hallo, Mum.
- Are you alright though me, son?
- Yeah, man. How's your day been?
It's one of them days right now.
- One of them days?
- Yeah.
Well, let me cook a pot of food,
you know.
I ain't got time to
eat that right now...
What you a say to me?
You don't have time?
Right now, sit down,
fe long time to eat
and you're going to eat with us today,
no doubt about it.
- But, Mum, right now...
- But, Mum, but, but...
- Listen to me.
- I got to go up the road.
Yo, wagwan? What is with this man?
- You seen Angel?
- You know I seen Angel.
You dropped him off. He got
what he wanted and then he left.
- You seen Evil?
- Evil? Who's Evil?
- Why you asking me such nonsense?
- Why you always got this attitude?
'Cause I am sick of you.
What makes you think I want
Mum and everyone to know my business?
Always talking with this attitude.
What's wrong with you?
- 'Cause I'm sick of you.
- Taleisha, stop and eat your food.
Why are you always defending him
and blaming me?
Like the time I brought home
that pen that didn't belong to me,
you beat me black and blue.
What about when he brought that
stolen TV, you watched EastEnders.
Did you never watch EastEnders 'pon it?
- That's so not the point.
- You never benefit?
You're a girl child,
you can't do what a man do.
Me never bring
you up as no tramp.
Aaah!
That's why pickney no should get beaten.
You want to come to church with me?
Nanny, my generation don't too believe
in the church thing, you know.
We believe in the big bang.
Big bang? What you name so?
What are you a call big bang?
You know, evolution,
the beginning of time.
Instead of, like, God at the beginning,
there was a big bang,
and that's what created everything.
Don't you know about evolution?
- No.
- Evolution. Beginning of time.
- The big bang.
- You know something.
If you no come a church with me,
you're gonna hell and you a gonna burn.
You know when they gave you that bible
they gave you in the slave days.
To turn the other cheek.
It was a mind control.
Right now there is a big conspiracy
going on. The Illuminati, Freemasons.
- They got us really confused.
- Freemasons?
- Yeah.
- What name Freemasons?
Me not know about Freemasons.
They're involved in the conspiracy
to keep the black man down.
Me and you need to sit down and reason.
Personally, I'm trying to
elevate myself, get my mind right
so I can activate my seven chakras.
Shackles, me no know what you call so.
Chakras, if you activate your
seven chakras, you can activate
your pioneer gland. Then me and you
can speak without speaking.
Bullshit. All you're doing is running
out there with your gang-banging-self
selling your drugs, keeping
yourself down. And what about us women?
Breeding up. One after another.
You're just full of shit.
Stop. We not talk about big bang,
pioneer gland,
goddamn pen and thiefing TV.
Wanna stop man, all me want to do
is eat me food and get fat.
- Go away.
- Oi!
Who dat lick down the window so?
Are that Pest again?
- Hi, you alright, babe?
- Yeah, I'm cool.
- Is Flash there?
- Yeah, he's here. Flash!
Who is it?
What you running away from us for
like some little bitch?
- I'm not running away.
- Flash! Where's my money?
No, on a level. Who is this sket here?
Who you calling a "sket"?
I'm his baby mother.
- Baby mother!
- Who's this?
- I don't know this girl.
- You don't know me?
If you don't know me,
then what is this?
Oh, how did I know? So if she don't
know you, why has she got your things?
Don't you love me no more?
You know something, ladies,
real talk, I love all of yous.
Pussy, please! Really? A wasteman.
So you love her, you love her
and you love me.
- Yeah.
- You don't know what love is, babe.
- Spell love.
- L-O-V--
Shut up.
You're a wasteman, fully.
And you got a pickney, too?
Why you making so much noise?
Why are you making up so much noise for?
We don't mean to be rude,
you know.
We're not trying to be
rude in any kind y'know.
We just need to show yer
that your son's just bang out of order.
I'll tell you something.
- ♪ Men are from Mars
- ♪ And women are from Venus
- ♪ Women follow their hearts
- ♪ And men follow their...
Move! Move from me front door!
Move from the front door!
Move from me front door!
We're going! We're going!
- Get in the house, blud.
- Hey, baby.
- Wha'appen?
- How you doing? You alright?
- Why you grab him up so?
- Nuttin', don't watch nuttin'.
- You're alright?
- Yeah. How are you?
- Long time me no see you.
- You're looking beautiful as usual.
You're looking healthier
every time I see you.
- Me hot like fire, you know.
- Smashing, smashing, fire.
Whoo-ee!
- There's mummy.
- Alright, little man.
- Look who's there.
- How's things?
- Yeah. Cool, cool.
- Here's Kenneth.
- How you doing, Mummy? Are you alright?
- Wait. Yeah, me alright.
- A long time me no see him, you know.
- He's growing up.
- Him grow a biggie.
- Yeah, man, I'm growing definitely.
So you're gone?
No, one minute, still,
going round the back.
- You go and what you go do?
- Going to talk.
- Mum, what kind of question is that?
- How you mean?
- Leave them, they're big men.
- Him just come and him gone already!
Yo. Where's my money, blud?
- Where's my money, blud?
- I got robbed, Don.
- Yo, taking the fucking piss?
- I'm not taking the piss, Don.
I'm going to make you watch
while I light up your nan, your mum,
your mouthy sister, your babies,
I'm saying, your baby mothers.
Then I'm going to duppy you
when I am done. You understand me?
- I hear you, cuz. I hear you.
- Fucking joke.
- Kenneth, you want one cup of tea?
- No, I'm alright.
- Me put sugar in it already.
- It's okay, Nan, it's alright.
Den a what dat you hide
in behind back of you?
- Just smoking, Nan.
- You not hear me say you not fe smoke?
Sorry, Nanny, sorry.
Yo, blud. You think it's a joke?
You think it's a joke, blud?
It's not a joke.
You get robbed like a pussyclot
and you're crying. Don't cry to me.
Cry to your mum. Fucking joker.
And you stabbed someone.
You drove over someone.
What the fuck was you doing over there?
I said, what the fuck
was you doing over there?
- I fucked up. Yeah.
- You fucked up?
Yeah, blud. Yeah, man.
You fucked up, blud.
Yeah, blud.
Look in my eyes. Tell me how
you're going to get my money to me.
Right now I got my Roley,
I got a necklace, a bracelet, a ring.
I got, like, four grand
worth of dope here.
I got eight bags of food put down.
I got two stones at my sister's.
And I got some scrilla put down
up there. Should be over 100 bags.
Make sure you link me at 12, you know.
Happy Shopper car park.
- Are you listening to me?
- I hear you, I'll be there.
- Yo, big man.
- Are you taking the piss?
- It's Angel.
- Where's my money?
Had a minor hiccup with that thing,
but I'll link you at one.
- One o'clock.
- Alright, cool, cool.
Yo, Evil's a joker, innit.
Evil's evil, star, straight violation.
You can kill him if you want, you know.
Kill him, blud, I don't mind.
I just want my money. Show me
some love, man. What's all that?
Come here, man.
♪ Oooh
♪ De blind man
♪ Stood on de road
♪ And cried
♪ Cryin'
♪ What kind of shoes
♪ Am dose you wear ♪
Where the fuck is my things?
I put them in here. Right here.
Right here.
When me find something
inna my garden, this here you look for?
This? This you bring come inna my house?
- I'm in some serious trouble, Mum.
- Serious trouble?
What kind of trouble you in a so?
What's this? All drugs?
Yeah.
Sorry about this, Mum. I just
need to pay the man back his money.
Right now, it's bigger than me.
I need to give him his things today.
- Why you bring this in here?
- I need it for the way I'm living, Mum.
"Need if for the way I living."
How you living?
This is what I do.
I sell drugs and bang guns.
Sell drugs and bang guns?
- That's not so me bring you up.
- I know. Sorry, Mum.
- Sorry?
- They've been buried there for ages.
- It was just safekeeping.
- Safekeeping.
You wasn't thinking about me, son.
You a think about yourself.
Mum, the way I'm living I was thinking
about you. I need to have that around.
- You need to have that around?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- 'Cause anything could happen.
People know where you live, they come,
I need to be able to get my things.
But why them want to come to me? Why me?
- To hurt me, innit?
- To hurt you.
- So what kind of trouble you inna so?
- I just owe the man some money...
Oh, Terence...
I took the man's things and I ain't
got the money to pay him his money,
and he wants his money.
Right now they're threatening
every-- Mum, my whole family.
- Whole family?
- Whole family.
Then you put my life in danger,
your brother and your sister. Everybody!
Why you do this? Why? Why?
You can't do this to me, Terence.
You can't. You bring gun,
come inna me house.
You have drugs inna me house.
Why you doing this?
- I'm sorry, Mum.
- Why?
- Sorry?
I got to go, Mum.
- Please, please, please.
- I got to go, Mum.
Where you going?
- Sorry, Mum.
- You think sorry can help?
- Hallo.
- You alright, mate?
- Full tank in there, boss.
- Thank you.
Flash, wait for me!
So how come you're taking him, not me?
How old are you now, Swipe?
- I'm ten.
- Ten.
- Next year.
- Whatever. Promise?
After what happened earlier,
when we're ready, blud.
Cool.
Ladies and Gentlemen.
I've been trying to phone you
from ages ago. Where've you been, man?
Mum, man...
My baby, my baby.
Come give your Mama a hug.
- Don't even start, man.
- Why you just pushing me like this?
What is it? What have I done?
Baby, come give your mummy a hug.
I haven't seen you in ages.
Why are you cha, cha, cha this for?
What's that?
What the heck? Thought you'd have
been in something better than this.
But you look good though. I like it.
- You got new clothes and everything.
- So what?
You look good.
Come give your mum some money, man.
Money, Mum? I'm living on the street.
You roll with the top man,
and you ain't got no any money at all?
- Top man? No, I don't.
- So what am I going to do, huh?
- What am I going to do?
- What do you mean? What am I gonna do?
- I'm gonna get a new mum.
- Alright, I can't do this.
This is hurting my head.
Come give me something, man.
What the heck,
shotting my mum shit like that.
Come. See you later.
Why you still in here?
Always talking. Always talking.
- Chat, chat...
- Just shut...
- Relax up, man.
- Come give me something.
Two minutes, Pest.
- I need something.
- What the fuck's wrong with you?
How can you be behaving like that
in front of your youth? You mad?
- Just give me something.
- Take this.
- I don't want to hear this shit.
- What's this, man? Who's this for?
Ants?
What's wrong with you, blud?
What the fuck do you mean,
what's wrong with me?
- Right now, blud...
- Shotting shit to my fucking mum.
- You're on the road, Don.
- On the road.
Do I give a shit about the fucking road?
Make sure you've got money. This morning
you never had nothing to eat.
You hadn't had a change,
hadn't had a wash for days.
I don't care. Why are you shotting my
mum shit though, man? What the fuck?
Getting all emotional, blud.
You look weak, rude boy.
Man'll walk all over you if
you're looking weak, you know.
You understand that? Look,
you don't want to be doing that shit.
Fix up, rude boy.
Are you rolling with me or not?
If you crying and shit like a baby,
blud, get out of the car.
Huh?
- Treating me like this?
- Fix the fuck up, blud.
- You, blud.
- Me?
Shut up, man.
Crying like some
little fucking girl, blud.
Here, hold this.
Start work for me tomorrow, but take
note of everything I do, you hear me?
Trick is to deal with them
as quick as possible.
- Yo, blud.
- Fucking hell.
What's popping, G?
Man was beginning to think
you were dead. What the fuck?
Man, left man waiting out there
for over five hours.
- I'm going to give you the thing.
- It's hot anyway.
- Yeah, yeah. It's hot.
- Cool.
- Sauna.
- Yeah, yeah.
Yo, Flash, what the fuck you call this?
Here, take these couple.
Deal with the rest of it later on.
- What you got for me?
- You want more, Don?
Don't fuck with me, rude boy. Yo.
- Alright, yeah.
- Walk safe with it, G.
In a minute.
Yo, Flash, you take the piss.
Blud, my day's been fucked up.
I don't care about your day.
There's been money to be made out there,
and you there taking the piss.
Who's this little shit anyway?
- Shut the fuck up.
- See...
See, while you're there picking up
little hood rats, you get me,
money's just been taking its time
to come, you get me?
But anyway, sort me out
with a little soops.
Safe.
Just doing business.
Hold it, yeah?
That scrilla, blud.
Getting hold of the money,
seven thousand pounds
in a 120 seconds, rude boy.
What time is it?
- I'm on point.
- You better be.
You alright, baby? Hmm?
Sorry about earlier, man.
This pretty face.
Don't move away from me.
S'wrong? Not talking to me
because of that bullshit?
Baby? Hmm?
I need my money, babe.
I'm going to have the money
for you later, alright.
- You know I love you, innit.
- I love you, too.
Hmm?
So sexy.
Flash!
Gentlemen.
Cool. Yeah.
- You seen Ashantay?
- Me no see her.
Big man.
You cool? Yeah, man. Yeah.
Cool.
Man, you alright?
- You alright?
- Yeah, I'm alright.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
- Sorted out everything still.
- You sure?
Yeah, it's alright.
See Ashantay, Mummy?
She over there in the kitchen
there, so you know.
Ashantay, baby. What's happening?
Why, what you saying?
Not much. Just come to tell you
how much I love you.
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
- Okay. What's brought all this on?
- Nothing.
Going to marry you one of
these days, you know that, don't you?
- Married.
Suppose you're going get me
a big house in the country?
Umm-hmm.
- Big ring.
- So where's my ring?
I'm going to buy you one real soon,
when I buy you the house...
So, really, what's going on?
I'm kind of in some trouble.
You always come to me when you're
in trouble. What is it this time?
Money trouble.
I wanted to believe it,
but I was just waiting for it.
You're in trouble so you come
sniffing around me. What do you want?
You want the chain?
The one good thing you give me?
I'm going to get you another one.
I just need to take it for a hot second.
Not bad enough I have to care
for the youths all of the time,
and the one little thing
that I've got, you want.
You know what, take it,
I don't even want nothing from you.
You can have it. Yeah?
- You got what you want now.
- You know I love you, innit.
Save it. Just save it.
♪ Hell, no
♪ Trying to take us
for some kind of fool
♪ He's a player who just broke the rules
♪ Let me tell you how it's gonna go
♪ Oh
- ♪ Hell, no
- Hello?
♪ We need to talk
thought I'd give you a bell
- ♪ Is it about Flash, I'm vex
- ♪ I can tell
♪ He's a wasteman
♪ He knows it
he's got a whole heap of girl
- ♪ And he's always chasin'
- ♪ Dutty boy
♪ Pussy boy, prick he thinks he's slick
Always trying to get up inside
♪ With his little dick
He thinks he's sick
♪ I'm watching my kids
while he's watching my thighs
♪ He's watching my lips
while I'm watching Sky
♪ Digital, typical
none of his moves are original
♪ Ain't even got a provisional
♪ Don't raise his kids
He's old and he's miserable
♪ Can't act like a simple individual
♪ Murk him with every word
verb, every syllable
♪ Trust me
He's a fool, you know
- ♪ Tried to come round here
- ♪ Joke ting
♪ Trying to go, "I love you, I love you"
And he's took my necklace
♪ He raw snatched my necklace
without me knowing
♪ My man's gone off
Don't know where he's gone
♪ Be warned
don't mess with a woman scorned
♪ Got a lot of talk
that can leave a woman torn
- ♪ To perform, you're a born actor
- ♪ He's my answer
♪ Making us think he was
taking the time out
♪ Playing us
Thinking we'd never find out
- ♪ We nabbed him, thought he was smart
- ♪ Caught him
- ♪ Caught him, walked over us
- ♪ Like it was a walk in the park
- ♪ You said you liked me
- ♪ Then you call me wifey
- ♪ Constantly on my psyche
- ♪ You take our feelings lightly
- ♪ He cheated on you
- ♪ He cheated on me
- ♪ That's one
- ♪ Found out
♪ There's three
I'm sick of this, just let it be
♪ 'Cause she cannot do it like me
Jeez!
Have to roll into this house
and get my last 28 grand, blud.
Hold these for me, wish me luck.
Get me two stones, as well.
If my sister nabs me in here
I'm fucked, blud. Here, grab this.
Two secs, blud.
This is raw gully, Don.
Jeez.
Aah... Evil, Evil.
- Hello?
- Put Evil on the phone, you slut.
Who you calling a slut?
Why you phone me so late?
I'm outside your fucking house.
Come to the window.
Put him on the fucking phone.
Flash is outside,
I think he's heard everything.
- Is he stupid? Yo, Flash.
- Where's my fucking money?
You're lucky I didn't lick off
your dome when I was in the house.
You're lucky you was next
to my sister. Where's my money?
I ain't got no scrilla for you.
What d'you mean you ain't got no
scrilla? I want my 100 thousand. Mmm?
You think I'm some dickhead,
you set me up.
Where's my fucking scrilla?
You're in there banging my sister
as well, are you nuts?
That's Angel's girlfriend.
You got no fucking manners.
Plus, the man just come out
the bloodclot pen, rude boy.
- What's wrong with you?
- What you talking about?
I'm not banging your sister.
I come to sort something out.
To bring something.
What you talking about?
Drop off a nut? I just come out the
house. I could hear the "Huh, huh, huh."
You think I'm stupid? Do you
really think I'm fucking stupid?
Right now you best rides with my money,
meet me at the happy copper shop,
the happy fucking cop,
the happy, whatever the fuck...
You know what I'm talking about.
Meet me there at 12 with my
scrilla or I'm blowing you up.
- Hearing what I'm saying to you?
- Trying to blackmail me?
- Exactly that.
- Hear what I'm saying to you:
I'm going to be at the
Happy Shopper car park at 12
but I'm telling you,
you're not gonna live long enough
- to spend the money.
- Suck your mum, dickhead.
So where we going now?
- What time is it?
- It's 11.30, Don. We got half an hour.
Right now I'm going to crank off
and smoke a spliff. Relax for a minute.
El Prezzie...
I miss him.
You like that, don't ya?
Yeah.
It's not a toy, rude boy.
I'm not saying I'm not going to give
ya it 'cause you might need it, now.
The Zampa boys know your face.
If you're really ready, and you want to
be a gunman... Take it.
Just know what you're doing.
Don't burst it unless you feel
it's absolutely necessary,
it's the only option left.
You wanna be a gunman, do ya?
Wanna dump off, bust shots
get locked the fuck up,
rot in the pen, rot in the grave?
See my homey right here, Don.
Look, cuz, you see here.
El Presidente, that's what killed him,
one a them, one slug.
Bang! He's dead, blud.
He ain't coming back,
kids ain't got no daddy...
It's real shit.
Saying you still want it?
Hmm? Can handle 35 years
if you kill a man?
And that's before parole.
Next thing you know,
40 years and you're coming out
when you're 50-odd, Don.
The age that you are now.
Are you ready for that?
Hmm?
Fuck it, if you think you're ready,
you can have it.
What's going to happen now?
Hopefully, Evil comes with the scrilla.
Pay Angel. Zampa boys keep my ride.
Today has just been one big nightmare.
If not? Fuck it! Come! Pass the dog.
Come.
We're going to dump these Zampas!
Going to burn man's skin.
Fuck that. They already know what it is.
You get me. It's the OSC.
♪ It's like their forgetting their
place, so I gotta get up in their face
♪ Carrying the venom on da waist
You never wanna see me in the darkness
♪ I'm a show this bitch
who's the hardest
♪ Regardless
Straight from the pen and I'm heartless
♪ It's cash dat I harvest
but da man dem are taking da piss
♪ I hope they know they're takin'
a risk, tryna tek man fi idiot
♪ I show them I'm serious
wid more force than previous
♪ You don't wanna get the angel evilous
I win fuck even scores
♪ I delete with the heat
Fuck remorse
♪ They betta gimme the P's
to link my source
♪ Or it's a permanent pause
they'll sink, of course
♪ We're gonna ride again
We're gonna ride again
♪ We're gonna kill 'em
when we come through
- What?
- ♪ Kill 'em when we come through
♪ We're gonna ride again
We're gonna ride again
♪ We're gonna kill 'em
when we come through
- What?
- ♪ Kill 'em when we come through
♪ For Flash, that boy gonna get merk'd
like chicken disposed when it gets burnt
♪ Gonna be a bit more than a little hurt
It's gonna be murder, murder
♪ Better grab that four leaf clover
after running my bredrin over
♪ Trying to fuck
with the Zampa soldiers
♪ Run him down like ten ton boulders
♪ Bring the heat down colder, leave your
clothes red like cherry aid soda
♪ Shoot the money bag off your shoulder
♪ See your face on a missing poster
It's over, it's over
♪ Gatt in my hand
I don't need no holster
♪ Gatt in my hand quick time
I'll ghost ya
♪ I'll ghost ya
♪ We're gonna ride again
We're gonna ride again
♪ We're gonna kill 'em
when we come through
♪ Kill 'em when we come through
Kill 'em when we come through
♪ We're gonna ride again
We're gonna ride again
♪ Gonna kill 'em when we come through
Kill 'em when we come through
♪ Gimmie da dough, I got places to go
I got things that's ready to blow
♪ Bullshit, bury it low, dem fools
I hope they know what the time is
♪ I'ma show dem who's the livest and
you don't wanna collide with the things
♪ That I ride wid
and someone's gotta pay
♪ I been waiting all day for the pape's
and waiting is one thing I hate
♪ And snakes who hide
tryna play both sides
♪ Don't fuck wid my ties tryna
jeopardise my merchandise
♪ I'm hurting guys definitely when
the lead does fly fuck the blys
♪ I don't play these games
when I see you
♪ Why you acting strange
'cause you haven't got my change
♪ Prang in your brains so
I'ma make you feel the pain
Yo, everybody get down, we soon reach.
I Don't want these pussy holes
to know you're with me.
- Pass that gun.
- What the fuck do you mean?
You just gave me a big lecture, Don.
What the heck?
- So I meant to leave it.
- What? You left the fucking gun, blud?
If anything fucking happens,
I'm gonna fucking kill you,
you understand that? Fucking joke thing.
I want to clap him, you know.
We're not gonna hurt them,
this geezer's a knob, you know.
Tell me to leave it and that.
What the fuck kind of snake shit
is that, blud?
How could you fucking
set me up you fucking snake?
What? Fuck you.
Who the fuck are you? Huh?
Are you a doctor? Huh? Are you a lawyer?
No, you're a fucking drug dealer.
What do you do for the community?
Huh? My name's Evil,
you know how I get down. What?
Blud, you're meant to be
fucking family, rude boy.
Family?
The only family I had was El Presidente.
When he died and I seen none of you
weren't riding and you ain't real?
I said any opportunity I gonna have,
I'm going to rob you.
- What?
- Yo. Shut the fuck up, hear me.
When the cat's away the mice
will fucking play. I'm fucking back.
- Give me my fucking money.
- Pass the fucking scrilla, blud.
Fucking geezer.
- Fuck you.
- Watch me.
Fuck you.
You're wrong, you know, you're wrong.
I'm gonna deal with you later.
Alright, cool.
Give me that.
Here, man. Walk away, blud.
You been fucking around all day.
Oi, Evil's banging your girl behind
your back. Evil mashed your girl.
- I saw him, blud.
- You mashing my fucking girl?
I swear I saw him Blud.
Going to believe them dickheads over me?
- I swear, I saw him.
- What the fuck?
I took a picture!
Fuck you!
Fuck this!
Yo, Kite.
Oi...
Fucked up.
Apache! Yo, fuck, man. Apache.
Apache.
- Apache...
- Yo, blud, take the P's, Don.
Take the P's?
I can't leave you here like this, blud.
- Go. Get out of here. Go then.
- Can't leave you...
- Come on, Flash.
- Get out of here man.
- Go...
- Quick! Come on, man. Hurry up, man!
Hurry up!
Come on, blud.
Hurry up, man. Hurry up!
Wait, I wonder who that?
It's me, Nan.
This hour of the night,
what you do here, boy?
I'm going to stay here tonight, Nan.
I'm going to sleep in the back room.
Which part inna the back room you a sleep?
I'm going to sleep on the floor,
or the settee.
Me new brand settee that me just buy?
- No. Just for tonight, Nan.
- Just for the one night.
You come wake me up out of my sleep.
- You feisty...
- Sorry, Nan.
You know something?
Me a gonna tell you momma, you know.
Me a going to call you momma
and tell her.
Not come back here again,
you better come out.
Me no want you here.
You hear me say?
Ah, Oh!
Flash.
Flash, oi.
Is Kite dead?
Is... Are all of them dead?
Don't worry about that right now.
Tomorrow I'm going to
sort out everything.
Done it with this road thing, blud.
You see this here, this 100 grand here,
you can do anything you like,
you hear me? Where would you like to go?
America.
Tomorrow we sort it out. We go America.
Go to sleep, and don't worry
about nothing. It's going to be cool.
You hear me. Go to sleep.
Blud, are you going to
answer your phone, man?
Fuck, man.
- Yo.
- Yo, you need that food still?
- Yo...
- I don't know, you know.
- I don't know.
- Where's Flash?
- We need the food still?
- Yeah... Yeah.
Tell him I got three bricks, 100 bags.
Yeah, safe, you know what? Make it four.
Put Flash on the phone!
- Yo.
- Yo. You want that then?
What you saying? Three boxes, 100 bags.
Make it three and a half
and I'll take it.
You know the deal. Link me in
the same spot half an hour, yeah?
Yeah, yeah.
Are you coming or what?
Come on man, fix up.