I'm stronger than you!
There's Uncle Jeff.
Bye, guys.
- You'll bring us salmon?
- You bet!
Bye, my love.
Safe trip.
Bye, kiddos.
You alright?
Yeah, top shape. Why?
With sunny skies everywhere,
it's a beautiful fall day,
and the weekend...
I'm not so sure about this.
What?
OK.
Yes!
Let's keep it tidy.
Which drawer do you want?
I'd like the bottom one.
Marco, take whatever one you want.
Sam, mind if I take
the bottom drawer?
Sam?
What are you doing?
If I want to be in shape for later...
Hey, bank boss, we're in Amsterdam.
Move, before I slug you.
- What are you doing?
- Getting ready to go out.
No shaving. We've gone fishing.
Wake up!
I'll put on clean undies at least.
What are you doing?
Aren't you going to unpack?
You bet.
Guys, wait for me. Guys!
Who's gonna roll?
Eeny, meeny, miny, moe,
Catch a tiger by the toe...
And you are it!
Why do I always lose?
Want to vote instead?
I hate you.
Come on!
I'm as nervous
as for my first communion.
All you need
is your leopard g-string.
So, have you ever played around?
I'd have told you.
Why are you asking?
No reason.
Move over.
- Move, move!
- Take it easy.
What are you doing?
Here.
You can't be serious.
Where'd you find it?
It'll help us rise and shine.
What are you up to?
We're here to party, but...
Shit, guys. When we were
planning our trip back home,
you were ready for anything,
but now you're...
What did we say?
You only live once.
C'mon!
If I'm going to hell,
then with my pals!
Cheers!
- Godawful!
- Your turn.
So, in the Red Light District...?
The book says,
when you see a girl you like,
you knock on her door, pay her,
and you get it on.
Love at first sight!
Do you have to bargain?
I hope not
'cause you'd get screwed.
Jerks!
Don't worry, it's a flat rate.
But how do you choose?
Me, to get hard,
I need to chat a bit first.
Choose one who looks like Béatrice.
It'll feel like home.
I hope they're OK.
My daughter was getting a cold.
Why don't we call them?
Ask if they did their homework,
what they ate for supper,
if things are OK?
Guys...
You sound like old farts.
Party.
Let's go, you clowns!
Well...
see you later.
See you at the hotel.
Hello.
Christ, you're gorgeous.
You have the same eyes.
It's just, we've been trying for 10 years.
I find it strange, that's all.
I don't give a shit about statistics.
Anything to tell me, Madeleine?
No, no, course not.
I'm happy.
Yeah, they're really biting.
Kiss you. Bye.
Me too.
Jeff? Jeff!
Sam's not back!
71.
What's he doing here?
75. This is the place.
Hey, you clowns!
Wanna tango with some trout?
Hi!
This is Juul, our fishing guide.
C'mon.
We won't be completely lying.
So, you studs?
Last night?
It was alright.
Shit, I want details, boys!
It's like bicycling.
You don't forget.
Like bicycling?
Wow, must've been steamy!
Me, not so good.
Oh yeah?
Yeah.
Couldn't get it up?
I thought of Madeleine.
No big deal.
Nah, it's no big deal.
You'll do better tonight.
Fish on, boys!
Holy shit!
Madeleine's pregnant.
She told me as I was leaving.
What?
So that explains it!
Welcome to the club!
Finally! You'd given up hope!
One guy squirmed through.
Mom said never trust doctors,
or bank managers!
Right.
Brother-in-law,
I'm so happy for you both.
You tried for so long.
Sam, this calls for a celebration!
See you at the hotel.
Sam, don't freak out.
I was a wreck with my first.
Sam, come on!
He didn't come back.
Good idea, let's pack.
There must be something else.
I'm sure.
It's not just the baby.
There's gotta be more to it.
Come on, you freaked out
with your first.
- What are you doing?
- My mouth's dry.
Go easy on that,
we're flying home.
Maybe he's in
the Red Light District.
To see if he can get it up.
I'll go shower.
Save time in the morning.
Tell the front desk to wake us.
Jeff! Sam's not back.
No way!
Christ, our flight.
Bea can't find out about our trip.
- OK, relax.
- Yeah, relax.
And you? They'll love this
at the bank. Fucking shit!
- Look, don't freak out!
- Freak out?
We have to look for him.
Where?
Don't ever pull that again!
I figured I should tell you.
What?
That I won't be flying with you.
Wait. You can't do that.
I need some time.
A couple of days.
The plan only works
if you come too.
Enough horsing around.
You're coming!
We're all boarding that plane.
Get off me.
What'll we tell the girls?
Sam, shit!
Sam, wait, fuck!
- Tell 'em I stayed at the camp.
- No.
Madeleine will charge down there.
Forget it. You're coming with us.
That's final.
Please, guys.
Help me, OK?
Sam, stop.
Shit, what are we going to do?
Quit fooling around.
Sam, stop.
Shit!
You can't. Fuck, our plan!
Sam, stop it.
If you do this, you bastard...
I don't want that baby. No way.
Don't you get it?
I'll come Wednesday.
Do it for me, guys.
I love you, guys.
It's Daddy!
Hi, kiddo. Where's Dad?
Let me catch my breath.
I hope you brought trout.
Or we'll be eating you.
Don't I get a kiss?
Sorry.
Where's my dad?
Give Uncle Jeff a break.
Take your bath.
Forget the bath.
Just put them to bed.
Should we order some pizza?
Jeff, has anything happened?
Well...
- Yes and no.
- Where are the others?
We think that
Sam went into the woods.
What?
What do you mean?
It's been 24 hours.
- 24 hours?
- He'll be back.
Tomorrow or the day after...
- He probably wanted to be alone.
- Wait.
Did he leave or is he lost?
We woke up yesterday, he was gone.
So we figure...
I bet he's at Jodoin's trailer.
He must be.
We checked. He wasn't there.
Since it was raining, we...
It was sunny here.
Well, it rained there.
We wanted to tell you.
I'm going back to search
with Marco.
Why'd he go off by himself?
We had a few beers that night.
He became, like... aggressive.
You know how he can be.
So then, well lubricated...
Aggressive?
What were you talking about?
We were riding each other,
that's all.
Not me, mostly Marco.
Marco and Sam fought?
We all got carried away.
Sam went for a walk to calm down.
Next morning he wasn't back.
Look. You stay here.
I'll return to the camp and look
with Marco. We'll find him, OK?
- Don't panic.
- Don't panic?
My brother's been gone 24 hours
and I shouldn't panic?
It's not like he's never
been in the woods.
No cause for alarm.
We'll find him.
Trust me.
Sam and I own a sawmill.
A lumberyard.
Nothing big,
but enough to feed two families.
I got married first, to Simone,
Sam's sister.
Marc and Sam were my best men.
Jeff's the godfather
of my youngest, Jeremy.
Every year we go on a fishing trip.
Like when we were kids.
We'd been drinking. You know
how it is, with old friends...
Nothing happened.
Just a little quarrel.
Can I be more specific?
Just guys being guys.
I have no idea why he left.
I figured he wanted to sober up.
Sam can be touchy.
He got upset, and then...
Tempers flared and finally,
he stormed out.
OK, everybody.
Gather round, please.
We're going to start.
First of all, thanks for the big
turnout, we really appreciate it.
This is Detective Thibault,
who'll say a few words.
Detective...
We'll form groups of four or five.
Mr Patenaude is a woodsman, so
from experience, I'd say he's hurt.
Team leaders, don't forget
your first aid kits.
Check Jodoin's trailer.
I'm sure he's there.
The guys looked. He's not there.
As kids it was our hangout.
You know.
Tell them!
- Go on, Detective.
- We'll focus on
where he was last seen,
west of the mountain.
Is that right, guys?
Calm down. You look suspicious.
Weren't we stalling for time?
Look, the girls overreacted.
We just have to play along.
They'll realize we weren't here.
Relax.
They won't investigate.
- If they call customs?
- Why would they? He's in the woods.
Everything OK?
Yeah, sure.
Sorry, I need you
to each lead a team.
It's all good.
Come on,
I'll take you to your group.
Did you check the stream?
Yeah, I think so.
- You think so?
- I dunno, Bea.
- It was dark.
- Even so...
You would've heard the stream.
Maybe, but...
What did you fight about?
Sam started to rag us. We were soused,
having fun, and suddenly,
- he didn't feel so hot.
- I bet. Gimme a break.
What happened?
Look me in the eyes.
I know you. You're hiding something.
Look, Bea...
We behaved like jerks.
You fought about the loan, right?
I knew it.
That's right. It was about my debt.
With the renovations,
I'm behind. Sam's mad.
I'll be glad when that's over with.
Me too. It'll be behind us soon.
I promise.
Let's get back to the others.
Ask for Martine at the bank.
I'll call you next week.
Right.
Thank you, Mr Paquette.
He called me.
When?
While you were fishing.
What did he say?
Did you tell him about us?
Of course not.
No way!
I haven't told anyone.
Shit, why did we do it?
I'm pregnant, Jeff.
I know.
He told you?
I'm sure that's why he took off.
How many weeks?
Sam's the father.
I'm sure it's his.
Isn't it strange that...
Jeff, please.
Hi, Noémie.
Sorry, we're late.
- Everything OK?
- Sure.
Cathy said she was cold upstairs.
We have to insulate.
- Winter's coming.
- I know, I'm on it.
- Do you have any cash?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
- Bye.
1, 2, 3... Here.
Where's this from?
This?
It's nothing.
- Thanks.
- Bye.
Say hi to your parents.
Come, I'll put you to bed.
My baby.
I'm off.
You're going back now?
We start early tomorrow.
What's wrong?
I don't want to become like them.
- Like who?
- Jeff and Simone...
Sam who's always sniping
at Madeleine.
We're not like them, Bea.
- I have to go.
- I know but, I need a cuddle.
You!
Well...
Here.
I stopped taking them.
- Why?
- I need a clear head.
Come on.
We have to tell Julie
her uncle's missing.
Let's not upset her.
- She has her mid-terms.
- Don't worry, I'll do it.
No reason to involve everyone.
We'll find him soon.
Why'd you let him leave?
What were you thinking?
We said you're lost in the woods.
Nake sure you let your beard grow.
Hello?
Nadeleine?
Sam, it's me.
Why are you there?
We're all at the cottage.
We said you got lost.
The cops are here. It's no joke.
The whole village is worried sick.
Let's not make things worse.
Where's Nadeleine?
She's sleeping.
On the sofa.
Wake her up. I want to talk to her.
You'll talk to her when you're back, OK?
- It'll all work out.
- No, it won't.
The baby's not mine.
Hi.
I was just saying.
He stopped gambling.
He's paying off his loan.
What's up?
I was explaining your fight
with Sam.
Why didn't you tell me?
Well, 'cause... there's nothing to say.
I pay off my loan monthly.
Jeff endorsed the loan at the bank.
Mind if we check?
No problem. Right, Jeff?
Perfect.
OK, everybody!
You're fewer today.
So you have to be
even more vigilant.
Why not just say
I smashed his skull?
I said the first thing
that occurred to me.
Fuck! Don't go putting ideas
into their head!
I want my life the way it was.
That's not going to happen.
What do you mean?
Look at us, Marco.
What are we doing?
We're sticking to the plan.
We should tell them.
Shit, tell them what?
The truth.
The truth?
What truth, Jeff?
"Sorry, girls,
but we were lying to you.
We went to Amsterdam to screw around
and get high. Sam's still there."
I'd love to see Simone's face
when she hears.
Your truth means...
I'd see my kids every second weekend.
I don't want to lose Béatrice.
I'm lucky she's still here
after all I've done.
I know.
We have to play the game.
We've no choice.
We'll stop here.
We're beyond the perimeter.
Simone, come back!
- Have you gone crazy?
- Don't call me crazy!
Am I the only one
who wants to find him?
How can we break his ankle?
Take it easy.
We're not gonna break it,
just sprain it.
Is it dirty enough?
Will they buy that he stayed here?
If he's wounded...
We actually pulled it off.
Tomorrow it'll all be over.
Good job, dude. Come on.
Noémie's going to sleep over tonight.
- And tomorrow?
- My mom will fill in, OK?
I was just asking. Jeez!
What's going on, Marco?
Nothing.
The card was declined at the store.
Darnit, I forgot to pay this month.
How you doing?
He knows the area
like the back of his hand.
He's either hurt,
or gone.
With the weather getting colder...
I meant, with the baby.
You started gambling again.
We'll get through this together.
We've seen worse. Right, baby?
We have a great family.
Nothing and no one
is going to destroy it, OK?
I'm not an idiot.
I know it's mine.
Look...
We did something stupid, one night.
But now...
I was stupid not to invite you
to the prom before him.
What do you mean?
Goddamn shitty day!
What? Did I piss in your punch?
I'm going to bed. G'night.
Good night.
What did I do?
Nothing.
Forget it.
He's out there somewhere.
We'll find him, Simone.
When he's upset,
he goes off and pouts.
He always comes back.
You know that.
Close the window, it's cold.
Come to bed.
I'm beat.
Yeah, right.
Help!
Simone's not with you?
She can't go
looking in the trailer!
Leave her to me. Stick to the plan.
You pick him up.
I'll say you had work.
- Did you see Simone?
- She's not inside?
Jeff!
Did we forget anything?
Marco! Jeff! Come on! It's Simone!
Shit.
We stick to the plan.
Girls!
What's going on?
Down there!
Uh, no. Nr Nasson?
Yes.
This is Nadine Cousineau
from Citibank Visa.
Did you leave the country recently?
No, why?
Your company credit card
may have been used fraudulently.
Fucking hell!
Nr Nasson?
- What happened?
- Someone in Amsterdam withdrew $1000.
Nr Nasson?
Mommy, I'm bored.
Daddy will be here soon.
What's keeping him so long?
Mr Décarie?
How is she?
She's out of danger.
She suffered a hip fracture
and a slight concussion.
Can we see her?
Not just yet. She needs to rest.
- What's going on?
- Where were you?
- We almost lost her.
- You're not serious?
She has a concussion and a broken hip.
What if we hadn't found her?
She's in good hands here.
How did she fall?
Will he be OK?
Jeff, listen.
I waited two hours.
He wasn't there.
You get it? He just withdrew $1000!
Simone nearly died.
Because of us.
Marco...
What?
I have to tell you something.
But promise to keep it to yourself.
Yeah, sure.
I got Madeleine pregnant.
You're kidding me.
When? When did you do it?
The week you were both
logging up north.
How could you do it, shit?
We just did.
Bravo, you fuck!
All this bullshit is your fault!
I told you
because you're my friend.
I couldn't keep it in anymore.
No, it's so I'll take your side.
Why didn't you tell me before?
You ruined our lives
for a roll in the hay!
I love her.
Jesus fucking Christ...
We are starting our approach to Nontreal.
The ground temperature is -16° C.
Thank you for flying with us.
Happy holidays to you all.
Madeleine?
Stop running.
I never thought
it could happen to me.
Like, the dumb cliché:
"The love of my life."
Well, bang! It hit me too.
I'm so happy for you.
Name's Philippe.
Julie, you're 17.
- So what?
- If it's true,
you've got at least
50 years with him.
- Mom...
- 50 years is a long time.
As I was saying, I met him in class in...
Another.
I know we open our presents tomorrow,
but I have a little surprise for us.
Merry Christmas, mi amor.
You'll have to shop for a swimsuit.
- We'll roast our pina coladas.
- Marco, I'm so happy!
Thank you, my love!
BUSINESS FOR SALE: SOLD
No, don't.
I'll have a white wine.
Don't touch or talk to her.
Understand?
- Relax.
- Your wife is in there!
And your daughter! Everyone!
- Stay away from her!
- I just wanted to dance.
We got lucky with the cops.
Don't screw things up!
You got a problem, bud?
What's going on?
- Nothing. We're fine.
- It's cool.
I'm glad you two are talking.
It's Christmas, after all.
Right.
Come inside.
We're going to toast Sam.
I'll just finish this.
Wake up!
I won't let you ruin my life.
You bet, old man.
Thanks for the lift.
Our pleasure.
Next year, you'll dance too,
Simone.
Yeah, sure.
Bye, Auntie. See you tomorrow?
Yup...
See you tomorrow.
Hello?
Anybody there?
Who's there?
I thought you were dead.
With my best friend.
I'm pregnant and you abandoned me.
What did you expect?
I'd pretend nothing happened?
Do you know
how many nights
I spent waiting for you?
It's not mine, fuck!
Sam...
When did it happen?
When did you betray me?
While... you stopped
looking at me, Sam.
So everything we said was bullshit?
- The adoption, tests, doctors...
- Where were you?
Where were you?
Where?
Amsterdam.
Come on, kiddos!
I need help cutting the tree!
Mom, you need to rest.
I won't stay in bed all my life.
The doctor said to take it easy.
Julie, get off my back.
Be reasonable. Lie down.
I'll bring your coffee.
Let her help you.
- I don't need help.
- Mom...
Especially not your dad
and his pity!
I'm sorry.
All this...
It's my fault.
The perfect father!
You disgust me.
Where are you going?
To buy cigarettes.
Think I'm stupid?
- Tell the truth for once!
- Stop.
Go on, tell your daughter!
- Want me to tell the truth?
- Yes.
Every morning since Julie moved out,
I wonder why I stay.
Yeah, right.
Next you'll beg my forgiveness.
We'll find an even bigger one
than last year.
Chanel's dad got an artificial one.
It's cold.
I want to play on the computer!
Quit griping. It's Christmas,
you need fresh air.
Go on, get in.
You too, sweetie.
Buckle up your brother.
OK.
What's wrong?
Dad's going to cut the tree
with Uncle Jeff.
- How come?
- He said it won't take long.
What now?
To: Marc & Jeff
From: Santa
Like a beer, guys?
Sit down.
Make yourselves comfortable.
Have you been back long?
30 years we're friends.
You realize?
Look, Sam, it hasn't been easy
for us here either.
You really screwed us.
Amsterdam only worked
if we stuck together.
30 years.
You were gone two months.
We did what we could.
Sure.
Your renovations, great.
I did nothing wrong.
How else could I support my family?
You were blowing company money
in Amsterdam.
I had to sell.
That's alright, Marco.
I understand.
I'm sorry, buddy.
That's alright.
Yeah.
It hurt to see the mill closed.
It was our dream, remember?
So much happens in two months.
But there's one thing...
I couldn't stop thinking about.
Look, Sam...
Who got my wife pregnant?
Where's Madeleine?
What do you want me to do?
Say I'm sorry?
Yeah, apologize.
All this crap is your fault.
You know, if I did it,
it's 'cause...
'Cause why?
Just say you're sorry.
Now's the time.
I wanted to take her to the prom.
She's my wife, Jeff.
You slept with my wife.
The baby's mine.
I know.
I can't have kids.
But you know how much
I wanted to be a dad.
I'm sorry.
Where's Madeleine?
She's gone.
Gone where?
The truth was too much for her.
- What did you tell her?
- Everything.
Amsterdam, the drugs, the girls.
Everything.
Christ, she'll tell everyone.
No, I don't think so.
She just left.
She was furious.
What were you hoping?
She'd leave with you?
There's only one solution.
We get in the car and go.
What? Go where?
Christmas dinner.
And we tell them.
Like men.
The return of the Messiah on Christmas?
No one will buy it.
Why not?
What's the plan?
We buy back the mill?
You two share custody of the kid
with Madeleine?
Gimme a break!
There's another solution.
A lot simpler, too.
- Don't be an idiot!
- Eeny meeny miny moe...
Calm down. Calm down.
Calm down!
Me.
It's OK, Marco.
For once I lose.
- Better for everyone.
- What?
- I'm going.
- Wait.
I'll jump in the lake.
It'll be over.
- Sam, please...
- Get back.
- Calm down.
- I said, back!
- Let's talk.
- Fuck you!
Stop!
It's been fun, guys.
Sam!
What are you doing?
Don't be stupid!
Fuck!
Enough! Enough!
Mommy, when do we open
the presents?
After supper, sweetie.
Still no word from Madeleine?
Make an effort. It's Christmas.
What's wrong, darling?
What's wrong?
Sam's dead.
Of course you're sad he's not here.
I miss him too.
- Are you alright?
- I'll be OK.
- Take a few minutes.
- Sure.
I'm coming.
Supper everybody.
Too bad for Madeleine.
Merry Christmas!
Subtitles: Robert Gray, Kinograph
Subtitling: CNST, Montreal