I'LL TAKE HER LIKE A FATHER
- A bunch of idiots, that's what you are!
- What?
You're a bunch of idiots,
blind and deaf!
You're right!
Counselor, I said you're right! I know!
This is like South African gold,
Rhur coal, Texas oil.
- You should thank me.
- And we do, Counselor.
- Thank you!
- You're welcome.
Let the north bust
its balls with factories,
strikes, oil that doesn't exist.
All of Europe must come here
to get drunk on real sun,
genuine wine, clean sea.
Take Mazzacolli's word for it!
150 singles, 100 doubles,
50 apartments, a dock, a marina.
- Sailing, hiking, water skiing…
- A magnificent, grand project.
Pools, tennis and sports courts,
saunas, mini zoos, mini safaris.
Where do I find
the space for all that?
Either make let me maximize this
or we'll take that.
But Counselor Mazzacolli,
how can we?
My lord, this is an agricultural area
and I'm not God Almighty!
This belongs to the Spina-Tommaselli
and who can touch it?
Dear Di Corato, I'll touch it.
I'll pay in cash.
And I will also buy them!
Yes, the Spina-Tommaselli are like
a bone that sticks in your throat!
Spina! Spina! It's like all
the province belongs to them.
- Not all but half of it.
- Can I drive, Counselor?
- Alright.
- Thank you.
Be careful, eh?
RIVA TOPAZIA S.p.A
DIRECTOR GENERAL
You'll never touch
this steering wheel again.
- It's not a bumper car.
- Here, Counselor!
This way, Sir.
I get it: You're quick, hold your own,
ambitious and rotten to the core.
If you listen and study,
I'll make something of you.
- In 10 years, you'll be rich.
- 10 years?
See that? You're in too
much of a rush, Surveyor.
You want it all right now. Study!
- Hi, Concetta!
- Counselor!
They wanted you from Rome.
From the Bregonzo Office.
They said it's very urgent
and you must call back soon.
- Don Amilcare wanted you too.
- Well done, Concettina.
He said it's urgent too.
And if you don't mind,
this is urgent too.
What's got into your head?
Dear Guercioli, how are you?
I'd like Bregonzo. He's not in?
Then the list of the new ministry?
Still not final? Christ!
Tell me… Go on and tell me!
Damn, I don't give
a shit about Healthcare!
What can I do with Bregonzo
at the Ministry of Health?
No, Guerc… Guercioli, please,
call back in an hour, eh?
Yeah, Healthcare…
The Ministry of Health is
poorer than Fund for the South.
Even if diseases are a good game.
I could turn it into a hospital complex:
Luxury clinics, check-ups,
total transplants, hormones,
spas, rejuvenation, in short,
a brothel for old billionaires.
- It's an idea.
- No, it's a fraud.
Shut up and study!
Blessed art thou among women and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners, now
and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women and
blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners, now
and at the hour of our death.
Heal us, Lord.
Let all the saints heal us:
Orontius, Justus, Fortunatus…
- Grace! Grace, Jesus!
- Lorè, what manners! Manners.
With the heart, Lorè!
Pray with your heart!
Yes, yes…
Useless fool!
- The novena all together.
- Holy Mother of God.
Pray for us!
- St Orontius, the Martyr.
- Pray for us.
And so your wait is over,
dear Saverio.
Soon you'll meet
Donna Raimonda Spina.
But if you want my advice,
just get to know her.
Don't talk about business, please,
unless she starts the conversation.
You need tact, Saverio. Tact!
- And if she doesn't talk about it?
- Don't make any false moves.
Once I've introduced you,
everything will be easier.
Concetta, when you've done having
your ass fondled by the counselor,
I'd like some more fish.
And from Rome?
What news do we have?
It's hard.
They've made and unmade
the government list a dozen times,
as if they were turning
their balls upside down…
- Ah, well…
- Sorry, Concetti'.
- The product's changed.
- It has.
What do you do if Bregonzo
isn't confirmed in the South?
- I'll cut off "my ministers".
- And spite me?
Who has, respectfully speaking,
married you:
You and Emerald Shores.
It was a love marriage,
Don Amilcare,
because respectfully speaking,
what did you get me? Debts, mortgages…
And the Loyola name, dear Saverio.
That's not yet mortgaged.
Come, Clo, come on.
We must get dressed.
Flower, my flower,
beautiful flower!
Anna!
Haven't you got her ready yet?
Hurry, Anna, people are arriving.
Yes, right away.
Come here.
Come, get up.
Come now. Come.
Just like that.
That's Don Liguori, the canon
and that's the family doctor.
- Countess Spina's notary.
- Does he have a price?
The prefect with the mayor.
The one who so gallantly
sees to the lady's necklace
is the director of
the Salentine Credit,
the president of which,
as you know, is Donna Raimonda.
Of course, the bank is hers.
- You already know the assessor
Di Corato. - He's mine.
- Senator Palmieri.
- He will be.
The one in the wheelchair is
Anastasia, a Russian princess,
mother of the late
Count Emilio Spina,
that blonde gentleman
you see portrayed there.
They used to cross the street
in order to pay me homage
but that's now ancient history.
Leave it to me, Don Amilcare and
they'll change palaces once again.
- She's coming. - Don't move,
she'll come over to greet me.
That is still owed to me at least.
- Don Amilcare!
- Dearest Raimonda!
It took our patron saint
to perform this miracle.
- If I may, Counselor Mazzacolli.
- Enchanté.
Yes, Mazzacolli. Emerald Shores,
that's what it's called, right?
I've only heard talk
of your project.
If the countess would like the honor,
I'd be delighted to explain it.
- It's a futuristic conception…
- With the greatest pleasure.
Comment vas-tu, you old whore?
I'm back in business!
- Maman, may I introduce you
to the Counselor Mazzacolli? - Oui.
- Enchanté.
- Come, Don Amilcare,
Elisa and Lorè will be glad to see you.
They're in the living room.
This way, Counselor.
- Who is that man?
- Counselor Mazzacolli.
Hmm. A man!
Oh, dear Amilcare!
Last night you made Emiliuccio
stay up late with those darn cards!
What are you saying, Lorè?
Emilio has been dead for 10 years!
Dead?
How did it happen?
Jesus, they never tell me anything!
What are you saying, Lorè?
How embarrassing!
And this is my daughter Clotilde.
It's been a while
since you've seen her.
How she has grown!
She has become a young lady.
16 years old in May.
Tonight she makes
her official debut into society.
- Right, Clo? Greet the duke.
- Raimonda!
What a splendid daughter
you have, Donna Raimonda.
Do you study, Little Countess?
What grade are you in?
These things happen often.
- Countess, about that request…
- Not now.
I wanted to give an answer,
I see him tomorrow.
Yes, but we've
already talked about it.
But I'm not
convinced by that clause.
Alright,
we'll talk about it tomorrow.
Anna!
Come, Clo, don't do that.
Come with your nanny, come.
You know, she's still a child.
What a pleasure it was
to meet you, Counselor.
Why don't you come with me tomorrow?
I'll give you a tour of my properties.
Excuse me.
We can calmly talk about your project.
I'd really like to know more.
Yes, sure. Why not?
Tomorrow morning.
Certainly.
Yes, it smells like spring.
Yes, forward. That's it.
Jesus! Jesus! Jesus!
Who would've thought
that poor Clotilde
was making her debut in society?
And the aunts? The grandmother?
Are they for real?
It's obvious Donna Raimonda
is thinking of marrying her.
A fool? Who would take her?
Ah, dear Saverio, husbands are
bought like any other goods!
- It's a matter of price.
- Yes, but a sick, demented girl…
But upon that poor
demented little head
there are houses, land, titles…
and 20 kilometers of coastline.
- 20?
- 20.
15 minutes by car
from stake to stake.
I know it well: it was all mine
before that cursed evening!
Two pairs of aces and kings
which was, believe me, a jewel.
And didn't that evil Count Spina have
a miserable trio of sevens in his hand?
- Did he have it?
- He certainly did!
May the devil take him to hell!
He was a born bluffer but shit,
that night he had the points!
And he screwed me from a property
that's worth billions today.
You play away billions
like that over a pair of aces?
- Excuse me, couldn't you back out?
- Counselor,
do you see that tree?
There is more than
6 centuries of history there.
The Loyolas ruled at
the time of Ferrante of Aragon,
better than the Spinas,
lesser nobles of the Bourbon restoration.
I am the last without heirs.
The one on the top right.
- But a Loyola's word is as good as…
- As good as a king's.
Why don't you adopt me?
I gain a title and you a lineage.
I mean it. Why not think about it?
Dear Mazzacolli,
my name will serve
you better if I wear it myself.
I don't know.
Do me the favor
and not to say "enchanté"
- when I introduce you to a lady.
- Isn't that done?
If the lady is French or you are.
Are you French?
I am from the European
Economic Community.
Bonne nuit.
Behave!
- Well done, Peppe!
- Remember we're not on your side.
Greeks, Arabs, Spaniards have been
spilling our blood for centuries.
- You have the plan?
- Yes, Sir.
When we say "yes or no", it might
mean yes or no but not necessarily.
- The heliport project?
- All there, Sir. - Good.
But when we're silent, you must start
shitting yourself because it's a bad sign.
- Understand?
- Sure!
Business doesn't require calculation
but intuition, imagination, poetry!
Poetry?
Meanwhile, you stink like a whore!
- Monsieur de Givenchy.
- Penhaligon.
There's only one cologne: Penhaligon.
Few know about it even in London.
Here, a present for you.
Can this cologne be ordered?
Never mind that,
think of the countess.
She's a son of a bitch.
Don't underestimate her.
I'll take that. I need it.
And this son of a bitch, who does…
sorry, Concetti, who does she screw?
As the criminal records
would say: "No charges".
Some trips now and then:
Paris, New York, Barletta.
Shit! Nail yourself to the table
and wait for Guercioli's call.
I'll call as soon as
I hear any news.
I'm off to fix the South.
I forgot to warn you it's going to
be quite a country day, Counselor.
Oh, please!
Sorry, rather,
if I kept you waiting.
A long-distance…
an international call…
I just came down.
More than 80,000
attendees a year,
for starters.
A business of several billions.
Don't overlook the possibility of
an outlet for your production, Countess.
- I won't overlook it.
- Here: wine, cigarettes…
In other words, the common market.
Oil! You also produce oil, right?
A little: 10,000 quintals.
Lovely plants. Ancestral.
The entire cost of the project
doesn't exceed 30 billion.
This includes buying the needed land,
for which I have the contracts.
- A transfer of ownership?
- No.
- You see, as an option. It's as if…
- Ah, "as if".
This vineyard is splendid!
Is all this yours?
And how much…?
260 hectares, 600,000 bottles.
Here's to the frothing wine,
sparkling in the glass,
like the lover's smile…
that makes every
thought a happy one!
Here's to the wine that's sincere,
that makes every
thought a happy one!
It's nice.
It's my refuge in the hot hours.
Make yourself at home, Counselor.
I always come here after I've made
my rounds. I grab a bite to eat
and when I feel like it,
take a catnap.
At home, I have no peace.
Excuse me, I'll take
a shower and be right back.
By all means. Countess,
while you shower, may I use the phone?
My house is your house, Counselor.
Peppe, it's me.
So, did he call?
And?
Holy fuck…
Fuck…
Counselor?
Were you bored?
I was thinking about you.
- Want some help?
- Yes.
You are so beautiful.
How nice you smell.
You smell of soap,
lily of the valley.
Flowers.
Why don't you tell me
you want to fuck me?
You liked that, eh?
We shall do great things together.
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Adding your forces to mine,
Emerald Shores is a done deal.
But that's just for starters:
We'll parcel out the Amazon!
Counselor!
Why "counselor"?
Did you say "counselor"?
Come here.
I don't want any misunderstandings.
It was very pleasant but…
- But?
- Just a small interlude.
We'll end it just as we began it.
And we'll forget
about it soon, OK?
You're a fine slut, eh?
I am a fine slut
but don't forget my title.
You, Countess, are a fine slut.
See? Much better. Thank you.
I'm so hungry now!
We can talk business while having
a bite to eat. Right, Counselor?
Very true. I'm very hungry now too.
May I get dressed?
Alright.
You're too hungry, Counselor.
You want my money.
- I don't. I'm giving you a chance
to give it to me. - The same thing.
No, it's different.
Oops! Sorry, ladies first.
Fine.
You offer me the chance to give
you my money in exchange for 30%.
- Exactly. - And I offer
you the chance to take it
and keep the 30% for yourself.
You don't want the percentage?
- Cheers.
I want the other.
- I want 70%.
- Hey, Countess, no.
Sorry. We're still friends
but see ya. I'll go it alone.
- Counselor, you will not
go it alone. - Ah, no?
I know your situation
as well as yourself.
You're in the hole for 423 million.
If you want,
I can tell you the change.
Isn't this cheese good?
You even know the change?
You are as dry…
as a bunch of raisins!
And if you don't find half a billion
within about two or three weeks,
you lose everything
and go back home.
- The Fund for the South (Midday)…
- For you, Counselor, it's midnight.
You were informed just now
that your friend, Mr Berg…
- Bregonzo.
"He hasn't found a seat
in the government ship".
Excuse me, how…?
There's a line in the bedroom.
Well done! How sumptuous,
how splendid, how sublime,
how celestial, how beatific
a son of a bitch you are!
A son of a bitch and a bitch!
Whore! Slut!
A hooker is what you are!
I did warn you.
Hello? This is Emerald Shores!
Yes, one moment.
Counselor, the Senator!
I've been saying this
to you since 3rd grade:
"Bregonzo, you're an asshole"!
It almost rhymes.
Weak blood.
And then the children pay for it.
It's a shame.
It's really a shame.
Yes…
Because…
she would have everything.
Just something missing in the head.
- Here's the coffee, Excellency.
- Well done, Concetta!
- Is she taking a bath?
- Shut up.
- Mind your fucking business.
- Sorry, Concetta.
- Thank you, Duke.
- Go to your kennel!
Punctum dolens.
The weak point.
Everyone has one:
you, me, Donna Raimonda…
But that's normal, Christ!
This Raimonda can't have it all!
The bank, olive trees, oil,
wine, tobacco! What the fuck?
Clotilde.
Clotilde?
Why, Clotilde? Lie down.
Like that.
Sleep. Sleep, honey.
Be good, good, my baby.
Why are you crying?
Beautiful flower,
go to sleep in the castle.
In the castle there's a gentleman
who wants to eat the flower.
Go beddy-bye in the castle.
In the castle there's a gentleman
who wants to eat the flower.
News has arrived from Palazzo Chigi
that the ministry assignments
could be determined by tomorrow.
The Finance Minister…
- Hello?
- Counselor Mazzacolli?
- In person. Who is it?
- Here's Dr Guercioli.
- Dear counselor, unfortunately,
I must inform you… - One moment.
- Stop.
- What? Are you busy?
- No, go on! Heel.
- What did you say?
Ah, you're talking to your dog.
- Who? No, go on.
- I'm still inside arguing.
According to the latest rumors
gathered by those in the know,
Bregonzo goes to Transportation.
At least, it seems so.
A funeral! Stay here.
Well, first of all
it's not a sure thing
and then it's not a ministry
to be sneezed at.
Give me the other one, it's firm.
A hard boiled egg.
- Hard? What do you mean?
- No, I mean the hard facts!
Nothing else can be done.
Cheer up, eh?
Yes, on a dick!
Where are you going?
- To sleep!
- No, wait, come here. Sit down.
You are a smart girl.
You must study, got it?
Study languages: English, French,
Arabic. They are useful today.
Study! You can do public
relations for Emerald Shores.
Study! Study and
you won't regret it! Study.
Transportation…
Healthcare…
The Countess.
The Countess…
Go to the post office and send
everything by express mail.
Then come and pick me up.
I'll accept, I'll sign
but I'd like to talk for a moment…
It's something particular
but the notary…
Notary, would you please
leave us for a moment?
Of course, Countess.
Go on.
I want to marry
your daughter Clotilde.
You want to marry Clotilde?
I want to marry Clo.
I realize that it's…
Counselor, I'm not disposed
to joke about that subject.
I'm not joking at all, Countess.
I want to marry your daughter.
Because it can be a guarantee
that's still missing from our pact.
This way, I won't just be a partner
but join the Spina Family, become…
But for that you don't need
to marry Clo, Counselor.
Then why not you?
There's already some sympathy
between us. You're a Spina…
I am a Spina as long as
I remain Count Spina's widow.
If I remarry, Counselor,
I am nothing.
Nothing at all.
Is the offer…
still valid?
No… Never mind, Countess.
Never mind!
Then I'll call
the notary so we can sign?
No, Countess, I won't sign until
you sign the marriage contract.
That is what's called
a fiduciary relationship!
Of course! It's the minimum.
Yes, the little snail. Yes.
If you knew, dear Raimonda,
what joy this gives me.
It's as if I were becoming
your relative too.
As if something of myself
was entering this union.
He's alluding to his mortgages!
Oh, well…
You'll do me the honor, dear Saverio.
Saturday my farmers are having a party.
- A yearly ancient festival.
- Sure, why not? Sure.
- You too, I hope.
- Thank you, my friend,
but you know I'd never go to it.
They burn the devil! But I bet
the lawyer doesn't believe in that.
Why not? Even the Pope has recently
relaunched it, in grand style.
In France, they say, "One candle
to God and two to the devil."
The French are great diplomats.
You never know!
What a beautiful bride you have,
Amilcare and at your age…
What, Lorè? He's not the groom!
It's Counselor Mazzacolli!
- Which one?
- Shh! Shut up!
Madame Countess, I am ready.
- Anna?
- Yes, immediately.
Come, Clotilde.
Come with me. Easy… easy…
Easy…
Step down… Very good, like that.
The San Gaudio estate,
96 hectares, as written in the registry,
the Suprammonte olive grove property,
36 hectares, as written in the registry,
the 25% share of
the Apulian wine cellars property,
the property of the plot of land
used for grazing and husbandry
for a total area of
1664 hectares denominated
the Duke's Springs.
- Counselor Mazzacolli?
- Yes?
- The size of this park…
- It's around 10,000 heads.
- Yes.
If you like,
I'll read you the details.
For heaven's sake,
we have all the time in the world.
Let's read the binding clause then.
The what, notary?
Countess Clotilde's
entire estate rests on,
by the express testamentary will
of the late Count Emilio…
- Rests on what?
- The restriction of usufruct
for Countess Raimonda
Spina-Tommaselli,
appointed as trustee and
sole administrator of the assets.
Rests on her?
This is true even if
Clotilde gets married?
That possibility, in truth, wasn't
foreseen by the late count.
The matter is in the hands
of Donna Raimonda.
You won't care about
such a detail, dear Saverio.
If I understood correctly, what matters
to you is joining the family, right?
And a dowry is not needed.
Just Clotilde.
A dowry? The thought never
passed my mind, dear Raimonda.
Where do I sign?
Next to the crosses.
56 signatures, Counselor.
Knowing that, I brought my stamp.
I have to pay!
It's the second time!
It's the second time she fucked me!
I have to pay! For everything!
- The countess…
- Save'!
What countess?
I told you, she was born badly.
She doesn't have any true nobility!
She has no elegance.
She doesn't give a fuck
about the noble and the elegant!
And she's right!
If the first Loyola had paid
attention to elegance and nobility,
instead of killing and robbing,
you would not be a duke!
- Saverio, don't break my family tree.
- Yes, dream of your tree!
Instead, by God,
I want to plant my tree here!
I don't know what tree you refer to,
but if it's what I think it is,
you've already planted it
but without any substantial results.
I admit that.
For the moment.
And after all,
you're marrying a beautiful girl!
Maybe she has no mind
but did you see those thighs?
What do you mean?
Did you see her?
She's lifeless. A thing.
Can one make love to a thing?
I do this crap because I must save
an exceptional venture, a great idea.
But I won't touch
that girl even with a finger!
I'll be a father to her.
That's right.
I'll be just like a dad.
A dad? In the sense that you'd
like to be the mother's husband.
Stop!
Here, a little present.
What's the matter?
- There, it's no longer a little gift!
- Yes, Sir.
- But when I'm done, not a word, eh?
- I don't even want to hear you.
- You won't.
"Yes, Sir. No, Sir…" Turn around.
What are you doing?
Excuse me, Concettina,
but that's my fucking business.
And mine too, if you don't mind.
Counselor, please…
Don't think about anything.
I'll show you!
You don't know me.
You'll know who I am!
No! No! I know! I know! Oh, Jesus!
- You're Counselor Mazzacolli!
- You shut up!
Damn slut that you are!
Why say those nasty things to me?
- What did I do to you?
- I don't mean you.
I'm talking about another,
that titled whore.
Wait, wait…
You'll see if I don't bend you!
I'll break you! I'll smash you!
I'll smash you! I'll…
I got it!
- I've done it!
- You're wrong, Counselor, not yet!
You shut up! I got it!
I got it, Duke!
Duke, an idea!
But… Counselor?
Duke! Duke!
Duke!
Duke, I got it because…
Duke! Duke, I got it!
What's the matter?
Counselor, you almost
gave me a heart attack.
- I've screwed the countess.
- Again?
No, I'll take everything:
the dowry and the daughter.
Don Amilcare, I'll take it all!
All! All! All! I'll take it all!
- How?
First…
Hey!
Can you hear me?
First:
I'll kidnap the girl.
Kidnap her?
You'll compromise her!
Sure, so I'll go to jail, I'll have to
marry her and it begins again:
courts, fees and all that bullshit!
Don Amilcare, someone, unknown,
- someone who must remain unknown…
- Not me!
Of course. An unknown
must kidnap, as you've said,
Clotilde Spina. Period.
Second:
The girl is found:
prayers, tears, candles
and the bad ordeal has left her,
how shall we say, stained…
- Compromised.
- Compromised!
Understand? Compromised.
Third: as the betrothed,
I am offended in my dignity,
- in my honor.
- Right!
At that point, I might back off,
"I don't buy second-hand stuff!"
But instead… Fourth:
I am generous.
I'll marry the girl anyway.
But…
You're fantastic!
What a brain you have!
You reason like us!
Drink.
And you have the subtlety to take
her all the same, even damaged!
And they can't deny you
either the girl or the dowry.
Well, "damaged", so to speak.
It doesn't need to go that far.
No, it's necessary, it is.
And the medical examination?
- What medical examination?
- We always do a medical exam.
We're no fools here!
She must be damaged goods.
If not, it won't work.
Have someone do it.
Christ, not a cuckold!
Save', it's either
cuckold or nothing!
After all, what is a horn?
A horn jewel,
payable to the bearer!
A fine pile of billions!
Or do the service yourself.
Out of the question.
I am a gentleman.
Damaged!
This is the Duke of Loyola's property,
the perfect place.
A place above all suspicion.
Hidden by the trees, out of the way…
Then look inside. Come!
Seems the Loyola family's
misfortunes began here.
- It was a famous fire.
- Bravo.
A beautiful ceiling, classic.
And if this works out…
I'll let you restore it all. Come.
The bedroom survived.
- Ah, a wedding favor!
- A bed for three, eh?
Hey! The van?
Bravo.
- And what's in there?
- The toilet. Go on.
Who knows how many beautiful
aristocratic asses have washed in here!
Mazzacolli,
I want my share right away.
I'm risking a lot.
Millions.
On the very evening
you bring her here.
But let's not screw up, Peppe.
The Spina House.
The side door.
The stairs.
So we agree, dear Don Liguori?
A private ceremony.
Maybe late afternoon.
Even late at night, dear Saverio.
Discretion is the golden rule
of Holy Mother Church.
Excellent.
Our notary has quite the appetite?
Yes but only at the table,
dear Saverio. Only at the table!
He's coming! He's coming!
Blessed Archangel Michael,
come and do justice!
Blind him! Blind the devil!
The ugly beast!
My flower…
What is it? You can't sleep?
You understand that
no one's there, right?
But don't be afraid.
Your nanny's here who loves you.
You want a drink?
Then you'll make a lake in your bed!
Alright then.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't. It doesn't.
Go pee pee, dear. Pee pee!
Beautiful flower.
Good!
How beautiful!
They're burning him!
But the devil doesn't give a shit.
Go to sleep.
"The gentleman wants
to eat the flower".
Come, go to sleep…
Sleep, beautiful flower, come now.
- Look! Look at that!
- Wonderful!
It's over the top but satisfying.
Extraordinary!
- Is there anything wrong?
- A call from home.
Barbarians!
Barbarians! Uncivilized!
Cowards! Scoundrels!
They would stop at nothing!
And what the heck,
she's a poor sick baby!
What does she have?
- Shut up!
- And nobody heard a thing?
- Go on, speak!
- I…
At 9:00 Gaetano locked the door,
then came back to watch TV.
We didn't hear anything.
The others didn't either,
until Anna called me.
- Was any door forced open?
- No, Ma'am.
- Stop crying, you old crone!
- Yes…
But if this monster, this assassin,
falls into my hands, I will…
I'll break him! I'll break him in two!
I'll strangle, destroy him!
Come, Lorè, come. Let's pray.
- Come.
- Poor Clo…
- Please, be calm, I beg you.
- Calm?
Calm? But how can you be calm?
- I marvel, you're the mother!
- That's right, I am! Got it?
But don't you realize
they kidnapped her? Kidnapped!
- She's in danger… - And why do
you think they kidnapped her?
Because she's worth money.
And what's worth money is valuable.
That's why I'm calm.
I'm scared but…
I'm calm.
You have no choice but to pay.
In this shitty region,
kidnapping has become big business!
I can't take it anymore.
- What are you doing?
- Calling the police.
You're not calling anybody!
- I don't agree.
- You still haven't got it, Saverio.
Nothing has happened here. Got it?
Clotilde's in there, in her room!
Everybody got that?
- She's just sick with measles.
You got that, Anna? - Yes.
And she must remain isolated!
- Everybody got that? Do you two?
- Yes, yes!
You too, Saverio.
Remember that you're about to marry.
You're a happy man.
So then smile. Smile!
Everybody smile! Smile!
Hurray! Long live the newlyweds!
What are you doing here?
Did Peppe phone?
- She's here.
- Peppe?
- She. She's in the cellar.
- Clotilde!
- Why didn't you take her to the cottage?
- It was impossible.
You crazy?
We'll all get in trouble!
I'm not crazy! I was about
to be taken by the carabinieri.
So I came back and
chose to go somewhere safer.
And I'm the only one taking risks!
And now you…
do your job and let me do mine.
Now, if you take Concetta with you,
I'll do it and finish my part.
- Get your hands off, Mazzacolli!
- Listen well, Surveyor!
You take it down a notch and
get the fuck out of here! Got it?
You'll do "it" when I say so.
Alright.
- If you want, tomorrow
I'll bring her to the cottage. - OK.
But keep calling me "Sir",
because I can hear you better that way.
What are you doing?
Have we all gone nuts?
- I'm putting her to sleep.
- Is this a sleeping pill?
Anna does this every night
to get her to sleep.
- I saw her do it, I swear!
- Really?
It's called fingering.
Get out and make me a chamomile,
else my head will explode.
- Get out!
- Yes, Sir, right away.
Clotilde…
Yes?
Clotildina…
Clotildina!
Now, Clotildina,
like a good little girl
goes beddy-bye.
Hey, little countess.
No, for heaven's sake!
Here, suck. Good.
Just look what I…
But tomorrow, Daddy will buy you
a nice bottle and you can suck that.
No. No, stop, please.
Clotilde, please stop. Oh, my god.
Are you an idiot?
I mean, sorry…
Shut up! You'll wake up
the whole neighborhood!
What are you doing? No! No!
Pl… please!
Clo, what are you doing?
Clo! No!
Let go of me! What are you…?
Please!
No, Clo… Clo, please!
Just stop it!
Clotilde…
Clo… No, Clotilde…
Listen…
Please, I beg you, Clo… Clotilde…
No… my… no…
I am flesh too.
Clo…
No… I…
You…
you are raping me!
Counselor, damn it, it's cold.
Want me to heat it up?
What do you mean?
The chamomile.
Yes, I need more than chamomile.
You stay down here tonight.
Watch her. Stay with her. Got it?
There.
That's enough.
Just like she was inside it.
Got it?
What do I do now?
- What do I do now?
- Jesus, give me patience!
What do you do every morning?
Open the blinds, idiot! Move it!
Everything must look
normal from the outside.
- And now?
- Sit down, stupid!
Tell her fairy tales.
Do what you've always done!
- Don't make me curse.
- Then the little girl
looked out the window.
- Hey, you must be up to this, got it?
- I can't…
Come on.
How come nobody woke me up?
Oh, Jesus, how I slept.
Lisetta, did you like
the theater last night?
- All that confusion!
- Yes.
And she screamed
at her sister below,
"Little sister! Little sister!
If she doesn't come back
I'll go crazy!
Shut up! Are you all crazy?
I told you to shut up!
They can hear in the street!
Enough! Calm down!
Go to Alfonsa!
You want everyone to hear you?
Get out of there!
No! Do what I tell you!
We've supplies for at least a week.
Then we'll see.
There's a stove over there.
Bring some underwear, shirts…
Well?
What? She's listening to music.
You don't move from here.
When I'm not here, don't leave
her alone for even a second, OK?
Yes, Sir.
And don't spend it right away.
That's how fools get caught.
By whom?
No one's looking for me, right?
For now.
Well?
What more do you want?
To do that…
which I must do.
It's no longer needed.
Are you disappointed?
A bit. It was the only
appetizing side of this.
- Why? Money doesn't amuse you?
- Yes.
Hey…
How was the girl?
Was it worth it?
Remember what you've left to do
and try not to do anything stupid.
At 6:00 sharp!
Alright?
Always at Sir Counselor's orders!
Hail, Queen, mother of mercy…
We resort to you,
the exiled children of Eve.
Moaning and weeping
in this vale of tears.
Don't worry, dear Raimonda.
I also sent Concettina to her village.
I gave her a holiday. You never know.
The girl is quick.
She would've ended up
sniffing out something.
Donna Raimonda,
the clock is correct, right?
Don Amilcare, why should you care
if the clock is fast or slow?
Nothing. I was just asking.
Saverio, please.
I understand that…
I can't take it anymore either.
My nerves are shot.
- Hello?
- Silence. Only I will speak
and just once.
Clotilde is fine.
You'll have her back soon.
We will send the instructions
to Counselor Mazzacolli.
We will deal only with him.
Hello? One moment! Hello?
No, no, Raimonda. I can't!
- It's a responsibility that I don't…
- Saverio, you heard him, right?
- He only wants to deal with you.
- No, please. No!
I'm afraid of messing up…
I know myself. I'd have no control.
With animals like that I'd kill!
Saverio…
You've heard it all, right?
What should we do?
Saverio, they spoke clearly.
They'll only show up for you.
When they show up, I'll tell them
I don't want to be involved.
And that they should go
directly to you, Donna Raimonda.
Try to understand me…
it's for Clo's sake.
Saverio!
Saverio…
Thanks to the Madonna!
Here, eat, my beauty! Eat.
If you don't eat,
you'll starve, you know?
- Eat, stupid!
- What's the matter?
- Is that how you do it?
- She won't eat.
She hasn't touched
anything all day.
- Here, beauty. Eat, it's good!
- Go away.
- Check that the shades are closed.
- I've closed them.
And now…
Papa will give you the good pap.
Open your mouth, go on.
Open…
Very good.
See?
What? Don't you like it?
Let me try it.
She's right!
It's crap! It tastes like nothing!
You forgot to bring salt, Counselor!
Is that my fault?
I'll bring it tomorrow.
Give her something else to eat.
- Is everything else fine?
- Yes.
- Oh, sorry, Counselor.
- Stay still.
I've already changed her
3 times since morning.
She pees more than
a platoon of soldiers.
Shut up.
Eat, you asshole!
The same voice. He said to look in
the trunk of the car and hung up.
The lock was forced
and this was inside.
"Prepare a billion
in small bills now."
They won't go easy on us, eh?
Are you really sure you don't want
to put this in the police's hands?
No! Don't insist, please.
It's not little.
Not even for the Spina
but we'll cough up the billion
Anything to save Clo.
Anything.
She gets messy so quickly.
There we go.
Now we'll put on a clean shirt,
all clean.
Give me a clean shirt.
Any will do. That one.
The underwear?
They're all hanging out to dry.
Concettina, you do it.
I don't have time.
And brush her hair!
Hello, Emerald Springs.
Who's speaking?
- This is Countess Spina.
- Is that you, Countess?
Excuse me. I…
Yes, I'm Surveyor Colizzi.
- You want Mazzacolli?
- Yes, Counselor Mazzacolli, please.
He hasn't returned yet.
One moment!
Sorry, I thought that was him
but I was wrong.
Don't worry.
I'll report that you called.
Three times!
And Bregonzo called from Rome,
Di Corato and the assessor of Bari!
Counselor!
The widdle bath is bye-byes.
Bye-byes!
All nice and clean! Perfumed!
Splash!
Let's dry off!
The shoulders,
the widdle titties,
the tummy,
and the lovely widdle pussy!
Up!
The widdle heiny…
- Please give the suitcase
to the gentleman. - Here.
Countess, if I may.
Thank you, Countess. My respects.
Do you have it?
- If you want.
- Yes.
Daddy!
You repeat it too: pa-pa.
Pa-pa.
Good. And now…
Listen up, eh? Pay attention.
Say…
screw me.
Did you understand?
No, don't get distracted. Say it.
Screw me.
Well done! Well done!
What's going on here?
Am I teaching you
or are you teaching me?
Hey!
That's a slutty look, eh?
Yes, there's nothing else to do.
My love…
Darling…
Daddy's widdle slut.
But I do want to, you know?
I want it too.
Yes, we've already done it,
haven't we?
God, how beautiful you are.
You are so beautiful.
And I envy you, I swear!
You have discovered
the feminine ideal.
A pure object, dear Saverio.
Pepper, please.
All the benefits and no hassles.
She screws and doesn't talk.
She doesn't think and doesn't bitch.
The perfect sex slave!
Oh, no.
It's not like that, Don Amilcare.
It's like I've discovered…
It's as if Clotilde had taught me
a new way of making love.
Without guilt, without sin…
Now we're philosophizing.
No, it's not philosophy, it's life!
I'm in paradise with Clo.
That paradise lost…
- In monthly installments.
- I like it.
I am happy.
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes! I'm happy!
Happy…
Save'!
You frighten me.
Hi.
Daddy's leaving now.
Bye.
Bye bye.
No, hush. Be good, eh? Bye.
Bye.
Either I'm crazy…
or everybody else is.
Here's what you need for tomorrow.
If the county calls again,
what do I say?
To stop bitching.
And if they create difficulties,
authorize Di Corato
to name Countess Spina.
When they know she's in the deal,
they'll shit themselves.
By the way, if Donna Raimonda calls,
tell her that…
that I'm not back yet. Alright?
- Counselor!
- What is it?
Counselor, that billion,
seeing that it's there,
why don't we settle for that
and go and enjoy it in peace?
In peace? And after?
I don't steal, Surveyor Colizzi!
I'm not a chicken thief like you.
I'm a businessman and that's worth
way more than your measly billion.
Do you understand?
Very well.
So what are we waiting for?
Let's give her daughter back
and close this deal.
What are we waiting for,
Counselor Mazzacolli?
We're waiting for me to decide. OK?
And turn that bullshit off,
because I pay the bills!
I pay!
Amen.
And above all,
don't break my balls!
There.
Spanish style, eh?
Fee, fi, fo, fum!
I smell the blood of an Englishman!
There is or there has been,
I can smell it on their skin.
Jump, little horse!
Hey! Hey!
Hey, but…
But are you crazy?
And yes you are crazy.
Look at this stuff.
I'll let it dry.
Well?
You not going to poo, are you?
On the pillows… No, wait!
Concetta, the chamber pot!
Wait. No, no, wait!
Well, in for a penny,
in for a pound.
Clo, now I like everything
about you. Everything!
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
It is a good thing! Human!
Right! Yes, gentle people, alright?
And please, don't break my balls!
Saverio!
Where have you been hiding?
You haven't been in touch
for 2 days or given any news!
- Why?
- Where did you just come from?
- I don't have a shirt on.
- I see.
Saverio,
what does this mean?
What happened?
Nothing.
- Nothing happened.
- No, you must explain.
- Do you trust me or not?
- I don't know.
- Great! Have we come to this?
- We have!
- Then you want to know?
- I do.
You want to know the truth?
Want me to tell you all?
Yes.
I won't tell you.
I won't tell you!
Alright?
Promise me you'll never grow up.
My little, little one.
Don't come to this world.
They don't understand.
I want to come where you are.
I want to be with you.
You and me alone.
They will sign, Counselor,
but they want 20 to
25 million right away!
To plug up the most urgent holes!
Insist.
Counselor, you must give me
at least 10 million now
or I can't keep them at bay!
- Counselor!
- Bye-byes!
Bye-byes!
- Where are you going?
- Hey!
What are you doing here?
- Are you keeping watch?
- You can't enter.
The counselor doesn't
want to be disturbed.
- Who wants to enter?
- Leave me alone!
Look here…
- What do you want?
- To talk with you.
- Don't you believe me?
- No.
I really mean it.
The lawyer's having fun in there…
and you keep watch outside
like a dog.
- My fucking business.
- Not at all.
If you listen to me,
you'd be a lady.
Furs.
- Apartments, cars!
- Yeah, with a beggar like you.
What do you think?
I know tons of people with money.
And vices!
If you were better dressed,
- you'd be a fine…
- Asshole! You think I'd be a whore?
- What's that with the lawyer then?
- I love the counselor.
Love?
For how much?
For 20?
For 30,000 lire?
With all these lovely
things that you have,
you could get 100,
even 150,000 lire a hit.
Leave me.
What do you want to do?
If I have to sell the goods,
I must try it first, right?
A little more red.
There.
Just like that.
Hey!
No! No! No! No!
Clotilde, please. I beg you.
OK! OK! OK!
Easy…
Concetta!
Sir, what happened?
Did you cut yourself?
- What are you doing here?
- The duke sent me.
He says Donna Raimonda
is beside herself.
She says if she doesn't hear anything
by tomorrow, she's going to the police.
- The duke says…
- He says! She says! You wait.
- You whore.
- See?
- Even the lawyer say so.
- Shut up!
- Alright. Concetta…
- He's nervous.
When I'm gone,
clean up a bit, tidy up…
and throw it all in the woods.
- It's your fault.
- Got it?
Tomorrow morning,
Peppe comes here at 8 sharp.
You go to the town
and only come back when your
holidays are over, not a day before.
- OK?
- Yes, Sir. - Come on!
Tomorrow morning,
you stay here with
Clotilde and wait for me.
I'll come later and
we'll take her home.
Counselor, why do I need to come?
Can't you bring her
back by yourself?
Just look…
Look at this imbecile.
I want to make you
look like a hero.
When we bring the daughter back
to Donna Raimonda with the billion,
I'll say you helped me
in finding out where she was.
I'm not from here
and you're a local.
Donna Raimonda will be grateful.
You'll get double the prize money.
Legal money, which you can
use in the light of day.
Tomorrow is your day,
Surveyor Colizzi.
Alright. I'll be here
tomorrow morning at 8.
Good.
- See you tomorrow, Counselor.
- Bye.
All night there, like a fool.
Well, I'm leaving then.
Little countess…
An ingenious scoundrel.
Who would ever think of the cottage?
Did I make you suffer?
But I wanted to be careful.
To catch him in the act.
I also wanted to be sure
he acted on his own.
- And then…
- And then?
And then I made sure
you'd see it with your own eyes.
So there would be no more doubts.
Saverio, forgive me
for the other night but…
No, please.
Won't he be rash if he's trapped?
He'll run away.
He's very intelligent.
And then fleeing and keeping quiet
will suit him as well as us.
What matters is
that Clotilde is safe.
By the way, I've already put
your money back in the bank.
You're an idiot…
but not bad at all.
Not bad…
I can almost sign off on that too.
Besides…
Mazzacolli and I are partners.
Stay where you are! Don't move!
Shut up! Shut up!
That son of a bitch!
Raimonda!
Help, Countess! Help!
Clo! Clotilde!
- Get up.
- Clo!
My flower! Beautiful flower!
What did that bastard do?
Love!
- Get the blanket, Anna!
- Yes.
- She passed out.
- Clotilde!
Clo… Clo… My daughter…
Clo…
Bastard!
- Well, Doctor?
- Later.
Unfortunately, it was done.
Dirty coward, son of a bitch.
- But this is not the end. I'll…
- You must be strong, Counselor.
The good luck is that
the countess, in this misfortune,
in the mental condition
in which she is,
must not have even realized it.
All is saved except for honor.
- You take me to her!
- Right away, Princess.
Excuse me.
I realize that
the situation has changed.
Saverio, if you want to back out,
you may.
No, what does this matter?
Who cares about that?
Sure, this has made me…
It's understandable…
Saverio is upset.
These things, you know…
Maybe it's best that I speak.
Maybe this isn't the best time but…
since you brought it up,
I might as well.
Indeed, as you well said,
the situation has changed.
But Saverio is a gentleman.
Let's give him time to recover,
to digest the blow…
He'll marry Clotilde.
He'll marry her even…
as she is.
- Though at this juncture…
- This juncture?
Well, you're an intelligent woman,
Raimonda dear…
a small tweak to the nuptial
contract would seem right to me.
See, I knew it: You're reasonable.
And it's just a small thing:
You renounce some of the usufruct,
let him manage the properties…
Let's say instead
that I will back out.
Excuse me?
Let's give Saverio time
to digest the blow.
All the time he needs.
My daughter will not marry.
I'll keep her with me as she is.
She's fine to me the way she is.
Donna Raimonda, I…
- I don't understand.
- I understand, Don Amilcare.
Fine, if you understand…
Saverio!
We'll rip up the marriage contract,
but business is business,
Counselor Mazzacolli.
Not as a son-in-law,
but as a partner you may suit me.
- But I wanted…
- Saverio,
let's talk about it tomorrow.
Clo! Drink, Clo.
Come now, be good.
My goodness!
Clo!
Clotilde!
What are you doing there?
Get the doctor! Hurry!
I'm going!
Clo! Clo!
Saverio!
But why don't you go to bed?
It's one o'clock, Save'.
Tomorrow. Take it easy.
I can't keep doping
her with sedatives.
I'm worried about her mental state.
I would call a specialist.
- The tarantula stung her!
They bewitched her! - Hush.
If she doesn't eat for a week,
we can't continue with the drip.
I'm sorry, Countess. Goodbye.
My respects, Princess.
Clo?
Clotilde?
Little one…
Raimonda!
She needs a man, understand?
We must marry her
immediately to that guy.
That will be the real cure.
You are all blind!
Save', here's the coffee
It's ten o'clock.
- At night?
- No, day.
At least come down
for a bite to eat.
- No pap.
- Huh? What did you say?
- No pap!
- Oh, no!
That won't do! No!
Bregonzo phoned. I spoke to him.
Everything can be saved.
Really?
- Tomorrow.
- What tomorrow?
He says the new minister is
ready to take an interest.
Indeed, to give a joint interest.
He expects a call.
What shall I do? Call him?
- Bregonzo can go fuck himself.
- Go fuck himself?
Have you forgotten that a half
billion of options are at stake?
Your money and not just yours!
Think a little about yours truly!
- Emerald Shores!
- Fuck Emerald Shores.
And above all,
don't break my balls!
He needs a doctor.
Leave me alone.
Otherwise, I'll…
I've been spying on you
for a few days, Mazzacolli.
If you think this is over,
you're wrong.
You'll pay for it.
You son of a bitch!
Disgusting worm!
Worm!
What did you do to Clotilde?
Nothing… Nothing, I swear.
On my life…
On my mother's memory.
Yes, I tried…
but I didn't do anything to her.
I swear!
What do you swear?
On my mother's life.
I didn't do anything to her.
Nothing.
I won't kill you because I pity you.
I pity you all. You make me sick!
What do you want? Money?
Don't worry, I won't stop it
in the bank. You can cash it.
It's even covered.
Counselor!
- Thank you.
- For what?
Servants are paid
when they serve well.
And you have served me well.
Actually… Take it!
A gift.
You've been drooling
over it since you saw it.
My gift to you.
You take care of the transfer
of ownership. Understand?
If you don't admit her immediately,
I decline all responsibility.
Electroshock and right away!
We will then have a consultation.
- So, do we agree, Donna Raimonda?
- No.
- What?
- I said no.
Well then, good day.
Good day, Doctor.
I'll give him everything:
palaces, lands, factories…
Everything. But he must marry her.
He must marry her.
Bravo!
Hurry up, for heaven's sake!
Bregonzo's plane with the minister
arrives in an hour and a half!
You made me sick all night.
But where the hell were you?
- You have become a wild cat.
- A cat is beautiful.
Watch out for those two, eh?
Are you listening to me?
Yes!
The minister is coming to look.
To talk to you and
have the project explained.
- The recovery of the South…
- The project, sure.
- The economic roll-out.
- Yes.
And all that bullshit. You don't
need me to tell you what to say, eh?
No.
- Concetta!
- Here, Peppe!
Tonight we sleep in Bari
and then… in Milan!
I've a friend who emigrated last year
and he's in the big leagues!
Is it really true?
He gave it to you?
He's a fine man.
Poor guy.
In Milan, there's
the Duomo with 100 spires!
I put it all in the bag:
drawings, financial plans,
a copy of the application,
copy of option contracts,
everything!
Certainly.
And the bag?
The bag can go fuck itself.
Bye.
Counselor Saverio Mazzacolli…
Mazza-shitty!
Go now to the Loyola Palace.
Deliver it to Counselor Mazzacolli.
Be careful:
give it to him personally.
Yes, Ma'am.
Ma'am, Counselor Mazzacolli's here.
- He's here?
- Shall I let him in?
Listen…
I want Clotilde.
No, I don't want anything else.
Just Clotilde.
You take everything, Emerald Shores…
Take anything you want.
Just let me be near her.
I love her.
Did you come here.…
- to tell me this?
- Yes.
- Have you read…?
- What?
- The letter?
- No, what does it say? - Nothing.
Nothing. It's not important.
Come. Come!
Clo.
My love?
Clo!
Clo…
Well?
Clo!
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Let's leave them alone.
It is the will of the Lord!
The letter?
Has he already read it?
Whatever! Well then...
everything is all sorted out!
Yes, go on. I love…
I love you.
I love…
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
I understand! I do!