[Noble] Never in my life did I
think I would kill a man.
[gunshot]
Couldn't imagine
ever being that mad.
But after everything he did...
I wish I could wake him up
and kill his ass again.
[hip hop music]
[Noble]
I grew up an only child.
Some people think that
I have lived a sheltered life,
but I disagree.
I worked for everything
that I have.
It might not be much,
but it's mine.
My father was a police officer.
He got killed in
the line of duty when I was 12.
My mother was a teacher...
but she's retired now.
When she got
diagnosed with cancer
she didn't have
the energy to work anymore.
[whispering]
Mama, wake up.
[coughs]
Since my pops died,
it's been my job
to take care of her.
Thank you, baby.
[Noble] She has her good days
and bad days.
Mostly bad ones lately.
I've always kept to myself...
so I don't have any friends.
I like it that way.
It keeps me out of trouble.
[footsteps descending]
You want something
from the store?
You're going to get your money?
Yes, ma'am.
Bring me a-- a Vernors, please.
Hand me my medicine
before you go.
The big one over there.
Oh, thank you.
[Noble] The one friend
that I do have...
Jay...
is really like my brother.
Watch yo' back, nigga.
Bruh, you play too much.
[alluring music playing]
That still you?
[Noble]
No, bruh, that's all you.
[Jay]
All right.
What's up, Keisha?
[plastic bags crinkling]
Hey, Noble.
What's happening, man?
-How you doing?
-[Noble] I'm good.
I guess you come here
to get your cash, huh?
[Noble]
Yes, sir.
How much money I owe you, man?
[Noble]
Uh, $300.
Oh, I see.
Uh, ten cents a paper
times 1500 papers
times two weeks equals $300.
[Green laughs]
That's my man,
always do the math, man.
Always. You hear me?
All right,
let's get you squared away.
Kelly, do me a favor.
Go to the register and get
my man Noble 300, please.
Thank you.
[Noble] If these peanuts
cost 50 cents each,
why do you say
"two for a dollar?"
Why not just say 50 cents each?
[Green] Well, that's called
marketing, my friend.
And see, why are you
gonna sell one
when you can sell two
for twice the price? All right?
Two for one
just makes people feel good,
give 'em the warm and fuzzies,
you know what I'm saying?
If you do the math,
it's the same damn thing,
but most people
won't do the math, you know?
So, it's like your gimmick
to make more money?
-How much I owe you, man?
-$300 dollars.
$300.
[bottles clinking]
'Scuse me.
You dropped your money.
What is you, a boy scout?
No.
Well, I don't know
nobody that'd give that back.
You keep it.
My stuff.
[indistinct]
Better chill out
with all that attitude.
[Katherine moaning]
You okay?
[Katherine yelling]
-Mama, you okay?
[retching]
♪
[doctor]
There seems to be
a slight uptick
in your cancer cells,
and I believe that's what's
causing your extreme nausea.
What does that mean?
That means that the cancer
cells have found a way
to defeat the medication
and are starting to grow again.
Can you stop it?
We're definitely going to try.
There's this new medication,
it's called Embrexa,
and it's been working very well
for cases that
are similar to yours.
However, it can be
kind of expensive.
What's kind of expensive?
[doctor] Well, we're talking
roughly about $6,000 a month.
But I think that your insurance
covers up to 99% of the costs.
Yeah, I thought
that would make you happy.
That'll be $60.
[Katherine]
How much you got, babe?
[Noble]
I don't have any money.
[Katherine]
I've got 48.
[Noble]
Wait, yes I do.
I'll take this, here you go.
[pharmacist]
There you go.
-$40 is your change.
-Thank you.
[pharmacist]
Have a good day.
You too.
[Jay] $6,000?
Man, what the fuck?
That's what
I need to be selling.
What'd you say
that shit called again?
Embrexa.
They're not drug dealers.
Pharmaceutical scientists.
I looked it up.
Okay. Whatever the fuck that is,
they make money selling drugs,
so they drug dealers to me.
Man, that shit insane.
How the fuck
can y'all afford all that?
Our insurance is paying for it.
[music playing from car]
[Jay] Man, what insurance
company y'all got?
Them sons of bitches
let my grandmama die.
[women speaking indistinctly]
-What's up, baby?
-[woman] Hey.
Hey, yo. Who got next?
-[Jay] We do.
-You want to run?
Nah, fuck y'all lames.
I got next.
♪ I tell them
ain't no leave me ♪
♪ Then he asked me
how I do that ♪
♪ Stay rounded like toofless,
collect all your dukeheads ♪
♪ Then grab the bag,
take it back ♪
Noble.
[Noble]
Yes, ma'am?
Bring me my good wig and
yellow dress out the closet.
We going to church today.
You sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
I haven't felt
this good in years.
We're going to praise
the Lord in church today.
Now, go get my stuff.
[singing]
♪ Call Him up and tell Him
what you want ♪
♪ Call Him up
and tell Him what you want ♪
[Robert] Amen!
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Yes, yes, yes! Amen, amen.
Call him up
and tell him what you want.
[all] Yes!
I think our choir
deserves a round of applause.
[crowd cheering]
[Robert] Bless you. Take your
seats with love and honor.
Amen, amen, amen, amen.
Is that Jesus on the main line?
Call Him up
and tell Him what you want.
He didn't say He was
on the subsequent line,
He said He was on the main line.
Then call Him up
and tell Him what you want now.
Now, that'll preach.
Let me tell you why.
People confuse need and want.
How many times
have we heard someone say,
"Well, he don't need all that."
[crowd chuckling]
"Well, does she
really need that?"
[crowd chuckling]
[Robert] Well, let me tell you
about the God that I saw.
If God woke you up this morning
and most of y'all
with your right minds.
[woman]
Yes, Lord.
He gave you everything you need
to go and get what you want.
[crowd cheering]
-A!
-[crowd] Men!
Call Him up and tell Him
what you want, church.
Now, you know,
here at Greater United, we--
we talk a lot about miracles.
But very seldom do you
get an opportunity to see
an actual living miracle
in your presence.
Well, watch this.
Sister McKinley, raise your hand
so that everybody
can see that you here.
That's Sister McKinley
right there.
Let's give her a hand of praise.
-[crowd cheering]
-[Katherine] Amen. Amen!
Praise God!
We have been praying
for a long time...
-Yes, Lord, yes you have.
-[woman] Yes.
...for Sister McKinley.
Just a week ago...
she was stricken
and she was in her bed.
She couldn't get out.
And I talked
to my dear friend...
Deacon Green,
and I talked to him
about God answering prayer.
[crowd murmuring]
I want you to know...
you are witnessing
a living miracle,
the answer of prayer,
because Sister McKinley
is right here with us.
[crowd cheering]
Thank you, thank you, yes.
[Robert]
Everybody say, "Yeah!"
[crowd cheering]
-Thank you!
-[Robert] Say, "Yeah!"
[all] Yeah.
-[Robert] Yeah, yeah.
-[all] Yeah, yeah.
He may not come
when you want him to.
But he's what?
[all]
Always right on time.
Somebody say, "Yeah!"
[all] Yeah!
How are you doing?
Thank you so much.
So I need you to go ahead and
handle your business, all right?
Katherine. How are you?
Oh, sure is good to see you.
-Yes. Yeah.
-Good to see you, too.
Pastor.
-Hi, Sister McKinley.
-[Katherine] Oh, my God.
Kiki? Look at you.
You're so pretty.
My, have you grown up
to be a beautiful young lady!
Thank you.
-[Katherine] Good to see you.
-Good to see you.
[Katherine]
Oh, my goodness.
Rosa Lee Kendry?.
Katherine Lee McKinley!
It's so good to see you!
[melancholic music playing]
[people chattering]
[door creaking]
[Katherine sobbing]
What's wrong, Ma?
They're not gonna
pay for the medicine.
[sobbing]
But they can't do that.
That's what insurance is for.
No, they can do
whatever they want.
[Katherine sobbing]
[cars passing]
[crunching]
I would really love to help you,
but there's nothing I can do.
Once the panel makes a decision,
well, my hands are tied.
[Noble]
Can we talk to the panel then?
The doctor said my mother's
medicine is covered.
The doctor said. [chuckling]
The doctor don't run this.
He can't tell you
what we'll cover.
This is a matter
of life and death.
I know...
but we can't save everybody.
♪
[Jay]
Can't save everybody?
You shoulda punched
that bitch right in the throat
like, "Bitch,
this ain't everybody,
this is my mama."
That's crazy, bro.
How do you expect
someone to come up
with that kind of money?
[Jay groaning]
I could talk
to Dada if you want.
See if he'll put you on with us.
[Noble]
No, thank you.
I heard he killed somebody
for stealing from him.
Then don't steal from him.
It's just a option
for you to consider.
There's nothing to consider.
I'll never sell drugs.
What, you mean
you'll never sell drugs?
Shit. I'd do anything
to save my mama.
How else do you expect to
come up with that much money?
Every month.
I'm gonna figure something out.
Well, you better
figure something out fast.
[Noble]
Where Mr. Green at?
[Kelly]
Aisle five.
Mr. Green.
[Green] Hey, what's going on,
my man? How you doing?
-I'm good, uh.
-[Green] All right.
I was just wondering if I could
pick up an extra route or two
to earn some extra money.
Extra route?
So, you're trying to get
some of those new Luccies, man?
Nah, I just need to
earn some extra money.
Okay.
Guess I got something
I can give to you.
Might be another route
I can give you for,
let's say, $100 a week.
But that's not the same pay.
150.
[Green] I'm trying
to help you out, Noble.
125.
[Noble]
Okay. I'll take it.
All right.
It's a good deal.
Good negotiating, all right?
All right. We'll talk later.
Come back, I'll make sure
I take care of you, all right?
-All right?
-All right.
Hey. Matter of fact,
go talk to pastor, all right?
He might be
able to help you out.
All right. Thank you, Mr. Green.
[Green]
Okay. You're welcome, man.
14, 15...
[Robert]
How can I help?
It's my mother.
The insurance company won't
pay for her medicine anymore.
They cancelled it.
We can't even meet
with the people
for the next six months, so...
we trying to raise the money
to pay for it ourselves.
[Robert] Hm.
Well, I'm glad
you've come to me with this,
and I'm certainly
willing to help,
but it's not going to be a gift.
I'm gonna expect you
to work around the church
to work it off, okay?
All right,
so what are we talking about?
[Noble]
We need $5,186...
a month.
Hm.
Well, the church
is in no position
to give away that kind of money.
Have you investigated
any other ways
that you could raise the money?
Yeah, I picked up
an extra route from Mr. Green.
I was going to start
a FundMe page, too.
Me and my best friend, Jay,
we've been brainstorming ideas
on how to raise money.
Jay?
-Mrs. Ganvelle's son?
-Yeah.
Okay.
All right, well,
here's what I can do today.
I'm going to
advance you $500, okay?
Tell your mama I'm going to
start a special fund for her
at church on Sunday,
and I'm going to send over, uh,
one of the ladies from the, uh,
ladies ministry
to help with the cooking
and the cleaning
and that kind of stuff.
Thank you, pastor.
I-- I really appreciate this.
[Robert]
Here you go.
Listen. Remember this.
God works in mysterious ways.
[Jay]
So, how much you got?
500 from the church...
another 500 a month from Green.
Now, all I need is...
$4,686 for next month.
Plus, I started the FundMe page.
[Jay]
That shit don't work.
There's literally
a million sad stories on there.
You'll be lucky
if three people see your shit.
Might as well start
casing the bank right now.
I'm not going to break the law.
Do you have a choice?
-You gonna let your mama die?
-[Noble] No!
Then what you gonna do, Noble?
Get a job?
What job gonna pay
an 18 year old $6,000 a month?
I don't know.
But robbing a bank
ain't the answer.
Even if I do get away with it,
I'd have enough money
for a couple of months.
And then what?
I gotta rob another bank?
How many banks
am I gonna have to rob?
All of them!
Shit.
To keep my mama alive,
ain't a bank
from here to Mississippi
that ain't gonna get it.
I already told you what to do,
but you ain't
never selling drugs.
So, I don't know
what to tell you.
Tell me it ain't no different
from being
a "pharma suda centralist."
[Noble]
Pharmaceutical scientist.
Bro, whatever the fuck it is.
They selling drugs to save lives
and you'd be selling drugs
to save your mama's life.
So, what's the difference?
[Noble] One is legal
and the other is illegal.
There's legal and illegal.
But then
there's right and wrong.
What the insurance company
did was legal...
but was it right?
♪
[Noble] I hate to admit it,
but Jay was right.
[Katherine]
How are you doing, baby?
[Noble] So far, I picked up
an extra paper route,
started us
a FundMe page, and...
we got $500 from the church.
You're so smart.
Your father
would be so proud of you.
You hold on to it.
[Noble] The pastor said
he's going to start
an offering for us.
And he's sending
one of the ladies
from the church
to help around the house.
That's good news.
But I want to know
how you are doing.
[Noble]
I'm okay, Mama.
So now...
all we need
is $4,686 next month.
And I haven't even checked
the FundMe page yet.
That's good news, Mama.
Right?
That's great news...
but we're gonna need
more than that.
[Noble]
I know, but we'll get it.
Noble...
I have to tell you something.
The insurance company didn't pay
for the medicine
that I already have.
♪
So, we have to pay for that
in addition to coming up with
enough money for next month?
It's okay, baby.
♪
[paper crinkling]
[objects clattering]
[soft piano music playing]
[gravel rolling]
-[knocking on door]
-[Katherine] Come in.
-[door clicking]
-[Robert] Sister McKinley.
How're we doing?
I'm making it, Pastor,
but it's rough.
[Robert]
Let us pray.
Father God, we come to thee now,
heads bowed, hearts abounding.
Your faithful and good servant
is counting on you, God.
We pray for our Noble...
that he make good choices.
Amen.
[paper crinkling]
[phone vibrating]
Hello?
♪
That's what the fuck
I'm talking about, my nigga.
Now, let's go save ma dukes.
All right, let me do
all the talking.
And remember, do not touch Dada.
He be tripping on that shit.
[Noble] Okay.
[knocking on door]
-[Dabs] Hey, Jay.
-[Jay] What up, what up?
[Dabs]
Smells good.
Hey, what's good, man?
-[Noble] What's up?
-[Dabs] How you doing, kid?
[Suge]
Who the fuck is that?
It's Jay and Noble off Waverly.
[Suge] Why would you open
the door while I'm bagging?
Is you that damn dumb?
Hey, it's Jay,
and he knew the knock.
[Suge]
So what?
You don't crack the door
for nobody
while I'm in here working.
I wouldn't give a fuck if
it was your dead mama, nigga.
Man, get your stupid ass
in time out.
But he did the knock, man.
[Suge] Dumbass.
[Jay]
Where Dada at?
Who I look like?
Dada keeper? The fuck you want?
You remember my mans,
Noble, right?
He wanna be down with the team.
[Suge scoffing]
[both chuckling]
[lighter clicking]
We don't need no new guys, man.
He real smart, Shooter.
No bullshit. A genuine genius.
He just needs some money
for his mama's medicine, man.
She got cancer.
That sound like
a personal problem, dog.
Look.
I know you don't
know Da like that,
so you're a little bit leery.
-[Suge] Yo.
-But you got my word, my nigga.
He good.
Fuck his mama
and fuck your word.
[Noble] I should have
checked him right then.
It would have saved me a whole
lot of headache later on.
[Suge]
Won't need no new niggas, nigga.
Let's go.
[Dada]
Put him on.
Dada?
I didn't even see you.
[Dada]
Most people don't...
until it's too late.
You that dude from the store.
I heard about your moms.
It's fucked up,
so I'm gonna give you a chance.
But don't get this shit twisted.
I don't play
when it come to my money.
You keep $2 for every sale
and bring me the rest.
-You know how to count?
-Yeah.
Okay.
Don't make me regret this
or I'm gonna fuck
both of y'all up.
Tell them
to put him in rotation.
[Suge] Sure.
[dog snarling]
[dog barking]
Hey, put this bitch in rotation.
Shut the fuck up.
Shit, not in front of me.
We've got to
cut this nigga in, too?
[Jay]
Yeah, nigga.
Nigga, you last bro.
[Jay] Monty, if you don't
shut the fuck up, man--
[Noble]
Monty never liked me.
I don't know why.
I guess that's just how he is.
[Jay] Nigga, why?
Why is you always touching me?
All right. Get your money, bro.
How you doing?
What the fuck is you doin'?
-Hey, Noble.
-Noble?
[Dabs]
Yeah. Come get this, man.
[Jay]
Look at what you doin', man.
[Monty]
Man, why you trippin'?
[Dabs] All right, look at me
if you need help, bro.
[Monty]
That's my dough right there.
Noble.
What you doing out here?
[Noble]
Trying to make some money.
Oh, yeah?
I got 16. I'll pay you back.
[paper crinkling]
Oh, yeah,
I could help you flip this.
You know, I know everybody,
and I won't charge you.
-What's up?
-No, I got it.
[Mike] And I heard
about your moms, man.
Streets talk.
I'm trying to help you out.
How long you think
it'd take you?
Gimme a pill,
I'll be back in five minutes.
[Monty] Here you go.
He's finna make his move, nigga.
Yeah, here, let me see.
-Bitch ass.
-Dumbass!
See, he's not gonna
fucking make it.
What happened to him
being a genuine genius, nigga?
Come on
and sit back down, my nigga.
Come on. Sit down.
[Jay]
You all right, bro, you got it.
[Monty]
It's your last day.
[Jay]
Listen to me next time, bro.
[microwave beeping]
[Katherine humming]
[Noble]
Here you go, Mama.
[knocking on door]
-[Noble] I got it.
-Thank you, baby.
[Katherine]
Who is that?
It's Keisha.
[Katherine] Kiki?
Let her in!
[Keisha]
Hi, Sister McKinley.
Pastor Stevens asked me to
come help you around the house.
[Katherine]
Oh, thank God.
Noble been doing a good job,
but no way Noble
cleaning like that.
Deep cleaning
a woman's going do!
I know, that's right.
[Noble]
I got to go.
[Katherine] Noble.
Look how beautiful Keisha is.
I gotta go.
[Katherine]
Boy, bye.
So, how have you been?
[wind blowing softly]
Man, I'm done for tonight.
Mosquitoes bitin'.
-[Big Red] Who next?
-[Dabs] No, no.
My friend Noble will go next.
No, thank you. I'm good.
What's wrong, new guy?
You scared of pussy?
Scary as hell, bro. [chuckling]
Come on, Dabs.
Yes, sir!
[Big Red]
With all that dick you got,
you better have my whole $40.
[Dabs]
Oh, I've got it right here.
[Noble]
This ain't gonna work.
I thought you said I'd be able
to make $6,000 a month.
[Jay]
I know you didn't think
you was gonna
make that from day one.
Got to work your way up.
$46 in three days?
[Jay]
Be patient, nigga.
You can't rush the game.
Now, once you get enough money
to cop your own work,
you'll make more money.
What you mean?
[Jay]
It take money to make money.
The more work you cop,
the more money you make.
[Noble]
How much more?
Depends on what you buy,
how fast you move it.
[Dada] Here, nigga.
Ain't fuck with it, fucker.
[woman]
It's the new guy.
Let him in.
Uh-huh.
Got your stupid ass, nigga.
Fuck you can't keep goin'.
What up, doe?
Dada, can I talk to you?
Yeah, talk nigga.
I need to make more money.
[Dada laughing]
I'm serious. I really need to...
cop my own work.
[Dada]
Oh, shit.
You got your own money.
Now, that's
what I'm talking about.
-How much you got?
-[Noble] I got $600.
-So you sold 'em all?
-[Noble] Yeah.
[Dada]
Tell you what I'mma do.
I'mma sell you
50 oxies for that.
You want it?
[Noble]
How much can I make of that?
[Dada]
That's up to you.
1,000, 1,200,
depending on
what you sell them for.
I thought you said
you could do the math.
I can. I'll take it.
Yeah.
[Dada chuckles]
I like this little nigga.
He about his business.
[Dada chuckling]
Man, fuck that nigga.
[door shutting close]
♪
[plastic bag crinkling]
[man]
How much are these?
[Noble]
Half pill, 15.
Whole, 25. Or two for 40.
-And what are those again?
-Oxies.
-You got oxies two for 40?
Lemme-- lemme get both of 'em,
lemme get two of 'em.
All right.
Hey! New guy
got oxies, two for 40!
[Jay]
You got oxies? Oh.
Hey, where'd you
get those from, man?
[Noble]
I bought them from Dada.
[Dabs] Okay!
[Jay]
This boy bought to be ballin'!
I think Noble is still hurt by
what happened between you two.
He never really got over that.
I know, Sister McKinley,
and I really want to
make it up to him,
but he won't even talk to me.
Just be patient.
When the time is right...
he'll come around.
You'll have your chance
to explain yourself.
[phone rings]
I gotta go.
My sister's at your house.
She'll watch your mama.
She's good at watching people.
I know, Dabs,
but I've gotta go check on her.
Okay.
Hey, Noble.
Let me talk to you, man.
Look, I'll sell those
for you if you want me to.
I mean, it's up to you,
but I could sell those for you.
[Noble] How much
you want off each one?
Two good?
[Noble]
All right.
Remember, half pill's 15--
Whole pill 25, two for 40.
[chuckling]
[Noble] Dabs.
You keep three off each.
-Bet.
-[chuckling]
[chatter in television]
Noble, are you
still mad at Kiki?
She broke my heart, Ma.
Listen, Noble,
Kiki is a good girl.
[Noble] And?
Just talk to her.
[Noble]
For what?
She'll never get a second chance
to break my heart.
Just talk to her.
Ain't nothing wrong
with listening.
[Noble]
Listen, Ma.
I'll think about it,
but that's over.
Just talk to her.
Okay, I'm leaving.
I'll see you tomorrow,
Sister McKinley.
Bye, Noble.
-[Noble] Hold up.
-[clears throat]
I'll walk you home.
You don't have to. I'll be okay.
[clears throat]
I better walk you home.
I insist.
Okay.
[Katherine]
Good night.
I'm sorry, Noble.
Hey, I know I hurt you...
and I really didn't mean to.
I just...
At the time, Noble,
I wasn't thinking clearly.
Both of my parents
had just died.
I was living
with my grandmother.
Everything changed so fast.
I really didn't know
how to handle it.
Did you get my calls?
Yes.
It wasn't just you, Noble.
I didn't answer
any phone calls or texts
or return any calls
or listen to any messages.
I just wasn't ready
to face the world.
But I realize now
that that was a mistake
and I'm sorry.
I should have
answered your calls,
if nobody else's.
Yeah.
[Noble] I just
didn't know what happened.
It just felt like
somebody ripped my heart
out my chest and stomped on it.
I really do love you, Noble.
And I promise I'm going to
make this up to you.
[Noble]
We'll see.
See you tomorrow.
[keys jangling]
[balls clanking]
[indistinct chatter]
[Dada] There you go,
right there, just like that.
[thud]
Hey, yo, we gotta
do somethin' about Noble, man.
What is you talking about?
Man, this motherfucker
puttin' two for 40 oxies
on the street, man.
I can't make no goddamn money.
Man, I don''t give a fuck
about you making money.
As long as he''s copping from
me,
he can do
whatever the fuck he wanna do.
That's his work.
So, can I get some oxies then?
Nope.
[Monty] Then what the fuck
am I supposed to do?
Let me think.
Cop your own motherfucking work.
Then you can do
what the fuck he doin'.
Let me guess.
You got on $300 pair of shoes...
$600 pair of pants...
and a $100 shirt.
With no money to cop with!
[Suge]
Goofy ass.
-[phone ringing]
-[Dada] Stupid motherfucker.
-Not you, but you too.
-[Suge] Hey, yo.
[Dada]
Did you tell them what I said?
Gimme that work back
since it ain't
good enough for you, nigga.
[Monty] Then it's time
to riddle nigga.
-Gimme that shit back.
-[Dada] Some people don't
understand nothing but pain.
[Noble]
Hey, watch out.
It's way better than the stuff
Shooter's got, bro.
-[chuckling]
-[Monty] Hey, yo, Noble.
Let me holler at you, bro.
What's up?
Could I cop some work from you?
What about Shooter?
Man, fuck that bullshit he got.
You got them oxies,
that''s what I want.
-[Noble] All right.
-Thank you.
I'll give you
the same thing I'm giving him.
-Three off each.
-[Monty] All right, bet, deal.
[engine revving]
♪
-[Noble] Really, nigga?
-That's a family heirloom.
There's a whole story behind it.
It's been passed
down for generations.
I know
what an heirloom is, Noble.
Come on, let's get out of here.
[Noble]
Give me a second.
That's the money you got saved
for your mom's medicine?
Yeah, that's
for the next three months.
That's $18,000?
[Noble] That's 21.
Nigga!
It's time to upgrade!
Your money's flowing in now,
and that's not gonna stop.
You got enough
money to live a little now.
♪ I can't give a fuck about
what haters say ♪
♪ I know you got away,
but I'll be on the way ♪
♪ Don't you worry, baby,
I'll be on the way ♪
♪ I'm just happy that
I got my cup, I got my drank ♪
♪ I can't give a fuck
about what a nigga say ♪
Let's go breathe your pants,
my nigga.
♪ But I'll be on the way ♪
[Robert] Katherine,
I know you understand
what I'm talking about.
This isn't easy for any of us.
You need to talk to him.
I think he'll listen to you.
-I'll talk to him.
-This is serious.
-I mean serious.
-[Katherine] Robert.
I'll talk to him.
[door creaking]
-You ready?
-[Keisha] Yeah.
Hi, Pastor.
Noble. How are you?
-[Noble] I'm good.
-[Katherine] Hi.
-[Noble] Hey, Ma.
-[Keisha] I'm ready.
[Robert]
Now, hold on.
Listen, I'm getting
ready to leave, Keisha.
-I'll drop you off.
-[Keisha] Are you sure?
I wouldn't want you
to go out of your way.
No, I am absolutely sure.
Noble, so I'll see you
in church on Sunday, yes?
Yes, sir.
Noble.
Sit down.
Let me tell you something about
this risky business you're in.
People will come after you
out of pure jealousy.
They don't need a reason.
I know and I'm being careful,
Ma, I promise.
Soon as I save up enough money,
I'm going to start a business
and leave it alone.
-That's what they all say.
-[Noble] I promise.
♪
-You promise?
-[Noble] I promise.
[woman on TV] You don't get it.
He's tryin' to take my daughter
-[knocking on door]
-because he don't wanna pay me
24,000 a week in child support.
-[man on TV] 24,000 dollars?
-[woman on TV] Yeah.
I don't think
that's too much to ask for.
[door creaking]
[Noble]
What's up?
How'd you get past
the first door?
[Noble]
I got my ways.
Dabs.
[woman on TV] What about her?
They're not married.
Homegirl gets nothing.
All that money
goes to me and my baby.
Why do you
keep looking at your watch?
I just can't believe
it was only $500.
That's a lot of money.
I know, but,
I mean, considering.
Don't get distracted, Noble.
Stay focused.
You don't need all this stuff.
What about
your mama's medicine?
I got enough for that.
I'm just living a little.
Plus, the money flowing now.
That ain't gonna stop.
You sound just like them.
But I'm not them.
I'm different.
Here.
Open it.
There's two of ''em.
-Thank you.
-[banging on door]
[Noble]
What up?
Yo, how much work
you got on you?
[Noble]
I got a little something.
Stop playing with me, nigga.
I got somebody
who want to buy it all.
I got about 500, here.
Why can't you get it from Dada?
[Suge] Because I don't
know where he at.
Damn, why everybody
think I got this nigga
in my back pocket, man?
Just give me the work
and I'll give it back to you
when we get around to the house.
[Noble] Yeah.
[Suge]
Yeah, 'sup.
[door clicks closed]
[Katherine]
Who is that?
Nobody.
Noble, don't you bring
that mess in this house.
-I mean it.
-I won't.
[Suge]
About time you got here.
[engine revving]
[hip-hop music plays]
Yo, what's wrong, bro?
[Jay]
Hey, where you been at, bro?
-The block on fire right now.
-[Noble] Give me a second.
[Dada]
It's a drought, nigga.
What's the drought?
There's been a drought for about
damn near a week, man.
Ain't nobody got shit,
talking about
the whole city dry.
[Noble]
What's a drought?
A drought.
Dried up?
Dry?
Come on, Noble. A drought.
Where do you get that from?
[Dada] I lucked up on this shit,
dog, it's some real shit.
What about that 500
that I just gave you?
I need that back.
Hey, I need to talk
to you about that man.
I got robbed.
I mean, I fought him
like a motherfucker, but shit.
He had a gun.
There wasn't shit I could do.
But that's the bag
I gave you right there.
I'm not stupid, Shooter.
He took the work, not the bag.
You calling me a liar, nigga?
I just want my money.
Money?
You worry about
some motherfucking money
when I just told you
I almost got killed?
Nigga, fuck your money.
I give it to you when I get it.
Now get the fuck out my face
before I riddle your ass.
I'm tired of these
young ass niggas, man.
-[laughing]
-Shit.
[Noble]
How long do they last?
[Jay] Sometimes months,
unless you find a plug.
I don't got months.
What's a plug?
[Jay]
The main supplier.
You need to beat Shooter's ass.
You can't let
that nigga run over you
because he gonna
keep running over you.
And so is everybody else.
And get shot?
He carry a gun everywhere he go.
So what?
Even if you lose the fight,
he'll know you ain't no ho.
When's the last time
you been killed?
What?
Exactly. Did you miss
the part about the gun?
♪
Thank you for understanding.
[Keisha]
That's not important to me.
You are.
[smooch]
♪
[engine roars]
[banging on door]
[grunts]
[sighs]
Noble.
-How you doing?
-[Noble] I'm good.
[Green]
Come on in, man.
Not quite looking
like yourself, you all right?
-[Noble] Yeah.
-Have a seat.
[sighs]
-Want something to drink?
-No, thank you.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah.
All right.
-All right.
-[knocking on table]
How long
I've been knowing, you Noble?
-All my life.
-[Green] All your life.
So why you never told me
your mother needed money?
I don't know.
I guess I was just
trying to keep it private.
Aren't doing too good
of a job of it, right?
I hear you need $6,000 a month.
I can help you with that.
How?
Let's just say
I know some people.
♪
[Noble]
You're the plug?
That's some grown man shit.
-You ready?
-[Noble] I'm ready.
All right.
Sunday.
There's a meeting
at the warehouse off of Third.
You're an invited guest.
You got a black suit?
Yeah, but it's too small.
All right.
[sighs]
Get yourself a new suit.
In the meantime...
keep your mouth shut.
Get your boys back to work.
How much I owe you?
[Green]
That's 4000 pills.
Give me five off each.
Bet.
[Green]
Get on out of here, man.
♪
[Monty] What the fuck
this nigga smiling for?
[Noble]
Who you love?
Shit! You nigga!
[Dabs] Come here!
I'm about to get the work.
[knocking on door]
♪ Can I be your star tonight? ♪
-[smooching]
-I got the plug.
[Keisha laughing]
Stop before you
make me spill my juice!
What are you talking about?
I'm back on.
♪ I hope you'll still want me ♪
♪ I hope you'll still need me ♪
♪ A million years from now ♪
You'll buy some more jewelry
and another fancy car?
[Noble] No, I'm gonna
stick to the plan.
Ten houses, then a franchise.
[Keisha]
Please just stay focused.
[Noble]
I am.
♪ I'm an addict for your love ♪
♪ It keeps me high,
it keeps me high ♪
♪
♪ Keeps me high ♪
Bitch, I'm not giving you shit.
You better ask
your husband for some money.
Call me when you need some dick.
Bitch got the game
all fucked up.
She'll figure it out though.
Hey, they got work
across the street.
Man, they over there
probably selling aspirins, man.
[paper rustling]
♪
Fuck is he doing here?
Sit down, Dada.
So, what the fuck is this?
We decided to give Noble
control of the south-end.
[Dada]
Get the fuck out of here.
He's a kid.
What do he know
about running the streets?
I mean, y'all better
quit playing with me.
[Green] It's been voted on.
[Dada]
Then un-vote on it!
I'm not working
for no motherfucking kid.
Sit your
motherfucking ass down, nigga.
The decision's been made.
You and every crew
from the south-end
will now go through Noble.
Are we clear?
[Dada] You all can
get the fuck out of here.
I said I'm not working
for no kid!
Matter of fact,
who idea was this?
This came from T.
[Dada]
Then, I need to speak to T.
You know the rules,
don't you, Dada?
[Dada] Yeah.
Nobody sees or speaks to T.
Now, how fucking
convenient is that?
How do I know if T is even real?
But y'all wanna put a kid...
in charge of the streets?
Y'all do that.
Good luck, little nigga.
♪ Life on the edge,
know when I'm coming correct ♪
♪ City's aggressive,
got a new bitch ♪
♪ All of my sexing,
hop on a plane ♪
♪ See you in L.A.,
got me a relic ♪
♪ All in my necklace,
tell 'em to sell it ♪
♪ The money, I get it and
everything that I be flowing ♪
♪ [indistinct] and shorty be
wetty like water in Venice ♪
♪ I'm running,
I'm taking advantage ♪
♪ They mention that
I'll be a menace, hold up ♪
♪ Gimme a minute,
baby girl, you trippin' ♪
♪ Lovin' the telly,
tell God I'm ready ♪
♪ Pop smoke, a nine milli ♪
♪ I know that I'm petty,
so sick I need medic ♪
♪ You sweet, diabetic ♪
♪ On scene when I'm ready,
heartbeat when I bet it ♪
♪ Put it on me like sweaters ♪
♪ Baby girl, you sweatin' ♪
-[Noble] Hey, Mama.
-[Katherine] Hey, baby.
[smooching]
[Keisha] Ugh, bae,
you got to look out for him.
We can't have him out here
with his collar all crooked.
Hey, Jay. Oh, one hour, yeah?
Hey, Sister McKinley.
[Katherine]
Hey, Kiki!
I see y'all back together.
Mm-hmm.
It's cool.
I don't like smart women anyway.
I'm about to get started.
I don't.
They always trying to rush it.
They always want to travel
and get married and shit.
I'm just trying to smash
then lay up and watch TV.
Bro, what?
That's crazy.
[Jay]
Look, I'm just saying, man.
♪
♪ All I hear, go get the money ♪
♪ Sure, I go get it,
get it, get it ♪
♪ Hate me 'cause I do something
right, so I let 'em ♪
[yelling]
[mug clattering]
[car radio blaring]
[Noble]
Turn that off, bro.
[Katherine]
Noble, what is that?
[Noble]
Nothing, Ma.
Just some idiot
playing his music too loud.
-They gone now.
-[Monty] Chill, bro.
[Noble]
What're you doin', man?
What're you talking about?
[Noble] The car, the paint,
the rims, the sounds?
-What's that?
-I bought me a car.
-What's your problem?
-Bro,
that's unnecessary attention.
[Monty]
It's just a car.
Nigga, you bought one.
[Keisha] What is that smell?
Girl, I was
dreaming about some fish
and woke up
craving salmon croquettes.
[Keisha]
Can I open the window?
That smell is
making me nauseous.
Sure, baby. I'm sorry.
How do you feel about Tasha?
[Keisha]
Who's Tasha?
It's not just a car, Monty.
That's a billboard.
Get rid of it.
Whatever, nigga,
you got me fucked up.
[Noble]
I'm not playing.
Get rid of that thing
and don't bring it back.
I'm serious.
That's just a name
that I always loved.
[engine revving]
If Noble had been a girl,
I would have named him Tasha.
-[chuckles]
-It's pretty.
[Suge]
This shit, man.
[engine revving]
This nigga Monty
getting paper now too?
Man.
How long is you gonna let
this little motherfucker
get away with this shit?
Should've never
put this nigga on!
With your dumbass!
Nigga, who the fuck
is you talking to?
I'm saying they eating
like a motherfucker.
Maybe I start rolling
with these niggas.
Then get the fuck on then,
you dick riding ass nigga.
I told you to give me a minute,
but if you can't wait,
then get the fuck on!
Look, D. It ain't like that.
But you know me, nigga.
I'm tired of waiting
and these motherfuckers
is making us look stupid.
You right.
Playtime is over with.
[Jay] If you ask a girl
what she doing?
And she say, "I was thinking,"
uh, you gotta go.
You little bitch ass nigga.
-[punch lands]
-[thud]
You sell another crumb
around this motherfucker,
I'mma take you
for everything you got.
You hear me?
[Noble spits]
Look at me.
Yeah, I hear you.
Can't nobody save your ass.
Not one more
motherfucking crumb.
Now try me
if you think I'm playing.
-Y'all have a good day.
-[laughs]
Whoo.
[Jay]
Oh, my God.
I told you to fight that
nigga Shooter a long time ago.
Now you gotta kill him, bro.
This shit ain't gonna stop.
[Dabs]
What you do, No?
[Katherine]
I love children.
I wished I could have had ten.
[laughing]
I don't know about ten.
Ready to go?
Yeah.
[engine revving]
-Hi!
-[Keisha] Hi, how are you?
I am great.
-Keisha, right?
-[Keisha] Keisha.
[realtor]
Hi, and you are?
-Dabs.
-[Realtor] Dabs.
-And you must be Noble.
-Yeah.
All right. Now, as you can see,
all the floors are new.
You got great flow through here.
And the kitchen
is being completely remodeled,
but the real jewel
in this home is the basement.
Let's go take a look.
[Dabs]
Dada wants 2000.
What do I tell him?
Tell him to give you an hour
and I'll call him back.
Hey, man,
gimme an hour, man, all right?
[Suge] Dabs.
What's in the bag, buddy?
[Dabs]
Nothin'', nothin'.
Yeah, well, we gonna see.
Hey, come on!
Now why lie to me, Dabs?
After all I did for you?
Man, you breakin' my heart.
I think I'm ''bout to cry.
That''s not mine, man,
give it back.
[Suge]
Or what, ho ass nigga?
[Dada]
I know whose it is.
Tell that nigga I said
this is more than a crumb.
[Dabs] Man, Dada and Shooter
just took my bag.
-What happened?
-Man, they snatched it.
And wouldn't give it back.
Dada said to tell you
that's more than a crumb.
Where they at?
In front of his house.
[Noble]
Come on.
Fuck.
Look, Shoot.
It's the Powerpuff Girls.
[laughing]
This nigga dumb.
Where my money, Dada,
I'm not playin' with you!
[Dada]
Neither am I, motherfucker.
The money's mine.
Matter of fact,
everything you got is mine.
-Them shoes, this shirt.
-[Suge] Full of shit.
[Dada]
Even that car's mine.
And I want it all.
And if you ain't
gonna give it to me...
then I'm just
going to have to take it.
Now, see, the problem is...
once I start taking shit...
I don't know when to stop.
I might take your dog,
your bitch...
and the milk from
your mama left titty, nigga.
So don't come ''round
talking that tough shit
because the only reason
you alive...
is because I allow you to be.
[Suge]
Nigga. Straight up.
[grunting]
-[thudding]
-Stupid-ass motherfucker.
Ass nigga. What's up?
Get your bitch-ass outta here.
[Dabs] Come on, Noble.
Wake up, man.
[Suge]
Damn, bitch ass nigga.
-[Dabs] Come on, wake up.
-[Dada] Let's go.
You're not waking up, man.
Come on, get up, man, get up.
[door shuts closed]
[footsteps approaching]
You gonna have
to kill them niggas.
Both of 'em.
There ain't no way
around it now.
I know these niggas,
and they ain't gonna stop.
How many you say they took?
Eight.
8000 pills.
That's unforgivable.
If you gonna survive
in this game...
then you gonna have
to dead them niggas.
Both of them.
[Katherine singing]
♪ You are important to me ♪
♪ I need you to survive ♪
Noble, come go
to church with me today.
No, Ma, I don't think
that's a good idea.
Why not?
It's good for your soul.
Oh, my God.
What happened to your face?
[Noble] I-- I got
into a little scuffle.
[sighs] Oh, baby. Come here.
Come here.
You don't have to do this
for me, sweetheart.
Please let it go, baby,
I've lived
a long and happy life.
And it's time
for you to live yours.
You don't have
to do this for me.
It's time for you
to let God take care of me.
Oh, Lord. Dear Heavenly Father,
please watch over my child.
Take away his fears.
Help him to have the strength
that he needs
to accept your will.
Amen.
[TV show playing]
-[Keisha] Diante.
-Yeah?
-[Keisha] Can you come here?
-Yeah, yeah. What's up?
We need some milk.
Can you go get me some?
-Milk. Yeah. Got it.
-I'll go get my purse.
No, no, no, it's cool.
I got-- I got my wallet.
[Keisha]
Thank you.
Yeah, welcome, you're welcome.
[door shuts closed]
[Dada]
Bitch-ass nigga right there.
[Suge]
Yeah, let's get his ass.
[Dada]
This hoe ass nigger.
[beeping]
What up, doe?
Shooter. Dada. Damn. Again?
So, you a whole bitch
out here now, Dabs?
[Dabs] That was wrong, Dada.
Noble ain't do nothing to you.
Ain't do nothing to me?
Tell me what that
motherfucker did for me.
I helped him
just like I helped you and the
rest of these hoe-ass niggas.
Who was there
when your parents died, Dabs?
Me.
And ain't none of you niggas
did nada for Dada!
Ungrateful bitches.
Let's take a ride, Dabs.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Keisha]
Have you seen Diante?
[Noble]
Not today.
I think I'm done.
[Keisha] Yeah.
I think this is God's way
of telling you it's time.
Me too.
I'm glad you said that, Noble,
'cause a lot of people
don't know
when to leave the streets alone.
They keep trying to make
a career out of selling drugs,
but it's more
of a temporary thing.
All right.
Good.
'Cause I was about to go
and kick Shooter's ass myself.
[laughing]
-You got my back.
-Always.
[phone buzzing]
Okay. I'll be right there.
I'm going to stop, I promise.
[smooching]
I just need
to wrap some things up.
[pop music playing
in background]
[Dada] Monty.
What's up, Dada?
[Dada]
Let's talk.
[panting]
[Suge]
Looking good, Playboy.
Thanks.
You got a nice chain.
-Yeah, this is real nice.
-[Dada] Mm-hmm.
Got a nice new car.
[thumping]
You eatin' good.
Lemme hold something.
What's up, man?
Listen, I ain't got it.
-[thudding]
-[vomiting]
[coughing]
[gun clicking]
Just gonna blow
this motherfucker face off.
-Right now.
-[panting]
Noble got it.
[sighs] F that shit.
[Monty]
Noble got it, I swear.
It's at his girl's house.
[Dada] Nice talkin'
to you, Monty.
[Green]
You positive?
[Noble] Yeah.
I'm not sure what he'll do next.
I think it's best
to just leave it alone.
[sighs] I'll let
the members know your decision.
I really feel like
you jumping the gun.
I think you need
to give it more time.
Come on, man.
Your people need you.
Your mother needs you.
I'll think about it.
[Green]
Ah, that's my boy.
Look, man, these type of things
happen from time to time.
All right?
I'll take care of it for you.
-What do you mean?
-[Green] Dada.
You know what the hell I mean.
Talk to him, see if we can get
your money back for you.
Look here, man, if you're going
to be a part of this thing
in the future,
you are going to stay.
You're going to have to handle
these things on your own.
-You understand?
-Yeah.
All right.
It'll be all right.
[phone dings]
[clears throat]
-I can explain.
-Explain what?
Why would you stash drugs
at my house, Noble?
After all I've been through
and all you were talking
about quitting
and realizing when God is
trying to tell you something,
you go and put drugs
in my refrigerator?
Keisha, it ain't even like that,
I put that there
a long time ago.
[Keisha scoffs]
That's even worse.
Just get your stuff and leave.
[Noble]
Excuse me.
[door creaking]
[door slams shut]
-[Katherine] Good morning.
-Good morning.
[sobbing]
[Katherine]
Noble, what's wrong?
I don't know what to do, Ma.
[sobbing]
It's like I want to stop,
but I can't stop.
Why not?
[Noble] I have so many
people depending on me.
Those people
don't need you, baby.
What are they going to do
if you die or go to prison?
They'll find
another way to survive,
-so don't believe that.
-You need me.
There's not enough money
in the world to save me, Noble.
You can't change God's plan.
What you need to do
is focus on Keisha.
I would, but that's over.
What do you mean that's over?
[Noble]
She left me.
[Katherine]
No, she didn't.
She might be
a little emotional right now,
but, um, she still loves you.
See, that's what you need
to be fighting for.
-Keisha and your new family.
-[phone buzzing]
[Noble] What family?
You only family I got.
Well, that's about to change.
-[Noble] What you mean?
-Keisha's pregnant.
-[phone buzzing]
-Why do you say that?
[Katherine]
Woman's intuition.
[buzzing continues]
-[Noble] Quit playing.
-I'm not playing.
The body of a young black man
found in the Downriver
area last night
has been identified
as 20-year-old Diante Watkins.
A woman's intuition.
[buzzing continues]
Investigators believe that
Watkins was beaten to death
and dumped in the river
approximately two days ago.
[Jay]
They killed Dabs.
-What?
-[Jay] It's on the news.
Google it.
You are asked to call
Detroit police immediately.
[reporter]
The body of a young black man
was found in the Downriver
area last night
has been identified
as 20-year-old Diante Watkins.
Investigators believe that
Watkins was beaten to death
and dumped in the river
approximately two days ago.
Police are asking for the
public's help with this case.
If you have any information
that might be helpful
in solving this brutal murder,
you are asked to call
Detroit police immediately.
It's up to you, man,
I could sell those for you.
[Noble]
You can keep three off each.
[Dabs] Bet.
[melancholic music playing]
[knocking on door]
What you want, Noble?
[Noble]
Came to apologize.
-Can I come in?
-No.
I really don't want
to see you right now.
I understand, Keisha...
but I really need
to talk to you.
They...
They killed Dabs.
I don't know what happened.
I just know that I really
need somebody to talk to.
Will you talk to me?
[sobbing]
I can't do it, Noble.
My brother
was all I had left...
in this world.
And that lifestyle just...
took him from me. [crying]
I don't want to be around it.
That's not
what I want in my life.
I get it.
And that all changes right now.
I'm done.
I promise.
Please, just open the door
and let me talk to you.
I can't do it, Noble.
[music continues]
[door creaks open]
Don't leave.
[tense music playing]
[gasping]
[Suge] It's way too
dangerous in these streets
to be asleep, nigga.
Wake the fuck up.
We can do this two ways.
We can do this the easy way...
or we can do this my way.
Where the fuck is the work?
It's not here,
but you can have it, Dada.
I'm done with this shit.
[Suge]
Strike one. You lyin'.
Leave him alone. He's not lying.
Shut up, bitch, 'fore I feed
you one of these bullets.
Now, let's try this again.
Where the fuck is the work?
[Keisha]
I don't know,
but it's not here, so get
the fuck out of my house.
[laughing]
[gun clicking]
[Dada] Bitch,
you must think I'm playing--
[Noble]
It's at my house.
[Dada]
Damn, you an ugly little bitch.
Your grandma
was ugly as fuck too.
I see where you get
this shit from.
This shit ain't here.
I told you, it's at my house.
Take me to my house and I'll
give it to you and it's over.
[Dada] Nigga,
it's over when I say it's over.
Let's go.
What should we do
with this bitch?
-Kill her.
-[Noble] Wait!
You don't have to kill her.
She ain't got nothin'
to do with this.
She's pregnant, Dada.
Come on, man.
Better yet, I got a better idea.
Bring her with us.
And if this nigga
come up a dollar short...
then you kill her.
Yeah.
Let's go.
[Suge]
Fuck you waiting for?
[Dada]
Stop moving, bitch.
-Give me a second.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Fuck you think you're doing?
Do I look dumb, motherfucker?
If we ain't back in six minutes,
put a bullet in that bitch.
[Suge]
Fo'sho.
Yeah.
You little sexy ass thing,
ain't you?
Pastor, I'll see you later.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, bye-bye.
[door creaks open]
Noble, where have you been?
-And who's this?
-This is Dada.
-How you doing, ma'am?
-I'm fine.
But who are you?
-I'm just a friend.
-Ma, it's cool.
We're just here to pick up
some paperwork and we're out.
-[Suge] Come here.
-[whimpering]
I'm going to take your pussy
and feed it to my dog.
Who the fuck
are you snatching away from?
[tense music playing]
♪
-Where's the rest of it?
-[Noble] That's it.
You already took eight of 'em.
Don't play dumb, motherfucker.
You forget who you talking to?
There's still two missing.
Jay got 'em.
See, now that's gonna cost you.
Let's go.
Is that for me?
Ain't you a little too old to
be playing with guns and shit?
Look at you, man,
You used to be a soldier.
Now, you just washed up,
coming out the house
all loud and shit.
You pathetic.
[bells chiming]
Where are you going with that?
He told me I could have this.
No the hell he didn't.
You don't walk past me
in my house.
-Hey, let me go! Let me go!
-Ma! Ma!
-[smacking]
-[screaming]
Make a move and I'll dead
both of you bitches right now.
Noble.
Let's go.
[Katherine] Noble?
-Oh, my God.
-[phone ringing]
[whimpering & crying]
Get your ass on, nigga.
Walk, nigga.
And don't try no funny shit.
[engine revving]
Hey, Noble! How's it going?
I just came by to see your mama.
She's not home
right now, pastor.
Really? That's--
that's interesting
because I just spoke to her
on the telephone.
[chuckles] All right.
And you know what?
You boys need to come
to church more often,
I ain't seen you in a while.
[Dada]
We good on church, pastor.
So you can have a good night.
On second thought...
since I-- since I can't get
y'all to come to church...
I guess I just
have to bring church to you.
[snaps fingers]
Put it down.
[Dada] Fuck.
You do realize that if I snap
my finger one more time,
these gentlemen
will blow your brains out.
Man, what kind of pastor is you?
That's a good question,
but I got a few for you.
Have you ever looked
into the eyes
of a young child
dying from a gunshot wound?
Hmm?
The only mistake that they made
is because they were trying
to steal something to eat.
What about you?
Hmm?
Have you ever spent your last
dime on a family in need
while you're waiting
for a government grant
to be approved?
Hmm?
Have you ever looked
at someone that you love...
who's dying?
And the only thing between
them living and dying is money.
Hmm? Hmm?
Tell me,
can you imagine the burden...
of trying to save a community...
that for generations has been
systematically disenfranchised,
beaten down, used and abused?
Some of them
so, so undereducated
that they can't even read
or write enough to get a job.
Hmm?
Do they deserve to die?
Do they not deserve
to have a good life?
A decent life?
They are why I do what I do.
They are my why.
You are my why.
So, don't judge me.
Leave that to God.
I'm just a man.
An ordinary man,
doing the best I can
against insurmountable odds.
Trying to level
the playing field
for people that our society
has left for dead.
Now...
we are all going to die.
That's inevitable.
But it doesn't say anywhere...
that we have to kill.
Brothers.
Put down your guns.
[Noble] I'm not going
to let these shits off, Pastor.
-Noble.
-They did too much!
-[Robert] Noble.
-No!
Noble, if healing has got
to begin, let it begin now.
[Noble]
Not this time, pastor.
[Robert]
It's got to start somewhere.
They killed my friend Dabs
for no reason.
He stole my money
and he smacked my mama.
They did too much.
[grunting]
Give me my fucking money.
Strike one, motherfucker.
Where's the other money
you stole from me?
It's in the trunk.
It's all there.
-[grunts]
-[smacking]
Bitch!
Don't ever touch me again!
Now...
which one of you
motherfuckers killed Dabs?
I don't know what the fuck
you talking 'bout.
Strike two.
-[gunshot popping]
-[yelling]
Let's try this again and stop
fucking playing with me.
Which one of you
motherfuckers killed Dabs?
Man, it was Shooter.
You lying motherfucker!
I wouldn't do that shit!
Dada did it with
a baseball bat in his garage.
Man, check the back
of the truck.
Think about it, man.
I'm Shooter.
If I'd did something
I would've popped his ass.
I did a lot of
fucked up shit, I know,
but I ain't do this,
not this time.
I promise you. Dada did it.
[grunts]
-[gunshot popping]
-You motherfucker.
Strike three.
[Robert] No, Noble. Don't.
Don't. Don't, don't, don't.
[Katherine] Noble!
[somber music playing]
♪
[Robert] If there's anyone
in the room
who ever received a letter
from Katherine,
please raise your hand.
And if it was...
right on time, raise your hand.
And if it appeared that
what she was writing to you
was specifically for you
and your situation,
raise your hand.
-[woman] Yes.
-Yes.
Because that was her gift.
And she was...
kind enough to share
that with each one of us.
We have so much
to be grateful for.
♪ I have the faith ♪
♪ That sees the invisible ♪
♪ Expects the incredible ♪
♪ Who receives the impossible ♪
♪ Faith that can conquer ♪
♪ Anything ♪
♪ Faith that overrules ♪
♪ My problems ♪
♪ Faith to know God ♪
♪ Can solve them ♪
♪ Faith ♪
[Noble]
After my mother died...
I realized that she was right.
You can't change God's plan.
After all the struggle
that I went through...
I still couldn't save her life.
But, I could still
help other people.
Show them that there's
a right way to do everything.
Even the wrong thing.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ There's something there
in the wild ♪
♪ It's a reflection of me ♪
♪ People fight for survival ♪
♪ I'm chasing tails,
I'm surrounded ♪
♪ Can't stop
for a second to breathe ♪
♪ My thoughts
are flowing like water ♪
♪ One day soon I will find ♪
♪ I know I am close,
I know I will shine ♪
♪ One day soon I will fly ♪
♪ And know I am free,
I'm feeling alive ♪
♪ Take me back to the jungle ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ The city keeps me distracted ♪
♪ But I know where I should be ♪
♪ Tell my mama I'm leavin' ♪
♪ Just take your mask off
and join me ♪
♪ I know you're dying to see ♪
♪ All the secrets I'm hiding ♪