Edition
www.trigon-film.org
And we begin our news tour
with the A! Jazeera channel
which said that an extensive
investigation has been conducted
by a team of international
independent technical experts
who confirmed the claim of interference
of an Al Jazeera Sports Channel
during the broadcast
of the FIFA World Cup,
and the experts were able
to identify the site
from which the interference originated
which is near the city of Salt, Jordan,
and noted that this site is deliberately
interfering with the broadcast
signal of A! Jazeera Sports
resulting in interference of
the live broadcast of a number
of World Cup matches.
"The Guardian" newspaper
confirms this hypothesis
and further more based
on the secret documents
that refer to the site of interference
being in Jordan and more specifically
near the city of Salt.
which used in the process
advanced equipment
that interrupts the origin
of the signal transmission
and the British newspaper assured,
based on the experts' quotes that
this has occurred with the knowledge
of the Jordanian government
in what appears to be linked to anger
in Jordan after failing to reach
an agreement with Al Jazeera Sports
from banks and currencies to the
prices that are changing day after day...
Well... I need two hours
and I'll be back.
Could you please turn it
down a little bit?
Of course I'm by myself!
Who would I be with?
No! Do not come by unless
you give me a call first.
Can I be honest with you?
I don't want you in my life anymore.
In Amman, hundreds of
Jordanians protested against the
repression and intimidation
of journalists
which took place when they organized
a protest under the name.
The Friday for Dignity
and Freedom of Expression.
The demonstrators burned
an American flag
to protest what they called
the U.S. intervention
in the policies of
the Jordanian Government,
and called for the resignation
of the Prime Minister as well as
demanding freedom of the press.
Last Friday, a violence fight broke out
when police tried to
break up a demonstration
that called for reform.
Many journalists were injured.
From Amman, the bureau chief,
Yasser Abu Hilal,
will report on the details.
Yasser, what was the extent of
the fight and what will happen now?
Demonstrations swept a number
of Jordanian cities south in Maan,
and in the south, in Karak
and Tafieleh and Irbid in the north.
This Friday called for reform
but brutal repression by the police
resulted in many of journalists
being injured and hospitalized.
Prior to the demonstration,
a meeting by King Abduflah II and the
official representative
of the journalist, Tareq Momani
took place yesterday,
and the message meeting was clear...
It will do for couple of days.
Can you take me to the airport?
What for?
I finally got my visa.
So what about the money?
Be patient with me.
I need it now!
What's the rush?
I have to have surgery.
Surgery for what?
When was the last time
you checked the oil?
No need... the engine
is the problem.
The car keeps shutting off...
This isn't working...
You want me to keep
going on like this?
I don't get it... what do you want?
Just fix the engine.
Fouad, get me the notebook...
it's in the drawer.
You've got 300 dinars worth
of fines since last year.
When are you going to pay them?
I'm going to be honest with you...
In general, I'm unhappy
with your performance.
If you don't shape up within a week,
you give me the cab back and go.
What happened?
The front part is totally wrecked.
So, when will it be done?
Half a day.
So what are you waiting for?
Get back to work.
You think you're the only one
with dignity in this world.
And what if I told you
to buzz off?
A couple of days ago
you called me a jackass!
Or do you only use
etiquette when...
What are you up to?
I'm bored out of my mind.
Going to work.
Mom, are you going out tonight?
Then can you leave me your car keys...
I'm going out but I won't be late.
You're going out every day now?
I'm going to a graduation party.
Take a cab.
You want me to step out of the hair salon
into the street and hail a cab?
No way!
The first time I ever went to a salon
was on my wedding day.
Did you add your father on Facebook?
I don't want to.
Why?
Because I don't want to.
Add him!
Mama, can you stop acting like a teenager.
Let me know when you add him.
What do you really want from all this?
Will you give me the keys or not?
Didn't your dad say he'd buy you a car?
Talk to him...
Message?
Call him!
I don't feel like it.
And, anyway, I don't have credit.
Your father doesn't answer messages.
You'll see...
I'll keep sending until he answers.
How's your boyfriend, the mechanic?
Mom, he's not a "mechanic".
Jaber is a mechanical engineer.
Darling, men are stupid creatures.
Don't comfort him,
don't ever let him feel safe.
You have to always
keep him worried... afraid.
Don't you dare tell him that you love him.
No! He told me loves me.
Don't say it until he loses
hope from waiting.
Jaber...
I've been a taxi driver for a while now...
When will you give me my old job back?
We still don't have any openings.
It's been 5 years.
You know more than anyone what
I can do for the showroom sales.
You're the one who left
to go work in the Gulf.
Imad, what were you doing
on their roof?
Do you want us to get
in trouble with the neighbors?
"After a women has found
her way into a man's heart,
she will seek to control him,
and there are many ways
she can keep that control
like, for example, if he has
a submissive personality,
or h' he is poor and she is not.
She could also be sadistic and
he could be unable to stand up for himself
Moreover, the women's family is
could be wealthy and have power in
society increasing
the psychological pressure.
AH of these things could cause
the husband to surrender
and remain silent in the face of abuse.
In fact, in the Arab world
today in only 7% of cases do
men started to admit to
the violence they face
and they do not fully recognized it
until they have reached
a severe stage of depression and abuse.
And so when we try
to know and understand
the reason for their depression
we uncover the truth of the violence.
I've missed you, kid.
Pretty soon you'll be as tall as me.
I might be taller.
So why weren't you two talking?
She was upset.
Why?
I was supposed
to wait for her outside.
Maybe she was afraid that
her mom would see her with you.
Is that why you went up?
I waited but she didn't come out.
No... this goes here.
Dad, I need a new wheel for my bike.
Don't, don't.
And the money?
Didn't you say it's ready?
Come pick it up?
What's wrong with you, man?
Do I have to tell you I don't have
more than 20 dinars in my account?
If you are so in need,
why don't you take from Imad's savings?
He's still young, and when you have
money again you put it back.
So, why don't you
go back to the Gulf?
When my mother was dying
and I wanted to come visit.
My fucking employer wouldn't
give me my passport back.
So I went to the police
and reported.
They threw me in their jeep with criminals
and asked him to follow in his car!
I stayed there waiting for
that motherfucker for half a day.
And what was the response?
Sort it out yourself".
Well, all you can do is play
and try your luck again.
Luck? What luck?
I lost two years of work in one night.
Good thing I registered under
her name before I...
The apartment she didn't like because
it didn't have the garden she wanted!
By the way, does she still
rent it out fully furnished?
I still don't get it, Fouad.
You've got your family and a good job.
You're supposed to be doing well.
So why do you want to leave?
Man, it's been three months
with no salary.
And you say I'm doing well.
And the last time I asked
Jaber to pay me.
He acted like a beggar with no money.
What's the story with this operation?
Today, I felt this strong
pain come and go.
It turns out I have a twisted testicle.
So now I need surgery.
The doctor say it's a simple procedure.
It's going to take 15 minutes
and it's over.
But I have a bad feeling about it.
Man, the pain will go on its own.
The thing is, the doctor says
if I don't do it before Friday
it will get worse
and they might cut it off.
So what... if they cut it off,
you still have the other one.
Do you know which one is yours?
Which apartment?
Number 7.
Do YOU pay the bill?
I always pay-
Seems some bastard stole your plug.
I think I have one
at my place somewhere.
If you're looking for a meter plug,
there's an extra one...
Do you know which meter is yours?
Which apartment?
Number 7.
...did not reveal is identity for
Britain's "The Guardian" newspaper,
that Jordan was behind
the confusion on Al Jazeera television
channel during the 2010 World Cup
and the source said,
that these allegations
are false and unacceptable and that
the government is ready to cooperate with
any neutral expert team to check all facts
and the Jordanian government is confident
that such an examination will reveal
the invalidity of such allegations.
The source expressed the government's
refusal to the speculation
and opinions expressed by Al-Jazeera,
to the Guardian newspaper
about the reaction
of Jordan to the failure of negotiations
of buying the rights of broadcasting
locally for the world cup,
and in this regard the source pointed
out that Jordan had spoken officially with
Al-Jazeera on the purchase
of broadcasting rights four months
before the beginning of the World Cup.
However, Al-Jazeera began
actual negotiations
only days before the start of...
Yusef, it's Jaber.
I tried to call you but haven't
heard back yet.
There's a deal.
If you close it, you'll get 500 dinars
and not a penny more.
The client will be waiting
at the showroom at 8.
Don't be late.
Yes, Mom.
Studying-
I don't know.
I can't hear you.
Hush him up or go somewhere
else so I can hear.
Yes, much better.
I was alone, he wasn't home.
He went to see a friend.
Fouad, maybe.
No, I'm not going to say anything.
He should know by himself.
Don't say anything, OK?
Thank you for making coffee.
You still haven't finished the book?
I have but I'm just reviewing.
Where do they sell bike wheels?
...the Jordanian parliament
didn't agree to vote on the
investigation committee's decision
that accuses Prime Minister Marouf Bakhit
of corruption by licensing
the casino project in Jordan.
The parliament session witnessed
a verbal argument followed
by scuffles between members
of the parliament
after clearing the Prime Minister
from any accusation
that needs the approval
of two-thirds of the members.
Meanwhile, the parliament did
validate the charge of corruption
of the former minister of tourism.
We've got two brands for this model.
A Chinese one for 7 dinars,
and an Italian for 25 dinars.
Unfortunately, we're out
of the Chinese one.
Well, bring us the Italian. - Sure.
Imad, I'm leaving the country.
Dad, the school principle
wants to see you.
What did you do? - Nothing.
So what does he want?
I don't know.
Tell him I'm busy.
He said that if he doesn't see you
he won't let me take the exam.
Take the first right and then
the second street on your left.
The electricity at my place got cut off.
Can I charge my phone here?
Don't look at your watch the client
postponed the appointment.
And you don't have a cell phone.
You should know that
we've showed her the car already.
But she's still not convinced.
Be careful, she's got a dirty mouth
especially when it comes to men.
Do you know her?
She might become my mother-in-law.
But don't mention it.
She doesn't know yet the showroom is ours.
Why?
I don't want her to get greedy.
So which car does she want to buy.
The Toyota Jeep.
And which car would you like her to buy?
- The Range Rover.
So how is this car?
It's your call ma'am.
But if you want to hear my honest opinion,
I recommend the Range Rover.
Why's that?
It's got more room,
it's true that it's two years older...
but I guarantee you that in three years
you wouldn't have to change a single part.
I want the Range.
And how's this car when
it comes to steep roads.
It's a fine.
But the options the Range Rover has
are better for all roads.
Whether you drive around town or outside,
off-road, hills, mountains.
Slow down ma'am.
Slowly. - Okay.
By the way, the Range Rover
has lights on the outside mirrors.
When a car gets too close
the lights turn red with an alarm tone.
So you drive in full control and vision.
Also ma'am, here you'd have buttons
to control almost everything in the car.
Stereo levels, the dvd player,
speed and cruise control.
Are you talking about this car
or the Range Rover?
To be clear with you ma'am,
that Range Rover was ordered specifically
for a client that couldn't
fully pay its price.
That's why it has all those
special additions
that you won't find in any other car.
Have you got any grandchildren ma'am.
I'm sorry. The reason I asked was
to tell you about the special feature
the Range Rover has that
no other car does.
You can separate the front
seat from the back seat.
With one click,
right from the steering over there.
A glass barrier would appear here.
You won't hear a single thing.
And from over here ma'am
there's a sound recorder
of whatever goes on in the back.
Be careful ma'am... give me the phone.
If you want to be with me
the way I want then fine...
If not, stay at home with
your father the doctor.
By the way ma'am, the mirror.
When are you going to understand
that all men are the same?
You just don't listen, do you?
Now he wants you to do things his way.
You've always been this stubborn.
You deserve it...
Now he wants you to do things his way
and if you want to stoop to
his level, it's your own fault.
By the way, ma'am, the Range Rover
has a very special advantage.
It's got this calm reaction,
you would hardly feel these
small jumps we're feeling right now.
Whose signature is this?
When you don't go to school,
where do you go?
I'm asking you.
You were absent for 17 days.
Where do you go?
Read.
What's that? I can't hear you.
She...
makes the things...
I'm sorry the cab broke down
and I couldn't give you a ride.
Don't worry about it.
I was having a bad day anyway.
Why, what happened?
My fiancé.
I've been trying for 3 months to tell him
that it's not working out
and he's not getting it.
Me too, I just got out
of a relationship that
has been suffocating me
for the past 5 years.
Now seriously, isn't the engagement
period the time
when you decide if someone
is right for you or not.
Of course.
I feel like there's something wrong.
This isn't the person that
I want to spend my life with.
Ever since we got engaged,
I'm not allowed to go outwith
my girlfriends without his permission.
I'm not allowed to talk to the neighbours
or even open the door if he isn't around.
I'm sick of it.
The best thing to do is to ignore him.
Eventually he'll get it.
I don't think so.
I've been trying that for
the last 3 months.
That's him knocking on the door.
Who?
My fiancé.
Who else have I been talking about?
What is he doing here?
I told him a hundred times
not to come without calling first.
Where is the extra electrical plug
you told me about?
No, this is not Youssef.
Who's this?
Man, how many times did I tell you
not to give my number out?
It's the accountant from the hospital.
Yes p
Yes, it's ready.
Sorry for being a bit late.
So when does the cashier close?
Don't worry, I'll be there before that.
What do you mean I'll lose my appointment?
I said I'll be there in a bit.
Wow, you were able to get
500 Dinars that quickly!
I sold a jeep for 120 thousand dinars.
After it was sitting there
getting old for 6 months.
I'm sure they'll take me back after this.
I feel like things are getting better.
I can feel it.
That's good.
How's Imad?
Imad doesn't know how to read.
So why don't you go see
Dalal and sort it out?
Didn't you say a year ago that you
wouldn't really care if you see her.
Or maybe you're afraid of getting weak
like you used to during college days.
Enough man! It's been 5 years.
After this surgery,
you should start a new life.
Don't forget that you're still free.
Unlike me. I've been married twice already
and not once did my heart skip a beat.
Where have you been all this time?
You don't want to buy a cell phone?
Congratulations on the garden.
It's really nice.
Are you here to congratulate
me on the garden?
No. I'm not here for that.
Imad is...
Yes, my love. No, he's still working
on it, but I told him.
He's playing.
Imad's father is here.
No, no. Don't worry I'm ready.
The minute you get home we'll leave.
OK, bye.
Imad wants a dog for
his birthday this year.
Do you want share the cost?
How much is it?
500 dinars.
What kind of a dog costs 500 dinars?
That's the price,
do you want to help or not?
I don't have the money.
Of course, you don't.
Dalal, don't talk to me like that.
Do you have the time to raise the boy?
Are you coming here
to place blame?
Your son has failed 6 subjects.
How many times have I said we should
put him in a private school...
I've told you a thousand times,
a stranger is not paying
for my son! Understood?
As you like, you are free to decide.
But if I ever hear that you took Imad
to a single one of your poker games...
it will be the last time you see him.
Dalal, have you forgotten
how I bought you the apartment?
And have you forgotten
how you lost everything?
Dalal, I didn't come here
to get upset and fight.
And I'm not here to blame anyone.
My only concern now is my son's future.
Are you okay? - It's nothing.
What's this?
This is the money I've been
saving for his university.
Youssef, what's wrong? Sit down.
Do you need a doctor? - No I don't
No need.
Tomorrow, I have a small surgery.
Why didn't you say anything?
Put him in a private school nearby.
With the money left,
hire a private teacher.
To teach him how to read
so he can go to high school.
Here is 200 dinars.
And these are the 300 dinars
of fines from last year.
Now we're even.
The youth of Egypt, are very precise
and the country depends
on them to make its future
and not accepting to be infiltrated
with those who seek to spread chaos
looting public
and private property, arson
and causing destruction
of the country.
My conviction is unshakable,
to continue
with the political, social
and economical reformation
for a better Egyptian society
free and democratic society,
embracing the best values.
I took the side of the
poor people in our country
convinced that the economy is the largest
and most dangerous to be left
to economists only
and was keen to set into action
the government's policies
of economic reform.
Hi, my son.. how are you?
No... it's not my number.
It doesn't matter now whose number it is.
Did you study?
What time is your exam?
I'm traveling, my son, as I told you.
I need you to take care of yourself.
And your mother, of course.
Don't make any trouble for her...
listen to her - every word she says.
Otherwise I'll be upset with you.