[knife chopping ingredients]
- [kitchen tools clattering]
- [tense music building]
[sous-chef] Hurry up.
[kitchen tools clattering]
[tense music continues]
- [sous-chef] One minute left!
- [all] Yes, sir!
[tense music continues]
- Ten seconds left!
- [all] Yes, sir!
- Five seconds!
[tense music continues]
[musical flourish]
- [children laughing]
- [quiet conversation]
[tense music building]
[tense music playing]
[musical flourish]
Winners are always...
the ones who hunger the most.
Enjoy.
Where's the cutlery, Chef?
Use your hands.
[clicks tongue]
[tense music building]
[music intensifies]
[musical flourish]
[wok clattering, sizzling]
- Picking up an order.
- Oh, okay.
I'm just preparing it for you now.
[customers chattering]
- Okay.
- It won't be long.
Thanks.
[woman] Pad See Ew, table three.
Rad Na, table four.
- Ready to order?
- Uh, two Rad Na, please.
Two Pad See Ew, ready for pickup.
- Ready! Two wonton.
- [woman] Table two.
- [man] Here's a pick-me-up.
- Hey!
- A taste of your favorite. Huh?
- Mm. Thanks.
Hey there, Pop!
- [woman] Your order is ready.
- It's grilled pork.
I got there early
but it was already packed.
Here you go.
Thanks.
- [man] I just picked it up. Won't be long.
- [cook] Bo, I need more noodles.
- Get more pork as well.
- [Bo] Okay.
[cook] Crispy pork's done.
- Hi, sir, how are you? The usual?
- [customer laughs] Yes, please.
[Bo] Okay, see you later. Thank you.
Who's that guy over there?
You've got quite the skill set.
You're too good
to be working in this place.
[wok clattering]
Come by if you're interested.
[chewing loudly]
Keep it down, Jang.
[clears throat] Give me a break.
Let me eat my food. I had a shitty day.
Again? What happened?
What else? My pitch got rejected.
[woman] Well, those old coots
will never understand our generation.
I'm quitting my job.
What?
My boss's friend pulled some strings
to get his child promoted.
Whoa. That's rash.
Did you think it through?
You have another job lined up?
- Mm.
- [Jang] Easy for you to say.
Soon as you graduated,
you had this job waiting for you.
We've got nothing.
Working our asses off for chump change!
[scoffs]
Yeah, but at least you have a choice,
whereas I...
I'm the eldest and I bear the cross.
[woman 2] Aoy, come on!
One of you has to carry on
the family business, you know that.
Yeah, but why me?
[Au] I'm glad it's you.
You cook better than Dad.
[Jang] Whoa! Way to suck up to her!
And what about you, Au?
Freelance online content creator, huh?
You have no idea how hard it is for us.
[Au] Of course I do.
I know how poor I am.
How much do you think I earn per gig?
Every day, I wake up
feeling so fucking poor.
[sighs] I used to think I'd graduate
and then, somehow,
I'd manage to change the world.
Yeah, right! Look at us now.
Menial work, no prospects.
For sure. It's not easy to succeed here.
Especially if you start out with no money.
You have to be
the child of someone rich to make it.
Normal people like us,
we've no right to be happy.
Oh!
Some weirdo came up to me today
and handed me this card.
Asked me to go and work for them.
Holy crap! Hunger! Chef Paul's kitchen.
- Let me see.
- Show me.
Chef Paul? Is he famous?
- Why, of course!
- So cool!
Chef Paul's
the high priest of fine dining!
Don't you know him? He's freaking famous!
Excuse me, sir, is this your car?
You have to move it.
Huh.
[car engine starting]
[car honks twice]
[woman 2] Wait.
I thought that was a no-parking zone.
[Jang] Yeah.
Some people get special treatment.
[woman 2] Gotta be some big shot.
It is what it is.
No parking for the rest of us.
[woman 2] What an asshole.
Let's finish up and get going
before it starts raining.
[sighs heavily]
[reporter] Recently,
trading has slowed down to a trickle
compared to what we've seen
earlier in the year...
WITTAYA, JUNIOR SOUS-CHEF
Joy, can I use your laptop?
[Joy] Sure.
[keys tapping]
FINALLY!!! I'VE WAITED A YEAR FOR THIS
# HUNGER #CHEFPAUL
THIS IS AN EDIBLE WORK OF ART
#HUNGER
FOOD THAT WILL TURN YOU
INTO SOMEONE SPECIAL
[dramatic music playing on video]
[Paul] Hunger is cuisine
designed for hungry people.
Because hunger will awaken
your primal instincts.
Hunger is what makes you special.
Are you satisfied
with being an ordinary person,
or do you want to be someone special?
[video stops]
[percussive music playing]
[Bo] Table four, one regular, two large.
[Aoy's dad] Two large Pad See Ew,
table two.
One large Pad See Ew, please.
[Joy] Two regular Rad Na to go!
[customer] Two regular Pad See Ew.
[Aoy's dad] Regular?
[percussive music continues]
[classical music playing]
[classical music swells]
[music ends]
Wait here a minute.
[door closes, beeps]
[sous-chef] Put that down!
I'm sorry!
[whispers] Shit!
[footsteps approaching]
Is she here for the tryout?
She is.
What?
- Hey. What do you think?
- Fine by me.
[door opens]
- Just the two?
- [sous-chef] Yes, Chef.
Good morning, Chef.
Name's Patt. I was sous-chef at...
Did I ask you?
Fried rice.
Well, a bit simple, no?
[suspenseful music playing]
[music intensifies]
A wok, huh?
[Patt hones knife]
[suspenseful music continues]
[suspenseful music climaxes]
[music ends]
You, go home.
Hey, Chef!
- You saying I failed?
- That's enough.
There's no way this hick-chick's
fried rice is better than mine.
- I'm a graduate from...
- I told you to get out of here.
I won't!
I told my mom I was gonna work for you.
I'm not leaving.
[Patt gasps]
Screw your mother.
[door opens, closes]
I repeat.
Those culinary school graduates...
Those classically-trained idiots
have no imagination.
They can't work the fire,
they're not stove hands.
Yes, Chef.
So you know
it's better to use leftover rice.
Do you know how to work the fire?
I... think so.
Do you or don't you?
I do.
Why do you want to work at Hunger?
[clicks tongue]
I want to be special.
[soft music playing]
[sniffs deeply]
The smell from your Pad See Ew joint
doesn't belong here.
Wash up and get changed.
[exhales]
[soft music continues]
[sniffs]
[kitchen tools clattering]
[sous-chef] Go to the market
once you're done,
and don't forget to check the potatoes.
We're a crew of seven... for the moment.
Including Chef Paul.
"For the moment"?
Seven for now.
That number can change at any time.
It's up to the Chef.
Come on.
Right here, that's Uncle Dang,
the sous-chef.
Chef Paul's second-in-command.
He's a real veteran. Been through a lot.
That is Tue,
in charge of the soup station.
If you hear him speak, you're lucky!
That's Keng.
He joined us just a few months ago.
He handles cold dishes.
He also makes sauces and desserts.
This is Bae.
The kitchen porter.
He can hardly speak the language,
so all he does is smile.
Hard worker.
And you are...
I'm Tone. Junior sous-chef,
just below Dang.
Um, what about me?
You? You're replacing
someone who got fired.
I'm guessing Paul wants you
to be the fry chef.
That's the same level as me...
more or less.
[objects clatter]
Tomorrow we have a
private birthday party.
Fifteen guests, total.
The average age is 40-plus.
The venue is a private residence.
The host is... General Premsak.
Guests are members of the upper crust.
Business and political.
The theme for the dinner
will be "Flesh and Blood."
Intense colors.
Everything juicy and succulent,
leaving the mouth stained and messy.
A5 BEEF, 16" GOLD PLATE
[Paul] Got it?
[all] Yes, Chef.
Now, your job
is to fry the Wagyu A5 beef
into tender pieces
that require no chewing.
[hesitantly] Yes, Chef.
Everything depends on perfect slicing
and your control of the fire.
Cook it just enough to keep the juice.
But do not overdo it.
Go on.
Too thick.
Still too thick.
Firm grip on the knife.
Keep the blade straight.
Don't tear it.
Again.
Don't saw it.
I told you not to saw it.
[yelling] Don't fucking saw it!
Again.
[tense music playing]
You're doing it again!
Have you any idea how much this costs?
Cook it.
Overcooked.
Again.
Overdone.
Go home if you're scared of fire.
Overdone. Again.
The meat's stuck to the wok!
Again. Come on!
[tense music continues]
There is too much oil!
[sizzling]
Don't you want to be special?
I hired you to handle the frying.
If you can't do that,
you don't belong here.
I've asked for one thing.
And I've made it perfectly clear
how I want the meat to be cooked.
Do it until you get it right.
If I don't see you when I get back,
then it's proof
that you belong
in your generic noodle joint.
If she can't manage,
we'll change the menu.
[all] Yes, Chef.
[tense music continues]
[tense music fades]
[intense music building]
[wok heating]
[music continues building]
[Aoy exclaims]
[inhales sharply]
[wok sizzling]
[music builds dramatically]
[music ends]
Whoa!
Oh! [laughing] Bro!
Looks like your girl
couldn't find her way home.
[groans]
[suspenseful music playing]
[switches off stove]
[Paul] Aren't you gonna get changed?
[all] Yes, Chef.
Here. Wipe off the oil.
[tender music playing]
Sir, could you squeeze in a little please?
That's perfect.
- Smile. One more, please.
- [camera clicks]
- [guests chattering]
- [soft music playing]
[man] How is he doing?
- Hi. Good evening. Good evening.
- Good evening, sir.
Hey, look.
Maya's a guest.
- You look lovely.
- Oh...
- She's dating Lieutenant Pom.
- [camera clicks]
- He'll be a military spokesperson soon.
[Aoy] That guy,
isn't he from the Chaiprakan family?
Why is he here?
It's a politician's birthday party.
Well, yes. Businessmen cozy up
with politicians for favors all the time.
That family, they've been busy
forging connections everywhere.
Getting invited here is a big deal.
Good evening, Chef.
Mr. Tos.
This area is reserved for me and my crew...
Come on now.
Don't give me the cold shoulder.
I'm only here so I can sample your menu,
not to pester you.
[Tone] That's Mr. Tos.
He's a prominent restaurateur.
He wanted to be our sponsor
but Chef said no.
[camera clicking]
Evening, General.
- Oh.
- How are you doing, sir?
Are you a general now?
No, not yet, sir.
I'm still just a lieutenant.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Let me know when you're a general.
- Yes, sir.
I'll give you my blessing. Oh, I see
you've brought your lady with you.
- Yes, sir.
- May I touch her hair?
[guests chuckling]
- Yes, sir.
- May you both be successful.
- [Pom] Thank you.
- Become a general soon.
- Thank you, sir.
- I wish you a happy birthday, sir.
- Thank you.
- You remember me?
Oh. You look familiar.
Minister of Finance, aren't you?
Yes, sir. I knew you'd remember.
You appointed me yourself.
Right. Now, share some
of that money with me.
[guests chuckling]
All right. Come on now.
[tense music playing]
[tense music building]
[tense music continues]
[switches off stove]
- Amazing.
- Mm.
[music ends]
[Paul] Begin.
[dramatic music playing]
[dramatic music continues]
[music ends]
[discordant music playing]
[discordant music intensifies]
[music ends]
- [guests praising Paul]
- [general] Ah! That was very delicious.
[man] It was perfect.
But please, don't tell anyone
how much food I had to eat tonight.
[guests laughing]
- Just say I had a few pieces.
- I didn't want it to end.
If you need anything,
you can call me anytime.
[general] Oh, it was very good.
We're quite lucky to be here.
Well done, sir.
[radio chattering]
[Aoy's dad] What would you like?
[woman] I'll have two regular Pad See Ew.
[Aoy's dad] Two regular Rad Na, table six.
[Bo] Table four, good to go.
[sizzling]
[Aoy's dad] Table five is still waiting.
You look chipper.
What are you doing?
Why don't you eat at home?
'Cause I miss you.
There's nothing more sad
than eating all alone.
What's that? Looks like pigswill.
Pigswill? It's meatballs!
What's your problem?
There's nothing weird about my soup.
It looks gross.
[laughs softly]
You get to cook for magnates once
and everything else looks gross to you.
- Do I have to say "Your Highness" now?
- [Aoy kicks table] Au!
The food before you,
what you're about to eat,
it should look good, not gross!
Hey!
Au...
[muffled] I'll tell you one thing,
I eat to live.
You see... fancy food might be good,
but I wouldn't know.
It's for rich people
who have money they can throw away.
For you and me, this does the trick.
- [phone buzzing]
- [Au] Cheap, tasty, fills you right up.
Hello, Tone!
What for?
[gentle music playing]
[Tone] What gives the food we cook
such rich and unique flavor
is the quality of the ingredients we use,
as well as their freshness.
Whether it's meat, fish, or spices,
their source give them a unique character.
[man] It's $40 a pound.
Oh, nice.
[man] Unfortunately, it's too small.
This one's big.
[gentle music continues]
This one's good.
I like this one...
That's good.
[man] Is she your girlfriend?
- Mm. No, no. Friend. Just a friend.
- [chuckling]
You're such a liar.
You guys seem very close.
I come here a lot.
I used to come with the Chef.
Now he trusts me to come here alone.
He used to come here?
Hmm.
Chef told me that, uh,
even the most luxurious dishes
rely on ingredients provided
or produced by poorer people.
He always pays them well,
but on one condition.
They should always provide him
with their very best.
That way...
all the villagers feel proud
of their products and earn good money.
[man] Here.
- Thank you.
- [woman chuckles]
[woman] Are you full already?
So, cooking for rich people
also benefits the poor?
Chef's all right.
[Tone] Here, Chef.
See if there are any fresher.
- [Tone] Yes, Chef.
- Chef, would you taste the sauce, please?
[Paul] Reduce it and add salt.
Yes, Chef.
[Dang] Chef.
[Paul] Find ingredients
that are more "golden."
Chef, is there anything for me to fry?
No.
What am I supposed to be doing then?
Scrub the pots and pans.
Mop the floor. Take out the trash.
Lots for you to do.
But I'm a junior sous-chef.
Says who?
Last job, I did all the frying.
Last time is last time.
This time you're a cook helper.
No, but I'm a junior sous-chef.
I should rea...
[Paul inhales sharply]
What makes you think you're so important?
You see Bae?
Try chopping like he does.
[knife slicing]
Faster.
[knife slicing faster]
Faster. Faster.
Faster!
- [grunts]
- [knife clatters]
[hisses in pain]
Besides frying...
there is nothing else you can do.
So what makes you think
you deserve the privilege?
[dance music playing]
[cheering]
[woman] More! I want more!
[whoops]
- Oh my God, this is so good.
- Ooh!
- You having fun? Yeah? Keep it up.
- Amazing.
- Hey y'all! Let's party!
- [guests cheering, whooping]
Yeah!
Hey! I said fuck off.
Hey, ladies! Want some cash? There you go!
[women giggling]
[growls playfully]
[dance music continues]
[speaks indistinctly]
Enjoy.
Mm!
It's delicious.
- Hey! This is great.
- [guests cheering]
[man] Whoo! Amazing, dude!
- [host] Wicked!
Wait a sec, I got you a present, bro.
- [all laughing]
- Hey!
I swear you're gonna love it, man!
[host] Let's go, Prang. Come on, come on!
[guests cheering]
- Ooh! That's what I'm talkin' 'bout!
- Hot!
- My man! He rocks!
- [host] Yeah!
Oh! Let me have some of that.
Oh, man!
That's my dream right there.
Look at those brats.
I mean, they're younger than us.
[Tone] That they are.
But can you make a fortune in crypto?
No.
But we're Chef Paul's crew.
They're all over him.
Practically worship him.
No, you're wrong. Look at them.
They don't even know
what's good and what's not.
They only hired Chef Paul
for bragging rights.
We're nobody to them.
We'll never be anything else.
Till the day we die.
As long as you don't make your own menu,
you're invisible.
Just keep that in mind.
[guests continue chattering and laughing]
Wow! Pork chop, sis!
Try it.
Hmm.
It's good.
[Aoy] Really?
You really think so?
[Joy] Mm. It's good.
There you go. You wanted to try it.
Cost almost six dollars.
That's expensive!
Oh, yeah.
The barista said the coffee beans
won some kind of award
and are single-sourced
from Kenya, I think.
Anyway, just try it.
- Mm.
- [Au] How is it?
Mm.
Pork chop and coffee.
I don't get the modern world.
It's got to be special.
So they can sell it at a higher price.
Is it expensive 'cause it's special?
Or special 'cause it's expensive?
Oh, wow.
Crybaby noodles?
- Yeah!
- Oh, yeah!
All right.
You made this?
- Mm.
- Let me try.
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Hey.
- Wait.
- What?
- Don't use your hands!
- Hey, I do like my ancestors.
Use a fork!
Ooh!
Tastes like the cheap pork
you find on the street.
- Oh, come on!
- It's true!
- This is Grade-A Kurobuta pork.
- The same.
- Cheap milk-marinated pork.
- Oh!
That's it! I'm right.
You just added pepper.
Hey! Greasy! Au!
Napkin.
Now, that is special.
It's got a killer name too!
- Thank you.
- Crybaby noodles!
Mm. Mm.
The best.
Aw, so good.
Pad See Ew for two.
[laughs] Come on in.
Wow, your place is great!
- Here. For when you're hungry.
- Oh, yeah. I've been craving some of that.
[uplifting music playing]
[Tone] Okay. Wanna try?
[Aoy] Hmm.
- Am I holding it right?
- Yes.
No. Do it like this.
Curl in the fingers of your left hand.
- Mm-hmm.
- Lift the right hand.
Hold it straight, nice and firm,
and press down.
That's the same cut Chef Paul uses.
Isn't it expensive?
[sizzling]
Keep the oil away from you.
Now, press the meat into the pan,
so it cooks evenly.
- This is seared.
- Hmm.
- This is sous-vide.
- Mm.
No condiments?
Why? Good as is.
Come on. Give it a good shake.
- I mean, shake it.
- What about the angle?
- Like this?
- That's good.
There you go, that's it.
Mm.
Well, is it good?
[uplifting music continues]
- Using a wok?
- Mm.
Textbook cooking is kinda boring.
- A pan's a pan.
- [Tone] Uh-huh.
- Whoa! It caught fire!
- Hey!
[uplifting music continues]
Hmm! All done.
What do you think, Chef?
See?
It gets charred when you use a wok. Also...
there is, uh,
there is a bit too much sauce.
Oh. Hmm.
And I think
you massaged the meat a little too much.
With a good cut of meat,
a gentle rub is all it takes.
Or else, the marinade takes over.
Okay. I'll try it again.
[Tone] I think...
Too hard?
- Gentler.
[Tone] Like this.
That's it.
[passionate string music playing]
[music ends]
Uncle Dang,
would you be so kind as to try this?
Here. Ah...
How is it?
The fat is undercooked.
- Huh?
- Here. Look.
The fat bits, there's still some white.
You have to be meticulous.
Make sure it's evenly cooked.
Is that clear?
- You still have a lot to learn.
- He's right. Still got a long way to go.
Not just in terms of flavor,
but swagger, also.
- Damn it. Keng!
- Hmm?
- [Aoy] Is that allowed?
- Come on!
Unreal!
Now that's swagger.
Why bother?
You look cool, hmm?
What's this? Keep it in!
What is this?
- It's...
- Leave it in your mouth!
[Keng] It's soup, sir.
[Paul] You have to keep checking the soup
to make sure it's properly done.
Now, check it. hmm?
[Keng grunts]
You think it's done?
[exhales]
[Paul] Is it good?
If this happens
when you're cooking for customers,
will you take responsibility?
Sorry, Chef.
There's a thief among you.
[tense music playing]
That's right.
Right here and now in this very kitchen.
There's a pound of dry-aged beef missing.
Also a pound of foie gras.
Anyone care to come forward?
A thief can never be a chef.
Chefs don't behave like that.
If no one will come forward,
I'll have to check
the CCTV camera footage.
But then...
the cops will have to be called in.
[tense music continues]
It was me.
I've been here for years.
Why can't I have nice things
like we make for other people?
You've been here for years.
Why don't you understand
that the food I make is reserved for
people who have the money to pay for it?
If you want it so much,
then use your money and hire me,
and I'll cook for you.
Consider your career over.
Get out.
[tense music continues]
[music fades]
For tomorrow's menu,
Aoy will be lead chef.
Since we're understaffed, Dang,
you will cover for Tue and Aoy.
Yes, Chef.
[somber music playing]
[man] Chef Paul.
Dad? When are we gonna go back home?
I want to see Caesar.
In a bit, sweetie.
Our house is getting fixed up.
Caesar's watching it for us.
When it's finished,
our house will be a lot bigger
and much prettier too.
Okay.
[music fades]
I'm going to color the house now.
I like it a lot.
I'm gonna give you a pink star.
- Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.
- Put in some more cheese.
- Here, Chef.
[sniffs]
Throw it away.
[ominous music playing]
[Tone] What's wrong, Chef?
Prepare to serve.
Come on!
[music fades]
L'enfant consommé soup.
[ominous music playing]
Enjoy.
[music fades]
What were you thinking?
You fucked up the soup. Didn't you notice?
I didn't, Chef.
There were shrimp in that damn soup.
Don't say you couldn't tell.
That's impossible, Chef.
We didn't have shrimp on the menu.
And the stock was prepared right here.
[menacing music playing]
Their daughter has a severe allergy.
You fucking knew!
One sip and she would've died.
I told you all!
Why did you do it?
You're the one who made the stock.
Hey! I'm talking to you!
Are you jealous?
These young kids are better than you now.
You're jealous because the new girl
can actually cook better than you. Huh?
You may be old but you're still a dumbass!
You blame everyone but yourself!
You and your bag of dirty tricks,
you want to ruin my career?
Huh? Am I right?
You want to ruin me?
Get this through your thick skull.
I will ruin you!
You'll never cook again!
You're done working in a kitchen.
Till the day you die... [gasps]
[groaning, gagging]
[knife clatters]
- [Paul groaning, gasping]
- [door opens]
- [gasping]
- [Tone] Chef!
Someone call an ambulance!
Hurry! Call an ambulance!
[Keng] Oh shit!
[gasps]
[music fades]
[monitors beeping]
[breathes deeply]
Chef Paul has no family?
[somber music playing]
[nurse] Flowers from the deputy, sir.
[Paul] Take them out!
Do they think I'm dead or something?
I don't want damn funeral flowers!
- Not eating.
- It's important you eat...
Who would eat this shit?
You need food if you want to get better.
This isn't food! I'm a chef.
Get this shit out of my face!
[door opens]
Noodles.
[scoffs] What's so good about them?
Crybaby noodles, it's my grandma's dish.
It's... When my dad was a child,
he used to cry an awful lot.
And he was a really fussy eater.
So to get him to stop crying
and start eating,
Grandma tried anything and everything,
and eventually came up with this.
It's a really tasty dish.
And made with love.
My dad always loved it.
The recipe got passed down.
It's a family favorite.
[sniffs]
Miso paste mixed with XO sauce.
You can tell with just one bite?
Hmm!
Made with love, huh?
Sentimental excuse
for when you're stuck living in poverty.
To me, love has nothing to do with food.
To be a chef, you need...
a stronger drive than love.
[sighs] So...
what drove you to become a chef?
[tense music playing]
[Paul] A jar of caviar.
My mother was a maid.
I watched how the rich live their lives.
And it made me wonder.
How come we never get to use
what they use?
Why didn't we ever get to eat
what they eat?
Especially those shiny black beads
in a jar.
I knew they were expensive.
[tense music continues]
Put that back!
Caviar is something
the poor can never afford.
[no audible dialogue]
[Paul] My mother had to
work her ass off for months
just to pay for that tiny jar of caviar.
After I got caught,
we had to clean up the mess.
The caviar was all over the floor.
[tense music continues]
You know what really surprised me?
It tasted like total shit!
[tense music intensifies]
What you eat
represents your social status.
It has nothing to do with love.
The poor eat
simply to satisfy their hunger.
But when you have more than enough to eat...
your hunger doesn't end.
You hunger for approval,
for something special,
for exclusive experiences.
That shitty caviar made me realize
that I wanted to be a chef.
I wanted to be the kind of chef
that the rich bow down to,
begging him to cook for them.
I would make them hungry for me.
[music ends]
SHUYOU
Bo? Why are we closing early?
Your father collapsed.
He's at the hospital.
[tense music playing]
[nurse] Everything's gonna be fine...
[overlapping conversation]
[woman] We have been waiting here
for 17 hours!
- Joy!
- Sis!
What's going on?
Why isn't he being treated?
[crying] Well, the nurse said
there are no beds available.
[nurse] Please, one at a time.
You have to wait until we call you.
Nurse! What are you doing?
Why is my father still lying over there?
[overlapping arguments]
- [nurse] Please, calm down.
- My dad is gonna die!
- He needs to be seen right away!
- [man] My father's been here for hours.
- You wait in line with everyone else.
- So is my father!
[silence]
What did the doctor say?
He's just had bypass surgery
but he's still not out of the woods yet.
They're keeping him under observation.
I don't know. Isn't there a way
we could get a better room?
[reporter 1] Three people were found dead
in what has been described
as a murder-suicide.
The incident, which took place
in the dining room of a townhouse,
claimed the life of one man, his wife,
and their four-year-old daughter.
All had been shot to death.
[reporter 2] Neighbors we have spoken to
say that the family had just moved in
and that they kept mostly to themselves.
Judging by their appearance,
they seemed wealthy.
- The area remains cordoned off.
- [uneasy music playing]
[reporter 1] Following
the crime scene investigation,
Police Lieutenant
General Rewat Rattanapan
revealed that the father
fatally shot his wife and daughter
before turning the gun on himself.
It is believed the father, Tawatchai,
a business owner
and luxury real estate developer,
owed a huge amount of money
to various suppliers and subcontractors.
[reporter 2] A truly horrific tragedy.
Our deepest condolences
to friends and relatives.
[uneasy music intensifies]
[music ends]
[pensive music playing]
At least we made them something nice
for their last meal.
That's what the father wanted for his kid.
We served them soup
made with ramen flavor packets.
I wonder sometimes...
the food Chef makes,
is it really all that important?
[pensive music playing]
[music fades]
[weapon clicking]
[dishes clattering]
Chai, Tone.
Yes, Chef.
[birds twittering]
- [gunshot reverberates]
- [Aoy gasps]
[ominous music playing]
[footsteps approaching]
- [hunter 1] It's a big one.
- [hunter 2] Yeah.
Come on. Picture.
[ominous music continues]
[winces]
[blood dripping]
Isn't this illegal?
We're just cooking it. We didn't kill it.
[Paul] Get off your high horse.
Food is food.
What makes you think this bird's life
is worth more than a chicken's?
If we only use pork and chicken,
we'd never find new tastes.
But, Chef,
it's not about the food,
it's about the law.
[Paul] If you can't handle this,
you can't be a chef.
[sighs]
Then I quit.
[pensive music playing]
Hurry up, Chai.
[door opens]
[pensive music continues]
TOKYO, THE MOST RECENT TRIP,
FEATURING 18 POPULAR DISTRICTS
I was impressed with how
you handled the wok at General Premsak's.
To be honest,
I've never seen anything like it before.
Right there,
I knew you were wasting your time
being Chef Paul's sous-chef.
But... don't you think this is too soon?
Aoy...
it's time for the next wave.
You're young and beautiful.
Not to mention
your incredible cooking skills.
I can make you the best
and most beautiful chef in the world.
I'm not saying it'll be easy.
It'll require total commitment.
However, you won't be doing this alone.
The reward for your efforts
will be well worth it.
[suspenseful music playing]
Here we are.
You like it?
Over here, we opened up the space
to accommodate a bigger kitchen.
Staff will have more room to maneuver.
Hey, sis,
the nurse handed me
Dad's medical bill last night.
Hmm.
I saw it.
Listen, I, uh...
I'll find a part-time job to help out.
You stay focused on your studies.
I'll take care of it.
[suspenseful music continues]
[Tone] Thanks for thinking of me,
but I'll pass.
But why, Tone? It's a great opportunity.
Yes. For you, it is.
But I wouldn't feel right
working under you.
Let me introduce your kitchen crew.
In the kitchen,
there is no room for democracy.
It's a dictatorship.
[music intensifies]
Here, Chef.
- Thicker.
- Yes, Chef.
How's this, Chef?
Try some other colors.
[music softens]
Prawn tastes good.
Everything is cooked just right.
But you're playing it too safe.
You're still in your comfort zone.
Nothing here
reflects your identity, who you are.
I'm not investing in you
for Chef Paul's food.
[suspenseful music building]
[sniffs]
No, not this one. It's too long.
Chef, the sauce.
You call this red?
The pork slices are too thick!
You're in Paul's crew?
Not anymore.
[man] Good for you.
Forget about him. Don't copy what he does.
Just stick to what you know
and what you do best.
[suspenseful music continues]
[music fades]
- [soft jazz playing]
- [quiet conversation]
[no audible dialogue]
[patrons laughing]
[music ends]
[Au] "The chic chef who plays with fire."
It's going viral.
The comments say,
"So hard to get a table!"
[high voice] "Have to book a month ahead!"
[Joy laughs]
Oh, well, she finally made it.
Aoy is famous now.
[chuckles] Hmm.
[door opens]
Come in, please, I...
[somber music playing]
[music fades]
[Tone] This place won't survive
till next month.
Following my dream
is harder than I thought.
I don't know how to run a business.
No.
It's the location of the restaurant.
You're too far from the main street.
Yeah, right.
I don't have a sponsor like you.
Oh.
This is the only area
where I can afford the rent.
Why do you say that?
Tone, it's not just
because I have a sponsor.
It's because I work really hard.
You mean if I get all these burns,
I'll succeed too?
Hey! Don't be a jerk.
What I've achieved,
you don't think I came by it honestly?
I don't deserve it?
Okay, so what?
You want me to congratulate you?
Congratulations, Aoy!
You are the best.
Tone!
You seem to forget,
you're the one who brought me into this.
Yeah.
And I don't regret the decision one bit.
The day I saw you,
I knew you were better than me.
I saw how much talent you had.
I was jealous.
[somber music playing]
You know what?
The reason why
you can't make your dream come true
is because you're not hungry enough.
That hurt.
You sounded just like Chef.
[inhales sharply]
[Tone] But maybe you're right.
I'm just not hungry enough.
[breathes deeply]
[somber music continues]
[door opens, closes]
[lively chatter]
[sighs]
Mr. Tos?
Do you remember Tone,
a sous-chef from Hunger?
You think you could help him out?
[Tos] Tone.
I remember him.
I'll be frank with you, Aoy.
He has absolutely no selling point.
Yes, but he's very skilled and works hard.
He is a brilliant cook.
I'm sure he is.
I believe you.
But there are a million like him
out there.
I don't want someone who cooks well.
I want someone with character.
Okay. I'll have a chat with him.
Thank you.
You're doing well.
But you can definitely do better.
Cheers!
By the way,
there's a big event next week.
It'll be your first
since we've opened our restaurant.
Madam Milky's birthday party.
- What, Madam Milky, the socialite?
- That's right.
Wants you and no one else.
A-listers on the guest list.
Top celebrities. Business people.
Even international foodies.
This restaurant's been open for months.
The hype isn't there yet.
We need something sensational.
This is your coming out.
Your chance to be discovered
by the whole country.
[man] See you tomorrow, Chef.
[line ringing]
[Au] Hello?
You're not in bed yet?
Won't be long. What's up?
Did you eat anything tonight?
Nah, I don't know what to eat.
You, Jang and the gang
should come to my restaurant.
I haven't seen you guys in ages.
It'll be my treat.
I miss you guys. Really.
I've already asked them.
It sounds like they were very busy lately.
Oh? Doing what?
They're so fussy.
Ah, don't blame them.
Look who's talking, huh?
Everything all right?
TEMPORARILY CLOSED
Come home, Aoy.
Dad's gonna be discharged
from the hospital soon.
[somber music playing]
You've already made it, haven't you?
What more do you have to prove?
I've only just started.
Take care of Dad for me, won't you?
[Au sighs]
Yeah, sure thing.
Aoy...
I miss you.
[laughs softly]
That's so incredibly corny.
Corny, my ass. I mean it.
The neighbors around here
said you've changed a lot.
I don't buy it.
You're still the same old Aoy to me.
[somber music continues]
[door opens]
Hang on. Sorry, we're closed...
[music fades]
You're not gonna say anything?
What's the point?
You're a famous chef now.
My comments... mean nothing.
Only your customers' do.
Still, I want to know
what you think of it.
My opinions aren't as important
as all those rich people Tos takes you to...
kiss the asses of, every month or so.
Tos is a damn good businessman.
So... you're special now. How is it?
Is it fun?
It's scary, isn't it?
[unsettling music playing]
From now on,
all you will ever think about
is, "When will I fall off the edge?"
"Am I still relevant?"
"Is this really for me?"
You'll cling to your success at all cost
without realizing what you've lost.
Like Tone.
You've lost him, haven't you?
But don't panic yet.
This is just the start.
There is so much more for you to lose.
That... is the price for being special.
[unsettling music continues]
It's a shame.
I couldn't teach you all I wanted to.
But that's okay.
I'll see you soon anyway
at the party for Madam Milky's birthday.
What are you talking about?
I'm saying
you're not the only chef she's hired.
[unsettling music building]
[tense music playing]
[music ends]
- [upbeat music playing]
- [guests laughing, whooping]
[guests cheering]
- [woman 1] Hi! Welcome. How are you doing?
- [woman 2] Hi!
Oh!
[man] You look great.
- Oh, my goodness, you look beautiful.
- [woman laughs]
[upbeat music continues]
Thank you. Enjoy yourself.
[chuckles]
Have fun, Elsa!
Hey, you! Is Chef Paul here?
Chef Paul's station is over there.
Oh!
Ah! You're with Mr. Tos, right?
What's your name?
Oh! Chef Paul's here.
Good evening, Chef.
Shall we take a picture together?
Of course.
[guests chattering]
Okay. A little closer, please.
Ready?
Just ignore him.
Focus on your job.
You are not going to lose.
It feels like
I'm being slaughtered in public.
Come on! Chin up!
I brought him here to cheer you on.
Mr. Tos,
is it true that Madam Milky
specifically asked for us?
Why?
[suspenseful music playing]
[music intensifies]
[no audible dialogue]
[music fades]
Triumph of the New Wave.
[lively conversation]
For you.
[man] This foam, is it edible?
- [crew] Everything is edible, sir.
- [camera clicks]
[woman] The fish is simply amazing.
Mm!
[loud clattering]
[clattering continues]
[tense music playing]
[tense music continues]
A Sacrificial Feast.
[music ends]
[calm music playing]
[guests murmuring]
[sizzling]
[calm music continues]
[music ends]
[soothing music playing]
Crybaby noodles.
A home recipe passed down from my grandma.
Each of us has this one dish
that makes us feel right at home.
As one gets older, you toil away,
and feel lonely.
Then you go home and eat this dish...
and you feel better.
And it makes you realize...
there's always someone who loves you.
And you love them also, just as much.
Enjoy.
Mm.
The noodles taste amazing.
The look is somewhat ordinary,
but it's delicious.
[trickling echoes]
[uneasy music playing]
How about some soup to counter the oil?
Ordinary people.
'Cause in the end, we are simply human.
Enjoy.
[uneasy music continues]
[man] That's great.
Let's go taste this.
[excited chatter]
[inhales deeply]
Wow.
[guests chatting indistinctly]
[uneasy music continues]
This is the final lesson I have for you.
No matter how good your food is,
how sophisticated it looks,
or how creative your menu is...
prejudice is something
you can never overcome.
These people know who I am.
They've already crowned me the winner.
Because they are hungry for me.
Don't you get it?
[music ends]
We need to bring you in for questioning.
[guests murmuring in shock]
[shocked murmuring continues]
What's all this about?
[phones chiming]
[woman] Did you see this?
[man] What's this?
[hunter] Chef, put this on a plate for me.
FAMOUS CHEF SERVES HORNBILL
TO CHIEF OF STAFF TUI IN NATIONAL PARK
- [guests exclaim]
- [man] That's Chef Paul. It is.
- [woman] What?
- [man 2] That's disgusting.
Delicious.
This is something else!
- [dramatic music playing]
- [murmuring continues]
[hunter] Put this on a plate for me.
Delicious! This is something else!
[dramatic music continues]
Thanks, all of you,
for releasing the clip.
I will get away with it anyway.
And then
even more rich people will line up
and take me out hunting with them.
[man] Oh, that's disgusting.
Because people like me...
we are totally above the law.
[woman] Take him away! Oh! That's it.
Are you absolutely sure
that's how you wanna play it?
[policeman] Come on.
- Well done, Chef.
- [policeman] Sir, come.
[Paul] Congratulations, Chef.
Well done, Chef!
[music fades]
I want to say
all your dishes were phenomenal.
I've always thought that
Chef Paul's cuisine was so pretentious.
[muffled] Yours is far more genuine.
[muffled] And now,
the next part of our show, "Spartacus"!
- [upbeat music playing]
- [guests cheering]
Oh! Spartacus! Let's go watch.
[somber music playing]
Aoy. I'm happy for you. You were amazing.
You have no idea how many strings
I had to pull to get you here tonight.
Chef Paul's era will soon be over
and yours will begin.
Imagine! The rising new chef
who overthrew Chef Paul!
Thanks to Tone's clip, no one will ever
look at Chef Paul the same way again.
That's what it's about, huh?
[Tos] Aoy, this world
isn't ruled by some principle.
The clip is the only thing
Tone has to offer
in exchange for my help,
just like you asked.
[somber music continues]
Hey, Aoy!
Don't be angry.
You didn't lose to Chef Paul.
Now all you have to do
is grow some real clout
and gain influence.
Let everyone know you're top dog.
First, we'll need
to work on your appearance.
It's a question of marketing.
I'll hire some experts for that.
Aoy!
Aren't you the one who told me...
that I wasn't hungry enough for success?
Isn't this what you were hungry for?
[somber music continues]
[indistinct chatter]
[music fades]
SHUYOU
[sobbing]
[emotional music playing]
It's all right.
You're home.
I missed you, sis.
[sniffles]
Well, suddenly Au wanted to sell noodles.
He was afraid we wouldn't have a chef.
What took you so long?
Hmm?
[sniffles]
Au, shut up, will you.
I'm gonna need your help, you know.
My help?
Mm.
Oh yeah, with what?
Your specialty, online content.
You got it.
[emotional music continues]
I'll be the chef of this restaurant.
[Joy] What about the other restaurant?
This is my restaurant.
This is where I'll set up my menu.
We'll restart our own thing here.
You guys hungry?
- Oh, yeah!
- Oh, yeah.
[upbeat music playing]
[foreboding music playing]
[foreboding music continues]
[tense music playing]
[uptempo music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[music fades]