Where are the boys?
Come here, you!
You whore! Come with me!
Don't touch my brother!
- Let him go!
- Where's your mother?
Let them go!
They're just kids!
Let them go.
Let's fucking castrate him now,
it's no fun when they're dead.
Damn it! Let's just finish this!
You can kill every priest
and landlord in Spain,
but you'll never win!
You're scum!
Now bring out his wife and kids.
No!
You can't kill two innocent boys.
I'm not even his wife.
Josico.
Josico, tell him.
I'm Cagorcio's daughter.
We were never married.
These poor boys
won't even inherit his name!
Is that true?
Yes, she was his mistress.
But he wouldn't marry a maid.
So the boys were born bastards.
Typical bloody toff.
Don't touch me.
- Don't fucking touch me!
- Please!
We'll let them go.
Should we torch the castle?
No, no.
It'll make a nice HQ.
I'm sure our maid here
will keep it tidy, right?
Right?
Now throw this sack of shit
to the vultures!
UNCERTAIN GLORY
Long live the Republic!
ARAGON FRONT
SPANISH CIVIL WAR, JUNE 1937
I'm Lieutenant Sales.
- Forgive me, lieutenant.
- At ease.
I'm to report to Captain Picó.
He's been expecting you.
He's at the river.
Suau, go with the Lieutenant.
We have two great enemies:
lice and pornography.
Plagues of war,
as Napoleon called them.
Lice and pornography!
We will only defeat our enemies
if we scrub ourselves clean,
both physically and morally.
OK, hand it out.
- Yes, sir!
- Make good use of this soap.
And make it last.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir!
Now get undressed.
Fall out!
You too, lieutenant.
Don't be shy.
Don't be ashamed
of your shameful parts!
We've all got one.
I want the cleanest regiment
in the Republican army.
Then, and only then,
will we dirty our hands
with the blood of those fascists.
Hygiene is the first step to glory!
This whole battalion is disgusting.
No hygiene or culture.
As long as they will fight
for their ideals...
Nobody here has ideals.
Or principles... Hey!
We need them, if we want to win.
This front has been dead for months.
Franco is concentrating on Madrid,
and we're here,
like cast-off old whores.
We have to do something.
You want to kill fascists.
I don't want to kill anyone.
But we need to defend
the rights of the Republic.
I hear there's an officer here
called Soleràs.
- Juli Soleràs?
- Juli, yes.
What about him?
We're mates.
We studied together.
That surprises me.
A cultured man like yourself...
What?
Juli is educated and clever...
He has no morals or principles.
Take the last battle we had.
He took out 20 fascists
with a machine gun,
then he just buggered off
and left,
in the middle of the battle.
Don't laugh.
We should've shot him for it.
This is it.
You'll be all right here.
Olegaria!
Yes, Captain.
You'll eat well in this house.
Look, some tasty haggis.
I'll show you around.
My nephew.
Handsome.
Joined up at 16.
I don't know which regiment,
he's on the other side.
This way, Master Lluís.
You'll have the boy's room.
The war caught him
on the other side.
That's how it is here.
You enlist or you get shot.
At least it wasn't the anarchists.
They killed all the friars
from the monastery.
Master Lluís,
don't take this badly,
but I don't care
who wins the war.
I just want it to end.
DEAR TRINI
In my village,
we have ploughs for this.
But they don't give you soap.
Why do they need a trench anyway?
To bury us in when we're killed.
Saves time.
Listen up!
That trench is to protect us
from the enemy.
From here,
we can spot any movement.
It protects us
from bullets and bombs.
Some of us might die in this trench,
but we will beat them from here.
Got it?
Yes, sir!
We bring our dying animals here.
While they can still walk.
Then we throw them down.
The vultures do the rest.
Some people end up here too.
My husband is down there.
- You're new here.
- Yes.
I'm training the soldiers.
Really?
What does that involve?
Teaching them to kill.
I thought that came naturally.
I almost killed my mother
when I was born.
That little one there
almost killed me.
I'm glad he didn't.
How come you speak Catalan?
My husband was from Barcelona.
I lived there for years.
- Are you from Barcelona?
- Yes.
And when you're not
giving killing lessons?
I studied law.
I wanted to be a lawyer.
I see you're from a good family.
This desert is bigger than it looks.
In those boots,
you won't even reach the enemy.
- What?
- Don't you ever knock?
Too risky.
People wouldn't let me in.
Let's not get carried away.
You have a great view from here.
How do you always get what I want?
By being friendly and polite.
You still have it?
This?
I'll take it to my grave.
- Anything interesting up there?
- More than here.
I bet. This place is dead.
The Fascists
could be in Barcelona by now,
but they use the ARAGON front
to make the war drag on.
The longer it takes,
the greater the triumph.
And we get to die of boredom.
But smelling of soap!
Not you!
You stink like a pig.
Follow my scent, then shoot me.
Sounds good.
Let's celebrate this reunion
with some fascist brandy.
- Are you crazy?
- I know where to get some.
You achieved glory
by killing a load of fascists,
then just walked away.
I left when it was over.
Glory only lasts a second.
I experienced it and then I split.
I must admit,
it felt like an eternity.
Now I'm counting chickpeas.
Apparently, someone
who leaves their post like that
can't be trusted.
Am I a bad example to the men?
Yes.
Juli?
Watch your back!
Always watch your back.
You can't trust your mates.
Dinner's ready!
Look.
Look, a piano.
Juli!
Juli, get down.
It's somebody's house!
You don't abandon a house
and expect to find it the same.
- Juli, you're an officer.
- Yes.
You shouldn't be stealing,
or counting chickpeas.
My subordinate does that.
You know I'm no good at numbers.
Et Voilà.
So what are you good at?
Escapism.
I could do it for a living
when I grow up.
But you're good at it too.
What do you mean?
Ask Trini.
You don't even open her letters.
Spying on your best friend now?
Don't you care about anything?
The man of great principles
is wrong again.
You know what I care about?
The stars.
And one in particular.
It's getting fainter every day,
and is about to go out.
There are millions of stars.
Be careful, Lluís.
Trini is like
these abandoned houses.
A stranger
could start poking around.
Don't talk to me about Trini.
Juli! Come!
- What is it?
- There are some fascists over there.
- See?
- Yes. So what? That's their side.
What do you mean?
Abandoned villages are the store
where both sides go shopping.
If nobody crosses the line, it's fine.
Put your gun away.
- Reporting for duty, Captain.
- At ease.
I'm making a contraption
to scare away the flies.
This says
I'm to requisition a horse.
This is a large area,
and we're short of cavalry.
You'll need to get closer
to the other side.
So where can I find one?
The locals only have donkeys.
You can use the Carlán's mare.
His widow has kindly offered
to let you ride her.
Me?
You made a good impression.
Shut up!
Is Mrs Olivella home?
Leave us, Fermín.
And put the axe away,
we're not at war here.
Are we?
No.
I don't have servants.
Just him, and a maid
who is out with the boys.
Mrs Olivella.
Forgive my boldness.
The Captain sent me
about the horse.
- The horse...
- My late husband's horse.
She is yours to use.
But you won't get far
with those boots. Follow me.
You be rough
and gentle at the same time.
My husband did it every night.
He loved Bellota
more than anything.
Only he could ride her.
I'm sorry to deprive you of her.
We're at war.
We must help however we can.
We can't hang on
to what we have.
We could lose everything
in an instant.
And since she's had
nobody to ride her,
she's been very sad.
She's getting old,
she thinks nobody loves her.
Get on.
Easy.
Good, Bellota.
I think she likes you.
You must have work to do.
Yes, inspecting the troops.
Don't forget to teach them
staying alive.
It's harder than killing,
although sometimes,
the two go together.
What a fine companion, Master Lluís.
- Where can I put her?
- Under shelter.
They say it's going to rain,
and this place floods easily.
Look at the horse.
What are they whispering?
Mind your own business!
That's the Carlana's horse, isn't it?
Yes. The Lady of the Manor.
What's so funny?
The Carlana is anything but a lady.
What do you mean?
If only you knew.
Her own father, Cagorcio,
called her "the dirty pig" because
she would bathe
naked in a trough,
and it shocked people here.
She seemed a very nice lady.
If you say so, but the Carlana
is not a lady,
she's not even the Carlán's widow.
He just gave her two bastard sons.
Good morning.
I'm with the Republicans here,
but my wife is sick in Barcelona.
If you were going that way...
I can drop you at Plaza Palau,
where I'm going.
Don't ask me to go any further.
No, no.
In the back with the sheep.
Fine.
I like them more than people.
BARCELONA
Hurry up.
Here.
At your service.
Comrade!
Eat your onion.
Trini!
Juli!
Always playing!
You smell great.
You stink of sheep.
No, it's dung.
The latest perfume from Paris.
How is Lluís?
Fine.
Getting on with the new regiment.
- He hasn't written for months.
- That place is a mess.
But don't worry,
the front itself is quiet.
Not like here then.
People don't realise
how hellish life is in Barcelona.
Ramonet!
- Uncle Juli!
- Hello!
- What did you bring me?
- Ramonet!
- You'll see.
- Always want more.
He's like me.
- Look!
- Uncle Juli brought you a doll.
Dolls are for girls.
Not a doll, a soldier,
like your daddy and me.
We'll make him a rifle
and a uniform. Here.
Put these greens on to boil.
- And the potatoes?
- No, there aren't any.
I have something for you too.
Is that a Christmas tree?
I keep them.
They're like treasure.
If it wasn't for you...
I'd like to do more.
You do plenty.
Did you know we got baptized?
No, that is a miracle.
Trini, the atheist anarchist
gets baptized.
- I daren't tell Lluís.
- He'd kill you.
I know,
but it makes me feel less alone.
Hold out your hand.
It's beautiful.
Where did you find it?
In a church with no roof.
It's really dark.
I go there to look at the stars.
- Is it a meteorite?
- I don't know.
You're the geologist.
I'll study it.
Wherever it came from,
it's the best gift I've ever had.
Hurry up!
It's going to pour down any minute.
Fasten it down,
or it'll get washed away.
You rascal!
You've blinded me!
The little girl
saw her chance to escape.
When she reached the door,
she couldn't believe her eyes.
The stepmother was holding
a huge stick to beat her with.
Why doesn't my dad
go and bash the stepmother?
He can't.
He's away at the war.
Then I want to go too.
Really?
But then who will look after me?
I will, Mummy.
How are you?
Tired, Trini.
I want to leave this world,
or get married,
and read fairy tales.
- Why don't you then?
- No woman could love me.
You? You're made
to make some woman happy.
Then marry me.
- Don't be an animal.
- An animal? Me?
Yes, you! Animal!
I can talk to you like a brother.
Lluís is completely ignoring me.
I know you're trying
to get him to come back to me,
but I don't think
it'll ever be the same.
This country
has been poisoned forever.
Don't let the mud cover your eyes.
You have to see the stars.
Our ideals were so good,
so beautiful to live by,
really believing in something.
That's over, Trini.
One year, the spring won't return.
April, that month of uncertain glory,
is slipping through our fingers.
Uncertain or not, it's the only glory.
What comes after will be nausea.
Lieutenant!
Come inside!
Don't stand there in the rain.
Oh, there she is.
We'd have offered you shelter
in our mill,
but you saw what happened to it.
It's bad luck.
It's a catastrophe.
Our daughter-in-law
died in childbirth.
The war took away our sons.
And now, with no mill,
we're all going to starve.
If you keep crying like that,
you'll flood the shack as well.
Oh, dear Lord!
Don't worry,
I'll go and see the Carlana
and ask her to rent us her mill.
She'll slam the door in your face.
She lent me the Carlán's mare,
to help our cause.
Because you're a gentleman.
And you are her neighbours.
Ever since
she moved into that castle,
she hasn't spoken
to us in the village.
My wife's right.
I'm ashamed to ask you this,
but...
being as she seems to like you,
maybe you could ask her for us.
Well, she only lent me the horse.
She never let anyone else ride it.
All right.
I'll talk to her.
Bellota!
Where were you?
What are you doing?
Go on, sit down.
Leave your boots in the corner.
Let me help, I'm used to this.
Pull.
I'm glad to see Bellota came back.
I was worried.
Don't worry so much,
you'll get wrinkles.
Now pull!
You told me to pull.
Put these on.
They were my husband's.
So, what can I do for you?
You're not only here for the horse.
I wouldn't want
to abuse your kindness, but...
the miller and his wife
would like to rent...
- My mill?
- Yes.
How did you know?
I saw the river flood theirs.
I see everything from up here.
They've been left with nothing...
They can come and discuss terms
when they like.
Thank you.
I'll tell them.
Sit down, please.
Don't be shy.
You like helping people, don't you?
Yes, when I can.
Could you help me?
You?
You said you were a lawyer.
I studied to become a lawyer.
I need help with a legal matter.
I'll help, if I can.
Tell me more.
I'm sure you've heard by now
that I was the Carlán's maid,
and he never married me.
Yes, you've heard.
What people don't know
is that my husband,
suspecting the anarchists
would kill him,
married me
so our children would be his heirs.
We did it at the monastery.
But the anarchists
destroyed everything,
leaving no witnesses
of the marriage alive.
Now nobody believes me.
But you must have
a marriage certificate.
No.
Come and sit here.
Give me your foot.
The problem is
that without that certificate,
my husband's family
will claim this estate
when the war ends.
And my sons and I
will be homeless.
But that certificate must exist.
It's in the monastery.
But I wouldn't know
where to look for it.
And the place
makes my skin crawl.
Why don't you look for it?
MARRIAGES
Fuck Juli!
You always appear unexpectedly!
- Ditto.
- What are you doing here?
This is my favourite place.
Silent corpses,
the stench of betrayal...
It's grotesque and macabre.
As if it were my home.
Juli, I'm not in the mood
for an absurd speech.
All that riding
seems to have upset you.
What did you say?
Isn't that the Carlana's mare?
She loaned it to the regiment.
Stop being modest.
You got it.
I was left frustrated.
What?
She never let me ride her.
- What are you insinuating?
- Nothing, except...
I imagine you have
returned the favour.
Don't get caught in her web, Lluís.
Why should I listen to you?
I'm your best friend, remember?
Trust me, and look after
those who really need you.
It's an air raid!
Everybody out!
- Give me a loaf.
- Outside, Trini. Hurry.
You have a child to protect.
Outside!
Help me!
Hurry, come inside!
If it's impossible
to find that document,
why not make a new one?
What do you mean?
You know the law.
You could get a judge
to write something...
Are you asking me
to forge a document?
I'm asking you to help us.
I'm sorry.
I understand your situation,
but what you're asking
is against the law.
Don't tell me about the law.
It's never helped me.
That's why I'm asking you
to help me get justice.
Look,
I was born poor,
I know how that is.
I'm Cagorcio's daughter.
You must've heard.
I watched as they daubed shit on
this castle and called me a whore.
I can take all that,
but I won't see my two boys
pay for this senseless war.
If I could find a witness,
I could make them testify.
I told you, they're all dead.
Don't come back,
unless you can help.
Good morning.
Look who it is!
Welcome, Master Lluís.
Come and see.
Try one of the loaves,
they're still warm.
You lot keep working.
What did I tell you?
I told you she'd make us pay
for the favour.
Be quiet,
and let the lieutenant explain.
You just need to swear
that you witnessed the wedding.
I'm sure that if you do,
you'll be rewarded.
Do you think
she might lower the rent?
She might even give you the mill.
- Really?
- Yes.
What you're asking us to do...
Is it legal?
Is it legal to kill someone?
And yet it happens every day.
- Because we're at war.
- Exactly.
If they hadn't murdered the friars...
Hold on a minute.
What you're asking us to do...
Could we get into trouble for it?
The Carlana and I won't tell a soul.
Why are you doing all this?
Those boys could end up
on the streets.
- Where they belong.
- Shut up!
Don't you see he's right?
Children shouldn't have to pay
for their parents' sins.
That's right.
You're doing the right thing.
What the hell.
Sign here.
Put a cross.
You too, come on.
We'll all go to hell.
María, take the boys outside.
Is this what I think it is?
I'm eternally grateful.
I don't want gratitude.
What do you want?
You know.
I think the situation
has affected us all.
You can't be serious.
I've never been more serious.
You don't know me.
Nobody's ever really loved you.
But I'm ready to.
Don't you see?
I'm getting old,
and you're just starting to live.
I don't care.
But I do.
You won't let yourself be loved.
Why not?
Don't tell me you did all this
just to have me as a reward.
You're a good man.
I wish you well.
Perhaps one day, I'll be able
to help you or your son,
like you helped mine.
How do you know I have a son?
I know you have a son with a woman,
but you're not married.
I know you're a man of your word,
weak, innocent
and high-minded.
Although apparently
not as moral as I thought.
Now go back to the village
and forget this ever happened.
And marry that woman.
For the sake of your son.
I didn't marry, on principle.
But I recognised my son.
Look at me!
Not like that sod
who turned his back on you.
And thanks to you,
that sod is now my husband.
You should show me some respect.
Now I really am the Carlana.
Get out.
Welcome, everyone.
We thought we wouldn't
be able to celebrate this year,
but thanks to the generosity
of the Lady of the Manor,
we can honour our patron saint
the Virgin of Olivel.
The war has brought hunger,
fear and hate,
but it will never
destroy our faith
in the Holy Virgin of our village.
Who'd have thought it, eh, Picó?
I know, Doc, but now everyone
thinks they were married.
This shift in collective memory
is suspicious.
It might start an epidemic.
They're not stupid.
They know
when to drop their trousers.
I hope no one screws them.
Lluís said
right from the beginning
that the Carlana was a real lady.
What do you say now?
Right, Lluís?
Does our lieutenant
have inside information?
Gentlemen, excuse me.
Anyone would think
he had a broom up his arse.
She's pleased with
the favour you did her.
What favour?
You got her a certificate
that makes her a noble!
- What makes you think that?
- She asked me too.
I was tempted, I must admit.
She's very persuasive.
But if I wanted to buy sex,
I'd go to a whore.
I never imagined you, of all people,
caught in her web.
I thought you had strict morals.
- You can talk!
- Yes, I can.
While you were riding
horses and landed ladies,
I was taking food
to Trini and Ramonet.
You never miss a chance.
I didn't tell her.
I love her too much to hurt her.
That's so romantic.
- Write to her and invite her here.
- I don't take orders from you.
Invite her, or I will.
- What for?
- You know what for.
Picó's inviting
the wives for Christmas.
- We're not married.
- Then ask her to marry you, Lluís.
OK. But when they get here,
you have to disappear.
Open the front door.
We have a visitor.
Olivella?
Come in, Father.
It's good to see you.
Not for me.
The Carlán treated you
like a whore,
but you've managed
to live like a lady.
What do you want?
Your good news
has reached the front.
My girl,
give me two thousand
and I'll never say a word.
Sundown.
I'll bring it to the sheep hut.
You're making this easy, Carlana.
Would you prefer it complicated?
Fucking hell!
- I never...
- Now go.
Don't let the villagers see you.
Fermín, do we have petrol?
Yes, one of those large cans.
Take the cover off the car.
Bandido.
Still bad-tempered.
Just like your dead mother.
If you hadn't beaten her to death,
I might've known her.
We're not here to argue.
Give me the money.
You've got your castle now.
Yes, but I'm still
Cagorcio's daughter.
What are you saying?
Even though I own all this,
I'm still the daughter of a pig.
I won't let you shame me.
You're Cagorcio's girl!
You never had any shame, Father.
Or you wouldn't have
done those things.
You fucked his lordship
and bore him two bastards.
Remember this trough, Father?
This is where my girl washed
her cunt like a dirty whore.
Get off me!
Do it.
Look, there's Daddy!
Lluís.
I thought
I'd never hold you again.
I'm sorry I didn't write more.
But you wrote that last letter.
Look how much he's grown.
Well?
- Don't you like me anymore?
- Ramonet, give Daddy a kiss.
You're so big!
I've missed you so much.
He's asleep.
I'm surprised Juli hasn't come.
Nothing Juli does surprises me now.
We can see him tomorrow.
Forget about Juli.
Sorry.
Don't worry.
A year without a woman
is too long.
- Tell her how beautiful she is.
- She's beautiful.
So beautiful, right?
That's it, get up there.
Good.
Give her a stroke.
Now like a soldier.
Chest out.
And give a salute, like this.
Now you can gallop.
Sit down, dear.
I'll fetch your husband.
It's fine. I'll do it.
Good morning!
Mummy, look at me.
Come and try this.
Breakfast!
- Go and see.
- Run, like a solider!
A breakfast fit for a king.
There you go!
Why are you all dressed up?
There's a funeral
for the Carlana's father.
He's dead?
Yes.
A terrible accident.
At the front?
No!
He was on leave and his hut
burnt down with him inside.
Don't let your milk get cold.
- Hello.
- Good morning.
Mummy, look,
it's uncle Juli milk.
Put that back.
What are you doing here?
- Looking for Juli.
- Me too.
He's meant to be on duty.
This soldier
had to stand in for him.
He's not here.
Tell the captain.
- He already knows.
- Tell him again!
Does he often disappear like this?
No. You know Juli,
he gets restless.
But I told him we were coming.
Seems he doesn't care.
Lluís, did he steal
that food he brought us?
Of course.
He has no respect for anything.
If it wasn't for him...
Where do you think he is?
I don't care.
You don't care
if he's dead or alive?
No, I don't.
And neither should you.
Who's that?
The Carlana.
The Lady of the Manor.
Go inside the chapel.
- My condolences.
- Thank you.
It's nice to see you
with your family.
My wife and my son.
Hello. My name's Trini.
I'm Olivella.
And this is our son Ramonet.
What a beautiful boy.
You have lovely hair.
Thank you, ma'am.
I can't keep them waiting.
Nice to meet you.
Let's get this over with.
Such an elegant woman.
Don't you think, Lluís?
And such sadness in her eyes.
María, put my mourning clothes away
- and starch my coloured suits.
- Yes, ma'am.
And send in Fermín. Hurry.
Olivella.
Take this
to the mayor of Olivel.
It's a safe-conduct
for Christmas Eve.
How do I get to the other side?
Tell the soldiers
you have a message for the mayor.
They'll recognise my car.
Do you mind if I pray with you?
Of course not.
We can keep each other company.
All the women here feel
those daggers in their hearts.
Women here and women everywhere.
It's no kind of life.
Praying for your nephew?
Every day, I pray
for the Virgin to protect him.
Who are you praying for?
For someone I love very much.
Did he give you that stone?
It's not a stone, it's a jewel.
From Master Lluís?
Let's have a little drink.
We all pray to that virgin.
Patron saint of marital
and family strife.
Have a seat.
The real one
is in the Carlana's castle,
but she keeps it locked away.
People don't seem to like her.
She doesn't get on with anyone.
She was very polite
with my husband.
Because Master Lluís
looks after her horse.
The horse is hers?
Of course,
like everything around here.
Why did she give it to my husband?
I don't know.
You'll have to ask him.
At ease!
At ease.
And lose this queer scarf!
Honour your uniform.
Our blood will build
a new fatherland.
Yes, sir!
- You see all that snow?
- Yes.
Look.
Where are they going?
I don't know.
To Africa, because they're cold.
Is it cold?
So cold it burns.
Shut that
before we catch pneumonia.
Come on,
or Mum will tell us off.
Good lad!
Just like a soldier.
I need a poo.
Go on then.
You're a big boy now.
You suddenly seem much older.
I'm so happy
to have you both here.
- Guess what he wants for Christmas.
- What?
A horse, like yours.
We'll buy him three.
Yeah, right!
We can't even afford a toy one.
I know how to get one.
By the way, how did you get
such a nice horse?
Picó gave it to me.
The last one in the regiment.
You were lucky to get it.
Yes, very lucky.
- Mummy, I've finished.
- I'll go.
Merry Christmas.
Come in!
I propose a toast.
Here's to our wives,
who, thanks to the Captain,
are with us for this special night.
Yes. To our wives!
I don't know how we've survived
without them.
But don't think
the women here have forgotten us.
Cigars from the Lady of the Manor.
For the officers.
And this is especially for you.
I don't know what it is.
A sack of spuds.
What nice boots.
First the horse,
and now the boots.
She must think our lieutenant
has delicate feet.
And I have a gift for you.
Doctor! Is it a book?
The guy is
cuckolded by the third page!
"The Horns of Roland."
No long descriptions of scenery,
just women who are always ready.
Who did you get this from?
- Who do you think? Soleràs.
- That bastard?
He might be a bastard,
but he's still funny.
Yes, he is.
An officer deserting
in the middle of the night.
Do you think your friend is funny?
He's not my friend.
I'm glad you've finally realised.
He's a coward.
He should be court-martialled.
But I can't deny he was clever.
I remember the day that
English politician came up here
and started criticizing everything...
- What's the matter?
- I've got a sore throat.
Is something wrong?
I think the boy has a chill.
- You're not taking him home.
- No? Then you take him!
Sorry, I don't feel well.
What have you done now?
Go easy on her.
What's got into you?
They're all talking about Juli.
He could be dead!
That's enough!
He's alive.
And doing as he pleases.
- You've seen him?
- Yes.
- Where?
- On the other side.
Prisoner?
No.
In a Fascist uniform
and aiming at us, Trini.
That irresponsible liar
is now a traitor.
I don't believe you.
It's the truth about your friend.
Why should I believe you,
when you've lied to me?
- You know all about lying.
- What?
You've betrayed me.
It's the Carlana's horse.
You're her lover.
- What?
- The whole village knows!
It's so humiliating.
Don't touch me!
Never touch me again!
Trini.
I knew you couldn't love me
like I loved you,
but I never thought
you'd become a fraud and a cynic.
Nothing happened.
She rejected me.
So you couldn't even enjoy it?
That's not what I meant.
Please, let me fix this.
Let's get married
and forget all this.
You're asking me now?
Just to clear your conscience?
No, I want to start over.
Like a real family, Trini.
You're Ramonet's father,
and you always will be,
but don't expect us to be a family.
- Trini, I know...
- You don't know anything!
You know what hurts most?
How you've treated your friend.
The only person who really loved me,
the only one who wanted to know me
and who cared about what I needed.
Go and have fun
with that bunch of drunks.
Ramonet and I won't bother you.
I'm taking him
back to Barcelona tomorrow.
Dear Lord,
thank you for allowing us
to celebrate another Christmas
and for protecting us
from so much death.
And thank you
for allowing us friendships
and alliances
in the middle of this cruel war.
And we ask you to protect
these children, who are our future.
Amen.
I hope you like the dinner.
Fascist crockery
and a Republican menu.
Very appropriate, My Lady.
I'm glad you could be with us
on such a special night.
It's a sad time for me,
as a widow.
And trapped inside enemy territory.
We must stick together in hard times.
Right, Federico?
But of course.
Despite all we have suffered,
our strength
- will bring us victory.
- God willing, Mr Mayor.
He's on our side too.
And that's good enough for me.
I hope order is restored soon
so our villages can be reunited.
We can't divide that which
was united by God and nature.
I couldn't agree more.
When this awful war is over,
I'll do all I can
to share my wealth.
My lands are on both sides,
and although there's a river
in between,
there is no need
to turn our backs on each other.
Here's to a bright future, My Lady.
Juli!
I missed you so much.
Get on.
Get off.
What's this?
I don't understand.
Don't judge me.
Right now, I can't judge you.
But why?
I thought I was already dead,
but I wasn't brave enough to die.
I feel I failed you.
You've never failed me.
- An advantage of being fickle.
- You never were with me.
When I look at you,
I see myself reflected in your eyes.
The Trini I want to be,
not the one other people want.
What are you doing?
Come.
I want to show you the sky.
The stars teach us a lot.
It's beautiful.
You see those two masses?
Some stars shining
and dark shadows around them.
That's like thirst and water.
Right next to each other,
without ever becoming one.
If they did it would make
the most glorious planet.
Do you know
what it would be called?
No.
Planet Solerasus.
Waiting thousands of years
for its moment of glory,
and then dying.
In geology, a century
is like the blink of an eye.
But we have just one instant,
a single flash
of such uncertain glory.
I came to get you.
I can't.
I've nothing left.
You'd hate me
for what I can't give you,
like I hate Lluís now.
- Don't talk about Lluís.
- I can't.
He humiliated me.
He stopped respecting me,
but I can't stop loving him.
Lluís might be weak,
but he'll always take care
of you and Ramonet.
So what do I do now?
Remember this moment.
It's perfect.
The moon,
the stars,
and your smile.
Your smile.
I'll never take it off.
Juli.
I had it analyzed.
And?
It's like you.
From another planet.
Where were you?
I don't have to
explain myself to you.
Trini, not now.
Our son is sick.
What's wrong with him?
I don't know.
He's boiling. Call the doctor.
- He'll be drunk.
- Give him coffee!
Thank you for a wonderful dinner.
- Thank you for coming.
- Goodnight.
- Thank you.
- Thanks for coming. Goodnight.
Fermín, close the gates.
I figure you don't mind guests,
whichever side they come from.
I've always had foresight.
We can't leave
our destiny to chance.
I totally agree.
More rum?
Yes, thank you.
I didn't expect this warm welcome.
You caught me in a good mood.
That uniform suits you better.
It seems these colours
also suit you.
The sun always rises
in the same place.
And we must turn towards it
if we want to stay alive.
Just like sunflowers.
We've always got on.
That's what I thought.
Until I realised you were using me.
- Juli, we all use people.
- No, not all of us.
Anyway,
you didn't do what I asked,
- so we're even.
- You're wrong.
You owe me.
What do I owe you?
Some compensation.
For what?
For having destroyed the honour
of the most decent man I know,
and for condemning a woman
to the worst humiliation of all.
What are you talking about?
A false marriage certificate.
Is it money you want?
No, I don't want your money.
Then why are you here?
I want you to undress.
- You must be joking.
- Not at all.
I want to see
what a spider woman looks like.
You think I'm going to
undress for you?
We're on the same side now.
I could talk.
You know I'm good at it.
Or you could be shot.
Yes, maybe.
Nobody would believe
a deserter and a drunk.
I could spread the rumour
and sow the doubt.
We both know that
to destroy a woman's reputation,
it doesn't matter
if it's gossip or gospel truth.
- I'll destroy you first.
- Please try.
I'm prepared to take the risk.
I've nothing to lose.
But you can't really say the same.
So you want to humiliate me
to make up for
another woman's humiliation
and to restore
your friend's honour?
- You think this will make it better?
- Not for them.
But for me.
What do you want?
I told you.
I want to see
what I imagine is there.
The saggy tits
of a woman who seems young,
but whose flesh is old.
Cagorcio's daughter,
"the dirty pig".
That's what I want to see.
I'd rather die.
You won't do it.
Try me.
And the rest.
How old was I
when my father did this?
Four.
And this?
Seventeen.
I stopped counting
all the ones in between.
You're not the first to treat me
like I wasn't a person.
Now you know
what a spider woman looks like.
Does it make you feel better?
Open wide.
Stick your tongue out.
Say "aah"...
The boy will be fine.
It's an infection of the tonsils.
It can't be.
It causes a high fever.
He had them out last year.
- Are you sure?
- Of course I am. I'm his mother.
Then it's not good news.
What do you mean?
It must be diphtheria.
But children die from that.
Not normally. With an antiserum,
he'd recover in a few days.
But we don't have any
in our pharmacy.
Are you sure?
I might be drunk,
but I know what's in our pharmacy.
So what can we do?
The Saint Paul hospital
in Barcelona might have some.
I'll ask the Captain to let me go.
Listen.
Go now.
The boy only has a few days.
Ask for Dr. Vega.
Tell him I sent you.
Thank you.
I'm looking for Dr. Vega.
Paediatrics is the third floor.
Doctor Vega?
Yes, that's me.
Doctor Puig sent me,
from the front.
My son has diphtheria
and we have no antiserum.
Could you give me some?
I wish I could,
but we ran out a week ago.
Every day, I lose
half a dozen like this.
What about the other hospitals?
Unfortunately not.
The Fascists
aren't letting anything through.
I'm sorry.
Open your mouth.
That's it.
Swallow.
He can't even drink.
The fever isn't going down.
He's dying.
My boy is dying.
Trini, we've had a telegram
from Lluís.
There's no antiserum
in the Republican zone.
The Fascists have it all.
He says not to worry,
he'll find it somehow.
He won't find any.
Please, God, don't take my boy.
Don't take him from me.
Please, God.
Listen, Trini.
Why don't you ask the Carlana?
The Carlana?
Why?
Because she gets on well
with both sides.
And what could she do?
She knows all the landlords
on the other side.
Will you go?
I can't see that woman.
Of course you can.
And you will.
I'd like to see her ladyship.
Let her in, María.
Is something wrong?
I need to ask a favour.
It's for my son.
What's wrong with him?
He has diphtheria.
Without an antiserum,
he'll die in a few days.
I'm so sorry.
I know you don't want to talk
to me, but I want to help.
What can I do?
There's no antiserum
on this side,
but you know people
on the other side.
Does your husband
know you're here?
No, I came on my own.
Tell him to come and see me.
Wait here.
Switch off the lights.
Halt!
Please, don't shoot.
Call Soleràs, he's with you lot.
- Say his friend Lluís is here.
- Why should I?
Wait here.
What do you want?
- It's Ramonet.
- What about Ramonet?
He has diphtheria.
What?
He doesn't have long.
We don't have any antiserum.
- I thought maybe you...
- Me?
What can I do?
We have nothing either.
But I'll check
with the other regiments.
Don't worry, Lluís. I'll find it.
I hope so.
Meet me tomorrow night
at the old convent.
Thank you.
And Trini?
How is she?
You can imagine.
Thanks.
Trini.
- How is he?
- Lluís,
thank God you're back.
How did it go?
I'll find out tonight.
Is it certain?
No, Trini.
Then go to see the Carlana.
The Carlana? Why?
She'll get it, if you ask her.
Did you go to her?
Go, Lluís.
Don't waste more time.
María, take the boys to their room.
Have them wash their faces.
You stay, Fermín.
My wife told me to come.
Hello, Lluís.
Come close to the fire.
Have a seat.
I once told you I would
be prepared to help your son.
I stand by what I said.
I'll get you the antiserum,
on one condition.
What's that?
That you kill Soleràs.
What?
You heard me.
Why?
Because he's dangerous.
Don't ask me to do that.
Soleràs is like a brother to me.
Soleràs is just a soldier
for the other side.
- We're at war.
- Give me the bloody antiserum!
My son is dying!
That's the deal.
If you want to save your son,
you know what to do.
I've never killed anyone.
It's never too late.
Don't I get an answer?
I'm sorry, Lluís.
I couldn't get anything.
What will you do?
- I've taken steps to get some.
- What steps?
The Carlana will give it to me.
The Carlana?
In exchange for what?
She doesn't give anything
away for free.
Lluís.
The important thing
is that Ramonet will live.
- He has to live.
- And he will.
His life is worth more
than either of ours.
Much more.
Juli, I want you to know
that despite our differences,
I've always thought of you
as family.
All families have a black sheep.
No, it's OK.
Relax.
Stain it with my blood.
Go, Juli.
Go.
Don't feel guilty, Lluís.
You're doing me a favour.
It's what I've always wanted:
To die.
And this way, at least,
my death will achieve something.
Just promise you'll look after them,
and never leave them.
I promise.
I don't want to be buried
with the winners.
A war can only end well if it's lost.
Go on.
I'm ready.
Let's kill each other
like good brothers.
Where's the antiserum?
I just gave it to your wife.
I knew you'd do it.
He seems to be getting better.
When the Carlana came here,
it felt like
the world made no sense.
It's absurd that the same woman
who hurt us so much
could have saved our son's life.
The main thing is Ramonet is alive.
He is.
What about us, Lluís?
They're shooting.
Quickly, AGUSTÍN.
It's all right.
Get into bed.
Go on, AGUSTÍN.
Everything's all right.
Go to sleep.
They say that when the moon
shines in the sky,
the sun has gone away,
because it's very sleepy.
Slowly, slowly,
close your eyes,
because you, my little girl,
are the sun
that I love the most.
And the moon peeps through
into the bedroom
and tells you to go to sleep
and not to be afraid.
And in your sleep you play,
you play with the stars
and fill the sky with joy.
Sleep, my child.
Your mother tenderly
rocks and caress you.
rocks you
in the bedroom.
Don't be afraid.