The kebab guy said they're dealing
in the loo or the stairwell.
Ruedi and I'll come from the front,
you guys cover the back.
Hey, Carol, today's my lucky day!
Won three francs in the lotto, went to
the thrift store and what'd I find?
René Botteron from FC Zurich!
- Come on, let's do something fab.
- Yeah.
Let's go score some dope.
The good stuff.
Yeah, but they've got Dragan locked up
and the stuff on the street is shit...
Know something better?
Things okay? Long time, no see.
Carol, we got to go.
Wait. Who's got the
best dope these days?
Baby, I've gone straight.
I'm a mailman. See?
Forget it, he ain't got anything.
Let's go.
So you're not the king
of the street anymore?
The coolest Yugo?
I'm not a Yugo!
I'm Swiss-Albanian.
Forget him and let me take care of it.
Awesome.
Kind of a retard
but he's got hot connections.
The mailman there. Do we know him?
Why would I know any mailmen?
Want to get going?
Let's wait a bit.
Hey, look: "May and
Analannabelle"...
I get it: "Anal-Annabelle!
New and hot"
in Zurich. "She really is new."
Got to check her out.
By the way: What's up with Vera?
You back together, or is she still
doing it with that other guy?
Nice piece of tin they gave you.
You know who it belongs to?
Us, you know. The taxpayers!
- So where is it?
- Man,
I'm not a dealer. But a guy
I know will be here in a sec.
Give me the money
You think I'm dumb?
Man, I'm doing you a huge favor here
and you're getting all worked up.
Don't you get all worked up. You'll
get your money when the guy comes.
Easy, man.
That guy there!
The one with the hairdo.
Ain't that the Albanian, Berisha?
All Albanians are named Berisha.
But that's really him!
Go in! Come on, go inside...
Oh, forget it,
he never goes in.
Fucking shit!
Well then, let's just grab
another of his boys
and ship him back to Yugoland.
Hey, Beko! Still at the post office?
He's inside.
It's one of Berisha's guys!
Fuck the post office.
Can you do me a favor?
I promised the girl something.
We told you you should
get in with us, but you
listened to your mother. Now don't
you tell me the post office is shit.
Wait here.
There's four of them.
Two junkies, a mailman and a Yugo.
Cover the back and wait for us.
- Good day, City Police!
- Everyone stay calm.
Hands on the table!
- Piss off! Fucking cop! Let go!
- Hey! Let her go!
Damn it, we're not here for you!
Fuck you! I'm not going with you!
The cops!
Damn it!
Have you lost it?
Just standing around?
I said cover the back!
What was that shit?
Fucking bullshit! You bastard!
Damn!
What do we have here?
Him again! What do I know?
What do you know about the other guy?
Berisha? Is he the boss
of the one who just split?
What do you want?
All Albanians are named Berisha.
This guy!
Man, I'm Beko. I know them all.
- But not that one.
- Don't lie to me!
Why are you asking me then?
Ain't you the super cop?
Listen up, Beko:
It's a jungle out there.
The big fish eat up the small ones.
Unless you're a piranha.
And that you're not!
Man, what's this whole fish thing?
Reported for theft, assault... You're
one of Berisha's dealers. Just admit it.
Man, no way!
Everyone fucks up a little
when they're young.
But those times are over.
I went to school in Switzerland!
Am I supposed to lie
and say I'm not working
at the post office?
- You got in my way, man.
That's aiding and abetting. Got it?
That'll get you at
least one night in jail.
If I don't go to work tonight, my boss
won't just see me as the foreigner.
I'll be the lawbreaking foreigner.
Uh, Dani...
Could you give his mom a quick call
and check that out with his employer?
Liens, liens, liens...
How can a junkie like you
be stuck with so many liens?
Hey, it's not my fault.
You know, once I had a
real cool bicycle workshop,
with super exclusive bikes. And then
they just took it all away from me.
Fuck! But you know what?
- I'm going to get it back again.
- You always buy your dope from Beko?
Definitely not.
Carol and I only went in there
because... Galatassaray was playing.
Is she your girlfriend?
Yeah.
Man, I'm not a dealer.
But that junkie chick,
she's totally hot.
Don't you think? She's a bit doped up,
but act a little nice, and then...
Did you know Beko's keen on Carol?
Well... why not?
Beko's a happening guy,
always got a good supply...
But he just took the cash,
and then you guys showed up!
And who'd he get the dope from?
How should I know.
From the Albanian.
Why do you want to lock up Beko?
If he's with them, we need him out
there so we can shadow him.
With him alone, you don't stand
a chance with the prosecutor.
- Going cold turkey?
- You crazy?
Look, not a single one!
And how about the ecstasy tabs?
Him again.
That's personal consumption.
I want out of here!
Fuck you
We've got a problem with you.
Man, can't you read!
We have to send you back
to Oberkirch Reform School.
You've run
away three times.
Shit, man!
I'm getting thrown in the reformatory.
I'll hang myself in there!
But hanging out in dealer joints,
that's okay?
None of your business. Fuck you.
What put you in reform school?
Stole a piece of candy.
Should I scream again?
If it does you good...
From my end, you can go.
You crazy?
Oberkirch is bullshit.
Can't you just totally
delete my record?
Get lost!
Damn it!
And? You guys happy?
10 grams of heroin, no dealer,
a little Albanian in jail
and a bungled job. And you, Marco,
what a screw-up!
You're the one who was so gung-ho!
That kind of thing can happen.
No! It doesn't happen to me! Know why?
'Cause I take this shit seriously!
Calm down. The lake beat guy's coming.
Fuck the lake beat guy!
This place is nothing but crap!
Beat Schuppisser from the lake police.
"Asked to switch to narcotics."
"You can learn a lot from Strähl"
but remember:
I'm in charge here,
not him.
- Hello.
- Good luck!
Ruedi. Break a leg.
And here's our little Strähl!
Is that necessary?
I figured if he can survive you,
then he'll survive the job.
Goodbye then.
A guy's got a private life too,
you know.
And there's no dealing
after six either, right?
- Come on, give me a little too.
- Why don't you ask Fritz?
Please, give me a little bit.
I don't have any more.
Come on, let's go or they'll
lock us up.
Yeah, come on, René.
Fritz has got ecstasy at home.
This constant oppression
is killing me.
Really don't have any more?
Hey Anz...
Shit, Anz is totally out.
- Don't you want to share?
- Hey! You nuts?
We outsiders have got to stick
together.
Fucking wild!
A grenade.
A hand grenade.
Let me see.
Don't worry,
he's done that to me before too.
Let me see the grenade.
- No, leave it alone or it'll go off.
- Come on, let me see!
Hey, Flaky,
did you leave the lake
'cause you don't like fish?
No, I just want to be
where things are happening
and where I can help people.
With us narcs, ain't much happening.
We mainly deal with garbage.
I prefer fish. Piranhas.
They eat the garbage.
Come on, I'll show you.
What're you looking for? I'm all out.
And what's that?
- That's just personal consumption.
- Nope.
To consume that you have to tell me
who's Berisha's new man.
Hey, leave me alone,
I don't know.
It's way dangerous
with these Albanians.
But you locked up René today.
- Didn't you find his hand grenade?
- Grenade?
Don't fuck with me!
Dangerous having a grenade around!
Just imagine what could happen.
The idiot doesn't know anything.
Let's go.
Uh, but... don't we have
to do something
if there's a grenade
going 'round the scene?
Listen, Flaky.
Join the UN peacekeepers
if you want to hunt grenades.
We narcs have more
important stuff to do.
The guy there with the hairdo.
That's Berisha.
The pig...
Lives around here,
two kids, a big fat wife, a big fat
Mercedes and a big fat business.
And we only manage
to nab his errand boys
with a few grams.
Damn it!
So what do we do now?
Nothing!
No mobile, no telephone, no bank
account. He never touches the dope.
And we don't know where he
stashes his big deliveries.
Why don't we just collect the few grams we
get from his boys until it's a few kilos
and then throw it in his car
and arrest him?
Mr. Brunner?
Yes, sir, everything's okay.
Come on, let's do a Smarties oracle.
And then we'll go out
and do some ecstasy.
Okay, I'll shake up the Smarties, then
you take the first five without looking
and that's your future...
Such bullshit...
Take five without looking.
Awesome!
Three green. Green's for professional
success, and you just got three.
Purple is for wild times
and red for love...
Swallow them or it won't work.
- Now what?
- Are you stupid? You know...
Professional success.
Your dream's going to come true.
You'll pay back your debts and
reopen your bike workshop,
but this time much
cooler than before,
and everyone'll want the
> bike.
Wild times: That's obvious, 'cause
we're going out to do some ecstasy.
And love.
- Because it's all with me.
- You don't even believe that yourself.
But you swallowed them.
It's already happened!
You're the best thing
that ever happened to me.
What's up? You upset?
Did you have to tell Brunner
about this hand grenade?
You're starting to piss me off!
Heinz!
- Come on in!
- You think this is the right apartment?
I didn't hear you ring.
You got the money?
Let's just cuddle!
Fuck.
You're so boring, you and your heroin.
If we'd only left.
What's the matter? What'd I do wrong?
- Police! Stay calm!
- Man,
you again, fucking cop! Get lost!
- Where's this fucking hand grenade?
- Damn it, we don't have one.
Where is it?
- Come on, this is pissing me off.
- Go fuck your grenade!
Fucking bastard!
Are you crazy?
That's totally dangerous!
You fucking bastard!
Stop or I'll jump!
So what made that junkie
jump out the window?
How should I know?
Because junkies are a bit stupid?
Listen! Wehrli said you threw him
out of the window. And Schuppisser
saw him flying as well.
You can screw
Schuppisser for all I care
Whatever. Another complaint
against you is one too many.
You're suspended.
And if Wehrli sticks
by his statement,
that's the nail in
the coffin for your career.
You don't mean to say you believe
the junkie and not me?
Listen, Strähl... It doesn't
matter who I believe.
You've got to protect people and
not throw them out of the window or
let them jump out!
What's the matter with you anyway?
Dr. Arbenz didn't help any?
Dr. Arbenz is a shit for brains
doctor.
You'll never manage without me!
Never heard we help
each other out around here?
Did you just let your colleagues
at the lake drown too?
Leave him alone! It's not his fault.
You know how much
Strähl would have to pay me in damages
if we were in the States?
Then I'd already be
general importer for Cannondale...
- You insane? Damn!
- Hey, what's the problem?
- You stupid fucking junkie!
- Man! Let him go, fucking cop!
Yeah! Thanks to you,
I'm fully disabled!
Go now and retract
your false statement.
If you'll pay me damages.
You insane? You're coming with me!
Here's a totally whacked ex-drug cop
beating up an innocent victim.
And on top of that,
he's a pill addict!
Fucking junkie!
- Fuck you! You're not a real cop anyway!
- Yeah!
And I want damages!
Where are you going?
Where do you think? To work!
But you've got night shift.
And you've hardly slept!
Now I'm on day shift.
- Since when?
- Since today.
Did they say something
about the police?
Leave me alone! I didn't do anything
and my boss trusts me.
How could they manage without me?
My son...
I'm so proud of you, Beko
Let me go, Mama. Got to leave.
Be careful.
Don't overdo it with work!
What do you want from us, Beko?
"Did we tell you:
"Go work at the Swiss Post"?"
We didn't.
But you didn't listen to us.
You listened to your mother.
And now they've kicked you out.
You know Winkelried?
Who's that? A cop?
You fucking us over?
Calm down. He's dead.
Back in school, I learned
he really helped Switzerland.
In war, he threw himself
at the spears of the enemies.
You understand?
Switzerland is still around.
And he's a hero.
Am I not your Winkelried? Haven't I
earned a job with you guys?
Don't screw up, okay?
Hey! I'm Beko! I never screw up.
Sugar, coke.
- What do you want?
- What do I want?
It's still my apartment too.
I need the car
and the key's still here.
- You're not getting it.
- Goddamnit!
The car still belongs to both of us!
So Patrick doesn't have a car?
That's not fair!
How did I stand it with you for so long?
You and your fucking job!
Damn it!
Since I saw you the last time,
a lot's happened to you, eh?
Now you're already out?
No, I just lost them.
Mr. Strähl. You're not
the only police officer unable to
cope with his job.
This continual pressure, this misery...
Not everyone can handle it.
It's important to admit when
the job isn't right anymore.
You should think about that sometime.
Clean things up in your life!
Damn it, there's nothing to clean up!
Mr. Strähl, it's like this:
You're trembling,
you smell like alcohol...
- Looks like cold turkey.
- You prescribed this crap!
You know, it's impossible to
tell in advance if someone's
predisposed towards addiction, and
only a small percentage will ever...
You're just a shit for brains doctor!
Did you hear that? That was
the junkie in you talking.
Idiot!
Hey! You can't do that!
It's Strähl!
You look like shit.
Thanks
Want a bite?
Otherwise? Things okay?
What're you doing the whole day?
Taking a little break.
Thinking about my future.
You know, it makes me sick.
You can really piss a guy off,
but it was also a lot of
fun sometimes.
Check it out, you can see
right up her privates.
Beat wouldn't have found that amusing.
So?
You guys making progress?
You know the Yugo mailman we nabbed
in the kebab place...
Brunner's got him under surveillance
now. Just like you always said.
You know, Beat thinks it's a blast.
He likes doing that, you know...
But, um, this Berisha...
I'm telling you: Slippery as an eel.
Little Beat doesn't have a chance there.
Well, I got to get going.
Hey, if I can help you out or
anything, just give a ring, okay?
Hi there! Strähl from the City Police!
Just great.
That's the fifth time today I've heard
that.
Suddendly everyone's with
the police, fire department
or security service.
Can I see your badge?
Hey, Anz, over here!
Goal!
That's a foul!
I let that one
in on purpose. You know,
because of the grenade.
Shit, what do you want?
Make a statement. Now.
What do I get in exchange?
And what else?
Hey, Zurich-Basel there.
Definitely not 1.
Zurich forever, man.
You got to stay true
to your principles.
- Make an X by 2. Zurich never wins.
Hey, are you crazy?
Man. Okay.
Basel, that fucked up
chemical industry shit!
That makes 356.20.
Thanks very much.
Thank you. I've got a good feeling.
- And what do we do now?
- Now?
- Nothing.
- Fuck yourself up the ass.
You go straight to the police station
and retract your false statement!
There's a case of bribery going on
here!
That enough for a
false statement at the police station?
- So cool!
Listen, if I'm supposed to say I just
jumped out of the window, then you've
got to give me a lot more than this
here. A half-kilo. Minimum.
Yes, Herbert here.
I'm in the World Bar
and have got a runaway here.
Can you come pick her up?
Thanks.
Zurich City Police,
everything under control.
You're such a bastard!
Goddamn asshole!
Leave her alone. Or you can forget
the statement, just so you know.
Listen: Now you go to the station and
if I don't hear from you in three hours,
your sweetheart is headed to
Oberkirch. Got it? Here's my number.
- Hey, you can't do that!
- Let Carol go!
I can break her arm too.
Shit, you can't do that!
You know where you have to go, right?
You're an unbelievably
fucked up asshole!
This is kidnapping!
You're totally nuts, man!
You still there?
Hallo?
Not hoarse yet?
Stupid question.
That's not my biggest problem, eh?
Your biggest problem
is your boyfriend.
Someday I'll pay you back for this.
Yes? René? All done?
Yeah, it all went really well.
I've got a good feeling about it.
And who'd you give the statement to?
Right, same as last time: To Brunner!
He's not even there!
What, not there? How should
I know why he was there!
Just go and make a statement. Don't play
around with Carol and no bullshit stories.
Fuck!
You've got until nine.
Brunner always leaves work at six!
But I think René is on his way now.
Hey... Can't you untie me now?
Fritz, can I ask you something?
If you had to choose
between betraying your dream
or the best thing
that ever happened to you...
Well, in any case, betrayal is the most
fucked up shit. Gotta go take a piss.
- Fritz. What time is it?
- About seven.
You're a total sicko.
No normal person goes through this
crap just to become a cop again.
Shut up.
Are you all doped up?
Hands off that and shut up!
Pills are total shit. You get no
kicks but you're still addicted.
You've got super cold hands.
Just shut up.
If I've got to sit
around in your shitty car,
then at least I
can talk when I want.
If you don't shut up right now,
then I'm driving you to Oberkirch!
And then? Huh?
You can forget your fucking job!
René's making his statement!
I don't care where you are as
long as it's not with him.
Fuck you!
Damn it! Stop!
Let go or I'll swallow all your pills!
Cut out the shit!
Fuck you!
Stupid bitch. Damn it!
Shit. I overslept yesterday.
You're such an idiot.
You say you love me,
but heroin's the only thing you love.
What's wrong now?
Sore from playing soccer.
Was it bad?
Just leave me alone.
I'm really glad you're back.
But you know... actually
we're really damn lucky.
- Now Strähl's got to pay!
- Just shut up!
You're such a fucking asshole!
Hello?
You know what?
If you want to be a cop again,
bring me that half-kilo of heroin!
Otherwise, instead of saying
I jumped out the window myself,
I'll say you kidnapped Carol!
Strähl! Now that's a nice surprise!
Hey, Ruedi, you know
you said you'd help me out.
Want a bite?
Shoot!
Honeybunny, uh,
give us a second to talk.
We'll pick back up in a minute.
Listen, Strähl... there's no way I can
give you a half-kilo heroin. And what for?
But it's no big deal for you. You'll get it
back in 12 hours, and nobody'll notice.
Okay, but...
But you're a total wacko
who ought to be in therapy.
I mean, the drugs you had
stashed in your desk...
I took a look at the package inserts...
only real psychos eat that kind of stuff.
Listen, have you gone completely nuts?
Don't take it personally but why don't
you go fishing in your little Amazon
and spare me this shit.
Just quickly: Sorry.
I overreacted a little there and...
I think you're doing a good job.
It's not so tough.
I've been watching this Beko guy
for ages. He deals and deals,
but you never catch Berisha with the
dope. Being a narc is really pretty shitty.
Remember your joke about Berisha?
Putting the dope in his Mercedes?
That's a good one.
Let's do it.
I'll give you a call when
I know something.
So, where's your connection?
Hey, Carol, have you seen Beko?
We need something.
Hey, Carol, you won't believe it!
I fucked over that Strähl guy.
Spare me your crap.
What now? Who's got something?
You guys into pills?
Strähl, City Police.
I want to help your son
but he doesn't want to be helped!
Don't believe him.
Why does he need help from the police?
My son works at the post office!
We found this on him.
That's heroin.
And that's not from the post office.
It's not true!
Listen, Mrs. Mussafr.
We're planning a big hit
against the drug mafia.
Your son could be
of great help to us.
- Then he wouldn't have to go to prison?
- No.
If he shows us where he got this from,
he doesn't have anything to worry about.
They're going to kill me!
Will you be able
to protect my son?
I promise, Mrs. Mussafr.
Take the laundry with you if you have
to do it in the middle of the night,
or I'll call building management.
But they won't do anything.
You've got to do it all yourself.
Who does this basement belong to?
No idea. I couldn't give a shit.
Man, you trying to fuck with me.
Where's the rest?
Think they tell me anything?
That guy with Berisha brings it here?
Hoxha?
Yes.
Shit. I don't know
anything about this.
Listen: Just keep going like nothing
happened. Leave Berisha to me.
Just don't screw me, okay?
Hey, watch out.
That junk makes you fat!
I don't know. Only retards
break in at a cop's place.
Perhaps that's the
good thing about it.
Yeah, you know, no one expects it
and that's what makes it totally easy.
Are you guys wimps
or do you want to break in?
Strähl's nuts. He's got a piranha.
So where are these pills?
Man, that's what we've got to find.
Everybody take a room.
Let me do this.
Hey, I know how it works.
Yeah, but let's hurry.
Those are my keys. Leave me alone!
Boys, I've got it.
That's all?
Where's René?
Come here!
Hey, don't screw around.
We got to get going.
It doesn't matter anymore.
You off your rocker?
Goal.
- Yeah, thanks.
- There.
13 right.
120,000 francs!
- Goal!
It's all just like you said.
And now I'm going to stop doping.
And open up a bike workshop.
The two of us...
- Damn it, what's...
- Shit. Why didn't we get out of here!
Fucking mess! Dammit!
Don't worry. I'll tell him I don't
want anything from him anymore.
- Lowlife shitheads. Fuck!
- Strähl...
You guys insane? Where are my pills?
Something I wanted to tell you...
What's that?
Shit...
- Double bingo!
- But you wanted to...
- Down to the station.
- Let me go!
- Let him go!
- Damn it! That's enough!
Shit, I'll do it.
Shit, René, I don't
have a good feeling
- Why? It'll be fine.
- Just shut the fuck up and go!
Okay...
You probably don't want
to take that in?
Just don't screw up.
Next time you see me,
I'm going to be starting a new life.
That's for you,
sweetheart.
Sugar, coke...
What's up, boss?
You screwed up.
I didn't do anything!
Shut up! Just give us back
what you stole from us!
Somehow we always end up sitting
in the car waiting for René.
What's taking him so long?
You going to give him the dope
when he comes back?
Would you give it to him?
I'll go have a look.
Did a junkie come in here two hours
ago wanting to make a statement?
Ever seen a junkie
wanting to make a statement?
Why don't ya get lost
if you don't like it!
Where is he?
Shit, did they lock him up?
He's dead.
The idiot had to go to the loo first.
Don't call him an idiot.
Shit.
Damn.
He's such an asshole...
such a retard...
What's the matter with you?
Why are you never taking the phone?
Shit. He'd really wanted to
set up his bike workshop again.
And now that he came so close...
He won.
13 for 13.
Fucking hell!
Why wasn't he more careful?
He'd never have quit.
You've got no fucking clue, jerk-off!
Can I have some of your heroin?
Want some too?
You haven't got any more pills.
Not hungry?
Junkies never get hungry either.
Fuck, Vera.
What is it this time?
Stressed out?
Sorry, boys, I'd love to
offer you a beer,
but today's really inconvenient.
- You handling her okay?
Don't you want to introduce
your new babe?
You see, I'm busy. Beat it!
- Are we supposed to put up with that?
- Shit! Carol! Put it away!
Goddamn, Strähl!
What's going on here!
Now you're doing it
with this junkie babe?
Calm down, man!
Damn it, don't act so bloody stupid!
Don't leave me hanging here!
What do you want anyway?
You guys nuts?
Brunner said you'd been
acting weird lately.
And know what? He's right.
Know what?
Brunner can just suck my dick!
And what about the
dead junkie in the loo?
About the prescription
slips from Arbenz?
And what happened to this one?
Shit!
What was that?
The big fish eat the little ones,
unless you're a piranha.
This one's not even dangerous.
Did you get this from her?
Will you just shut up!
How can you stand it with her?
Does she scream in bed like that too?
I would have never thought one of us
would sink so low. Not even Strähl.
Listen. You and me, we don't
let our colleagues drown,
even if they are total loonies and
want to catch a disease between
the legs of a babe like that.
We'll just tell Brunner
the girl had the dope.
And there's no way this Arbenz shit's
going to land you in jail.
You can't do this. Strähl,
tell me you won't do this.
Fuck. Now I'm getting locked up.
Go! And don't let 'em catch you.
I'll take care of this!
- Damn! Son of a bitch!
- Fuck, Strähl!
Have you lost it? Goddamn...
Go ahead and run! Just wait
until Strähl puts the bite on you!
So did that make you feel better?
Do you have to always
screw up everything?
Strähl, damn it! Come on, pick up!
That's him! That's the officer!
Shit.
Strähl, help! They're
going to kill me!
And now? What're you gonna do?
Hey Beko, sorry,
can you just quickly...
Thanks, but sorry,
I'm really in a hurry.
Hello.
Can't do this one. It's much too much.
Can't pay that out.
You have to mail it in and
then they'll send you the money.
But I need the dough right now.
- Sorry, I can't pay out that much...
- But I need the dough right now!
Sorry.
Those are the rules.
I can't pay it out.
Damn!
Do you have a connection who can
trade a 120,000 lotto ticket
for 80,000?
Fast and in cash?
Come on!
Um... is an hour fast enough for you?
Fuck you
- You want to fuck us over?
- No!
- She ain't getting money from us!
- No! We'll take the ticket from her!
The ticket'll get you 120,000 francs.
And then we're even.
But if the girl fucks up,
then you're both in trouble!
I used to think you
were a good police officer.
But this here is like kindergarten.
And if you simply don't answer
the charges by Mrs. Mussafr
and the others, then...
then things look grim.
Admit it! You stole
heroin from Mr. Mussafr,
and there you really
picked on a weak one!
And now he's got
the Albanians after him!
And you don't remember
why you stole the prescription
slips from Dr. Arbenz either.
And then you didn't have anything to do
with the dead junkie in the bathroom.
Well, I really don't see any other possibility
than to call in the prosecutor's office.
Then what? What'll you tell them?
That I stole a half-kilo
heroin from Beko?
And where'd a small-time street dealer
get a half-kilo of heroin?
And anyway, you guys are
trailing Beko day and night.
You never noticed anything?
And you think the prosecutor's
going to believe you?
Or believe a mom of
someone with a record?
Do you still have it together or what?
Don't you have anything
better to do? Know what?
This is and always will be
a fucking lousy outfit, damn it!
Sorry,
Flaky Beat said Beko is
out with another Albanian.
And he said... I don't know,
it doesn't make sense... he said
they'd picked up something at a kiosk,
something with the lottery.
And your babe was with them too.
Shit. Know what?
Go ahead and do whatever
you want with your prosecutor.
- Hey, baby. Now show me the ticket.
- Now first you show me the 80,000.
The girl's here.
You idiot, what're you waiting for?
You're always screwing up. Kill
her off and bring me the money!
He's got the money.
You got something?
Sorry, Anz, not now.
Then what're you doing
with that guy there?
Hey, you guys crazy?
Come on, now we're doing business.
Get the ticket from her!
What's this? Where's the cash?
Give me the ticket and it'll be fine.
The money, damn it!
What is this shit?
Or we're going up in smoke.
Hey! Are you guys crazy?
Get the ticket from her!
Come on, do it!
Freeze!
What are you doing here? Get lost!
In a sec. But first let's do
that joke with Berisha's
Mercedes.
- Have you lost it, man?
You want to just fish around a little
or really catch one?
Soon you'll be rid of Berisha too.
Well, yeah, you said that before.
Give me an hour.
And you take a look in the trunk.
We could have easily kept
some dope for ourselves.
A little less would have still
kept the guy in jail long enough.
Too late now.
Do you know the Smarties oracle?
The first five you take
will tell you the future.
And what does that mean now?
Red's for love,
purple for wild times
and brown for shit.
Now you've got to eat them,
otherwise it won't work.
So cool.