Downloaded from
HQCINEMAS.COM
Official HQCINEMAS movies site:
- What am I supposed to do now?
- I'm sorry, Mrs. Cutler.
I know these are hard to see.
- 20 years of marriage.
20. Thrown away for what?
A cheap fling?
I have leave him now, I mean...
I have to leave him.
- Now, Mrs. Cutler, that's...
That's really not for us to say.
- Well, what do
your other clients do?
- Some people leave,
some people stay.
Everybody reacts
differently.
The main thing right now,
Mrs. Cutler,
is that you have
all the information,
which means you have
all the power.
- Power? Do I look like
I have power?
- Just because you're hurt
doesn't mean you're powerless.
You're armed with
everything you need
to make an informed decision.
So you hold all the cards.
- I just knew that he was
messing around behind my back.
I knew it. But now
that I know for sure...
I just feel so worthless.
- You are not worthless.
Hey, you were smart enough
to come in here
and ask a question you maybe
didn't want the answer to.
But you did it.
And that takes guts.
And strength.
And yes, being betrayed
by somebody you love,
somebody you thought you knew;
that hurts.
But that is not on you.
That is on him.
It is always on them.
Men cheat;
they break promises,
but now, you get to decide,
is this a man that you can learn
to trust again?
Or do you move on,
knowing what you know now?
You stand in that power
and you make that decision
for yourself.
- You're right.
I've done nothing wrong.
- No, you didn't.
Never take the fall for
someone else's wrongdoing.
- I have a lot to think about.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- You've been helpful.
- 10 bucks says she stays.
- Nah.
She's gonna bleed him dry.
- Lucy Thompson?
- Who's asking?
- My name is Clive Cassel.
You came highly recommended.
- Yes, Mr. Cassel. I believe
I spoke to your assistant.
- That's right.
- What can I do for you,
Mr. Cassel?
- Please, call me Clive.
- What can I do for you, Clive?
- I think my wife
is having an affair
and I would need
your help proving it.
It's not always
the man who cheats...
- Of course.
Uh, please, have a seat.
August, aren't you
going to join us?
- No, I've got an interview
to get to.
You can bring me up
to speed later.
- Sure.
Can I get you a coffee?
- Please.
Adriana was
my interior designer.
We met shortly after
I sold my first start-up.
We've been together
just under eight years now.
The first six, happy.
The rest...
Well, I'm here, aren't I?
It was the closest I'd ever come
to love at first sight.
And now, she's got me wondering
whether she ever
loved me at all.
- A lot of people wonder that
when they suspect
their spouse is cheating.
- Right.
- So, what initially made you
question her fidelity?
- Oh, the usual stuff, I guess.
Gradually, throughout
the years,
I could sense her pulling away.
I know I can take
some of the blame for that,
I travel a lot for work
and she's always busy too.
It's hard to find time
to be together.
But when we do make
the time, it's... different.
- Different how?
- Well, for starters,
we stopped having sex.
And she became difficult
to get a hold of,
screening my calls,
she started having
private conversations
behind closed doors.
She never used to do that.
She's an interior designer.
What could possibly be
so confidential?
Do you need me to continue?
- No. From the sounds of it,
you're completely justified
in feeling the way you do.
- Oh, thanks.
It's nice to know
I'm not losing my mind.
- You're not. In my experience,
it's always best
to trust your instincts.
- Well, it'll be
a relief to finally get
to the bottom of this.
Whatever the truth is.
- I understand.
- So, how does this work?
Do I have to sign something?
- Uh, do you have
any questions for me?
Am I the first investigator
you've met with?
- No. I met with
Rudy Davis last week.
- Oh, Rudy. How'd that go?
- He's a hack.
- Wasn't gonna say.
- I've done my research.
I've explored a few
other options and...
I want you.
- What makes you so sure?
- Let's just say
I'm trusting my instincts.
- I'll have August
send over a contract
and we'll go from there.
- Wonderful. Thank you.
- Hey, Cami.
- Happy almost birthday.
- Do you have to remind me?
- What would you do without me?
- Not have a birthday party,
for starters.
- Oh, don't be such
a party pooper!
This is your 35th! We have
to do something special.
I've kind of invited someone
I want you to meet.
- You know I don't do setups.
- Look, sweetie, I know you
don't trust anyone.
I get it. You're exposed
to a lot of bad guys
doing what you do every day.
But, not everybody cheats.
I mean, just look
at Charles and I.
If you just let someone in,
just for once,
maybe you can be
as happy as we are.
How bad could it be?
If I'm wrong,
I will leave you alone.
No more setups.
Hello? You there?
- Alright, fine.
You can invite him.
- Yes!
- But if he turns out
to be another dud,
you leave me alone?
- Scout's honor.
- I'll see you Friday.
- Love you!
- Love you too.
- Who you texting?
- Just Lucy.
You ever meet Adriana or
Clive Cassel at the CATC ball?
- Not that I know of, why?
- Must be for a case
or something.
- Uh, I got to get to work.
Hey.
I love you.
- Love you, too.
- Hey! Uh, just my usual.
And uh,
a round for my friends.
I can't believe it,
she's wearing a dress.
- Nice. I should set you up
on blind dates more often.
- No, you shouldn't.
This was so much work.
- Can you grab...?
- Yeah.
- Happy Birthday!
- Happy Birthday, Lucy.
You guys!
I love them!
These will come in handy!
Thank you both so much.
So, tell me about Mr. Wonderful.
- What? Remi?
Well, he's... He's...
He's wonderful.
Unless you're already
spoken for, that is.
I'm pretty sure he's kind of
the monogamous type.
- Oh, that is August,
my new associate,
wishing me a happy birthday.
He has been a lifesaver,
I honestly don't know how I did
anything without him.
Thank you.
Well, cheers.
To best friends.
Thank you guys for doing this.
- We love you, Lucy.
- Cheers.
- So, seriously,
tell me about this guy.
What's wrong with him?
Why is he single?
- Well, I occasionally snore,
casually drink and I may have
a slight shoe fetish.
- Uh, well, those look like
regular old shoes to me.
- I like her.
Remi.
- Lucy.
- Nice to meet you.
- Well, there it is,
ladies and gentlemen.
Love at first slight.
Hey, I'm just really glad
the two of you got off
on the right foot!
- Ugh!
- Wow.
- Yeah.
- What?
- Well, what do you think?
He's nice, right? He likes you,
he asked me for your number.
- I will admit,
I had a good time.
- So, you gonna see him again?
Charles can 100 % vouch for him.
- Cami, I don't know.
- Take a chance!
Life is full of unknowns,
but risks like this are
worth taking!
Lucy, how many times
do I have to tell you
they are not all bad guys?
- Okay! Fine!
If you stop badgering me,
then I'll go out with him again.
- Now wasn't that easy?
Your chariot awaits.
- Ladies...
- Thank you.
- Sorry, boss.
Didn't mean to scare you.
- That lunch?
- Yeah.
- Then, I won't fire you.
- Thanks.
If you need anything else,
I'll be at the office.
- Thank you!
Where are you going?
And who might you be?
Surprise!
- Thank you for meeting me.
- Of course.
- What are you drinking?
- Uh, I really shouldn't.
I'm charging you
by the hour, remember?
Uh... Manhattan.
- On me.
- Thanks.
So, uh...
Sorry to say I've been tailing
Adriana for a week
and I have nothing
to show for it.
- Oh?
- There's no suspicious
activity.
Her phone log is clean,
she goes to and from work
most days,
consultations,
a homecoming party...
I don't know what to tell you.
I don't think
you need to keep me on.
- Well, I appreciate
your honesty.
- Thanks.
- But, I want you to stay on.
- You would?
- She's up to something.
You've only been
on the case for a week.
I'm sure if you stay on longer,
something will come up.
Call it intuition.
- You really don't trust her.
- Well, a wise woman once
told me to follow my instincts.
Typical.
- Someone you know?
- No.
Turns out,
I don't know him at all.
- And what does that mean?
- You don't want to know.
- Try me.
- Okay. Um...
We met last week.
Thought he was interested.
- Well, for what it's worth,
he's obviously an idiot.
- Thank you.
But I'm the idiot.
I let my friend convince me
to let my guard down
despite my better judgement,
I did.
Serves me right.
- No one deserves
to be deceived.
- I know that better
than anyone.
Look at what I do.
- Right.
So, what got you
into all of this?
Private investigating?
- Well...
My dad left when I was little.
Ran off with his secretary,
believe it or not.
Blindsided my mom,
left her with nothing.
Just seemed like the best way
to make sure
it didn't happen
to someone else.
- So, it's personal.
- Yeah.
That and I always thought
I had killer instincts.
Until now, that is.
- Oh hey, don't let this guy
make you doubt yourself.
We all misjudge people
once in a while.
- I should have known better.
This is why I don't date.
- Ever?
- I always saw trust
as a weakness.
- That's a little harsh,
don't you think?
- This coming from the guy
who asked me to follow his wife?
I'm sorry.
That was uncalled for.
- No, don't apologize,
you're right.
- Well, I should get going.
Thank you for the drink.
- Stay.
- I really shouldn't.
- Don't make me eat alone.
- So, you don't eat alone.
What's that about?
- Oh I didn't say I don't.
I just prefer not to.
What? Is that so hard
to believe?
- I don't know,
I just had you down
as the independent type of guy.
- Oh no, you've got me
all wrong.
Total codependent.
- Really?
- I'm kidding.
Though, I'm starting to think
no one is as independent as you.
- How do you figure?
- You live alone,
you don't date ever,
you see trust as a weakness.
- Okay. Point taken.
- But come on, there must be
someone you can trust.
- Cami.
We've been best friends
since college.
She's been by my side
despite my... intensity.
Through thick and thin,
no matter what.
For years it was me and Cami
against the world.
- Was?
- She married her husband
Charles a few years back.
- Charles?
And how do we feel
about Charles?
- At first, I had my doubts,
as you can imagine.
But he's actually become
a really good friend.
And they're great together.
They're like
the perfect couple.
If there's anyone who could
convince me that...
Never mind.
- What?
- No, it's nothing.
It's stupid.
- Come on, say it.
- No. Really.
- You know I won't let up.
- You are shockingly persistent.
I was just gonna say,
if there's anybody who could
make me believe in true love,
it would be them.
That was even sappier
out loud.
- I think it's nice.
I'm starting to think
you're more of a romantic
than you let on.
You're sure it was him?
- Positive.
- Damn, Luce. I'm sorry.
I totally misjudged him.
- Yeah well, I did too.
I'm just glad it ended before
it even started, you know?
- What were you doing
at The Waverley, anyway?
- I was meeting a client.
- At The Waverley? Fancy.
- Yeah, well, he insisted.
Actually, he um...
He made me feel better
about the whole thing.
We had dinner, talked.
It was nice.
- Having dinner with a client?
I never would've thought
I'd see the day.
- Like I said, he insisted.
- Hey, Luce.
Cami mentioned a Cassel
the other day,
is that the client?
- His name is Clive.
I don't know, there's like
something about him.
I just feel like
I can talk to him.
- Are you sure
this is a good idea, Lucy?
Fraternizing with a client?
He's obviously going
through a lot.
Maybe you should just move
away from this one.
- What are you talking about?
A job's a job!
They just had dinner.
What's the big deal?
- He's a married man, Cami.
What do you even know
about this guy anyway?
- She's a professional, babe.
She's done her due diligence.
Right, Luce?
- Obviously.
Look, I gotta get ready work.
I'll talk to you guys later.
Bye.
- What?
- I really don't think
it's a good idea.
- She knows what she's doing.
- You're right.
Okay.
Love you.
Oh, hey, I've got
that meeting tonight.
So I'm gonna
be home late. Okay?
- Yup. Love you too.
- Bye.
- Have a good day!
- Good work everyone.
Keep it up.
Let's go! Let's go!
Train hard, let's go! Again!
Alright, let's go, come on.
Hard, let's go.
Come on, train hard.
Cross, jab, cross, jab. Come on!
Cross, jab, cross, jab.
One, two, three, four!
Good, keep going.
Come on, come on!
Hey, Clive, you made it.
Come in.
- Sorry I'm late.
- It's all good.
Alright, let's go.
Come on, guys, let's go!
Come on, guys.
Let's keep training!
Let's go, let's go, come on!
Train hard, let's go,
come on!
Ten more, come on!
Next combination.
Let's go, Lucy! Come on, hard!
Come on! Don't slack off.
Come on! 10 more! 10 more!
Let's go!
Okay, listen up,
time to pair up.
Try and team up with someone you
haven't worked with yet, okay?
Let's go, find somebody.
Let's go, come on,
don't waste time.
- Hey!
So what do you say?
Partners?
- Sure.
- Alright.
- Jab, cross!
Again, two more times.
Jab, cross.
Let's go, let's go!
Okay, next combo, Lucy,
next combo.
Right cross, left hook,
right cross.
Don't give up, come on,
everybody!
Come on, I see you slacking
back there, come on!
Get your ass in gear,
let's go, come on, guys!
There it is, yeah, you got it.
- That's quite
the right hook you've got.
- It comes in handy.
You'd be surprised the number
of unsavory characters
I've had to use it on.
- I don't doubt it.
- I've never seen you here
before. New hobby?
- That obvious, huh?
- You held your own.
- Yeah, well, I'm thinking
about investing in the studio.
So, figured I'd come
check it out.
- And?
- I can definitely see
the appeal.
- Well, I should get going.
I don't want my employer
to think I'm slacking off.
- Yeah. Of course.
Nice running into you,
Lucy Thompson.
- Have a good night.
Thank you.
- I know you're following me.
I don't want to hear it,
I know Clive put you up to this.
You're not the first person he's
hired to chase me around town.
He's not who you think he is.
I'd be careful if I were you.
- Dean Calvet plus one, bar.
Clive. Hi.
- Hi. I hope I'm not
calling too early.
- No, not at all.
I'm actually at the office.
- Wow. The reviews online
weren't kidding
when they said
you were dedicated.
I was going to see
if you wanted a coffee.
- Yeah, actually,
that would be great.
Um, there's been
a development with your wife,
I'm just not sure
what it is yet.
Do you know a Dean Calvet?
- Uh, no. Why?
- She had dinner with him
last night.
I was hoping maybe
you knew who he was.
- No. I've never heard
that name before.
- I've got a couple photos.
Maybe you could come by
and identify him?
- Absolutely.
I'll be by shortly
with your coffee
and take a look.
- Great.
They didn't so much
as kiss goodbye.
So they're definitely not
romantically involved,
but she did hand him an envelope
right before he got in the Uber.
So you're right,
there's something going on,
I just don't know
what it is yet.
- Well, I don't
recognize him, but...
What happened after
the envelope?
- He just got in the Uber
and then I followed her home.
- What?
So, you were at my place?
- Yeah.
Why?
- Did you see me?
- Yeah.
She came in, went straight
to the kitchen,
kissed you.
That's when I left.
- Lucy...
Nothing happened.
- It doesn't matter.
She's your wife.
- We're not in love anymore.
- Then why do you care
if she's having an affair?
Why don't you just leave her?
- It's not that simple.
I need to prove
she's cheating
or else she'll fight me
for everything in the divorce.
- So, it's about the money.
- It was...
But it's not anymore.
- What's it about?
- Lucy... it's about you.
- I think you should go.
- Yeah.
Right. I'm sorry.
- No. I'm sorry.
- It's just...
I've never felt this way
about anyone.
- Clive, I...
- What?
- I can't cross this line.
- I understand.
I'll go.
- I'll let you know if I find
anything else about your wife.
- Yeah.
- Lucy!
Sorry I'm late.
The line-up at the coffee bar
was nuts.
Damn hipsters!
I'm in here. Come on in.
- Oh, Mr. Cassel,
good morning.
I'd have brought you a coffee
if I knew you were here.
- Clive brought coffee.
I got some pictures
of this guy last night
and Clive was kind enough
to drop by last minute.
- Thanks, August.
I really do need to get going.
- Thanks for coming by.
- Not a problem.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm good.
Dean Calvet. Got these photos
of him with Adriana Cassel
last night.
I need you to help me figure out
how they know each other.
- Okay. I'll do some digging.
Ah!
- Okay, you ready?
Come on, let's go! Jab!
Double jab! Good, okay.
Ready? Let's go, fast!
Right hand
Duck! Here we go again!
Ah!
- I'm so sorry!
- What's wrong with you?!
- I was distracted, I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
- Yeah, it's okay.
Alright, everyone,
let's switch partners.
Come on, let's go!
Charles?
Charles!
- Luce! Hey.
What are you doing here?
- I just finished boxing.
Why are you
on this side of town?
- Oh, I'm just meeting
a potential client.
- Here?
- Yeah. He insisted.
He owns a couple
of these places.
- Ah, an underground gambling
ring leader.
Say no more.
- Yeah.
That's why they pay me
the big bucks.
- Well, I won't keep you.
- Nice seeing you.
Hey, Luce?
Would you just mind not telling
Cami about this?
You know how she worries.
- Sure. Okay.
- Great.
- Hey!
- I just don't think
this is something John Cutler
would be capable of.
- Yeah, me neither,
just doesn't fit the profile.
- Well, then, it leaves us
with Dimitri Alexander.
What's his story?
- Last I checked,
Dimitri was in jail.
- Okay. What happened?
- I put him there.
This was years ago when
I was doing surveillance
for the police department.
They had me tailing him
for weeks to gather evidence
against him
in a drug-related incident.
Turns out he wasn't just
into drugs.
He had a thing
for beating his wife.
I testified against him.
Put him away for a long time.
Well, interesting.
- What?
- Well, it says here
Dimitri Alexander was let out
on parole last week.
- Are you kidding me?
- No.
Wait a minute, where you going?
- I'm going to El Caballito.
That's the bar he used to run
his business out of.
- Hold on.
- I'm not leaving this
to the cops.
They couldn't put him away
without me last time.
I'm not trusting them
to do it now.
- Okay, Lucy, sit down. Please.
Listen, just leave this
to me, alright?
Take the day. I will go
through the files,
I'll come up
with some questions.
It's not gonna get us anywhere
if you go over there
and get hurt by a violent
wife-beater
who has a personal vendetta
against you.
- You're right.
- Now, go home, take the day.
You've been through a lot.
- I can't go home.
I've got to get back
to the Cassel case.
Adriana's supposed
to be going out of town
with her sister tonight
and I still don't know
who that guy was
she went out for dinner
with the other night.
- Lucy, breathe.
I'm sure Clive will
understand
if you take one day
for yourself.
- Who's there?
- It's Clive.
- Hi.
What are you doing here?
- I just needed to see you.
You alright?
Hey...
- I don't know what to do.
I don't even feel safe
in my own home anymore.
- It's completely
understandable.
Someone breaks into
your house
and with this Dimitri guy
out there...
- Yeah.
And then,
there's the nightmares.
I feel like I'm losing my mind.
- You're not losing your mind,
Lucy.
Hey. Look at me.
You're being personally
targeted.
This is stressful and scary
and this guy is obviously
deranged.
Something like this would be
enough to rattle anyone.
- So what do I do?
- You could get out of town
for a few days.
At least until August gets some
information out of this guy.
- So what, just... up and leave?
What about your wife?
What about the case?
- You know, Adriana is
out of town with her sister
for the next few days.
- Or so she says.
This could be our smoking gun.
Don't you want to know
where she's really going?
- She's going to Vale to see
her sister and her nieces.
She goes every year, she'll be
posting about it all weekend.
- Yeah, but...
- You can take a break from
the case, Lucy.
Seriously.
It can wait.
- Well...
Where would we even go?
- Trust me.
- August, hi.
- I'm just calling to let
you know that Dimitri no longer
runs his business
out of El Caballito.
- Damn.
- No, no, it's okay.
I've managed to find
where his new front is.
It's a nightclub called
The Blue Grotto.
I'm gonna pay him a visit
later tonight.
- Nice work.
I should come with you.
- No, no.
It's better if I go alone.
He doesn't know who I am
and he won't know I'm connected
to you in any way.
- Right.
Okay, well, be careful.
- Yeah. Of course.
- I, uh... I should let you know
I'm gonna be out of town
for the next few days.
- Oh. That sounds great.
That should be good for you.
- Yeah. At least until you get
something out of Dimitri.
- Yeah. Couldn't agree more.
Where you heading?
- A cabin in Meadowbrooke.
- Nice. You're renting?
- No, it's... it's a friend's.
- Nice friend.
I've heard there's some pretty
fancy cottages out that way.
- Yeah. For sure.
- You okay?
- All things considered?
Yeah. I'm good.
- Alright.
Enjoy the countryside. And...
I'll give you a call after
I talk to Dimitri.
- Sounds good.
Everything okay?
- Yeah. I don't know...
I just feel like he knows
I'm hiding something.
- Well, I wouldn't worry
about him.
You're the boss.
If he finds out, he'll just
have to deal with it.
- This is amazing.
- Thanks.
It's been in my family
for generations.
Oh, it's one of
my favorite places.
- Thank you for
bringing me here.
- Name?
- Hey. No.
I'm not on your list.
I'm here to see Dimitri.
- No one gets in
if they're not on the list.
- I'm one of
his business partners.
He's expecting me.
- Yeah, well, Dimitri
is not here right now.
- Oh yeah?
Why don't you let me go inside
and have a look for myself?
- Like I said, no one gets in if
they're not on the list.
- Right.
Dimitri.
I need to talk to you.
Damn!
- Hmm.
So, what do you think?
Oh, I'm sorry.
You're obviously
still a little on edge.
Well, why don't I put
on a fire
and you can pour us some wine?
- That sounds great.
- Okay.
I'm sorry.
- What?
I'm just looking at you.
Oh, my God. That smile
is gonna be the death of me.
- What is it about you?
- What do you mean?
- I never let my guard down.
But around you...
I know I just met you.
I don't know,
it just feels like...
- Like an instinct?
- Yeah.
- Come on, Dimitri.
I know you're down there.
- What do you want, man?
- I just wanna talk to you.
- What do you wanna know?
- Where were you the night
of April 27th?
Let me phrase it another way.
Did you break into
Lucy Thompson's house?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- I was paid by some guy
to mess with her.
That bitch ruined my life,
seemed like a win-win.
- Someone paid you to break
into her house?
- Yeah, some guy named Clive,
gave me 10 grand,
said it was time for the hunter
to become the hunted
or some crap like that.
- Clive...
- Hey!
Who are you?
Who the hell are you?
- Lucy, pick up the phone.
- Hi, you've reached
Lucy Thompson...
- Lucy, pick up the phone!
- Please leave a detailed
message and I'll get back...
- Meadowbrooke?
- Good morning.
- How are you feeling?
- I'm feeling a lot better.
- This place has that effect.
- I think you have that effect.
Do I?
Coffee?
Thanks.
- I'll be right back.
- Come on.
- There you are.
- Hey.
Ooh.
Didn't mean to sneak up on you.
Everything okay down here?
- No! August left me a voicemail
and I can't check it
because I have no signal.
- Yeah, the reception here
is pretty awful.
- I don't know what to do.
This could be important.
It could be about Dimitri.
I shouldn't have come here.
- Oh, hey, hey.
It's a good thing you came.
You needed this. Remember?
- I need to get back
to the city.
- I know where we can get
a signal. Come on.
Try now.
- Two bars.
That should do it.
You don't have to wait for me
if you don't want to.
- No, I'll wait.
I want to know what he said.
What did he say?
Lucy, hey! Hey!
Lucy, what did he say? Lucy!
Just talk to me!
- It was you!
You paid Dimitri.
I can't believe I trusted you.
- I've never even met Dimitri.
Lucy, stop! I love you.
- Oh, my God.
No!
Oh, my God!
- Lucy!
What did you do?
Come on.
- Thanks.
- What's going on?
- Self-defense.
They're not gonna hold me.
- Great, then come on.
Let's get out of here.
So... you were sleeping
with the client.
I'm sorry. I'm just trying
to make sense of all this.
- It was stupid, I know.
I can't talk about it
right now.
- Okay.
- Thank you... for warning me.
Who knows what would have
happened if I'd stayed there
with him.
- Hey.
We're in this together.
- Lucy, where the hell were you?
I tried calling.
- Thank you for being there.
- Of course. Get some rest.
- Uh, August,
this is my best friend Cami.
- It's nice to finally meet you!
- Pleasure to meet you.
I should go.
Call me if you need anything.
- I will.
- What's going on?
- Clive's dead.
- What?!
- It was an accident.
I was defending myself.
He wasn't who I thought
he was at all.
I was at his cabin.
He was the one behind
the break-in.
He was after me the whole time.
- Oh, honey.
Let's get you inside.
Come on.
So, what happens next?
- I don't know.
But right now, we drink.
Hey.
What's going on? You okay?
- I'm fine.
I'm sorry. You don't need
to hear this right now.
- Cami, something
is clearly bothering you.
Talk to me.
- You've just been
through so much.
Now is not the time.
- I'm here for you, always.
What's going on?
- It's Charles.
- What about him?
- I just...
I think I might need
to hire you.
- You think Charles
is cheating?
Where is this coming from?
- He's been acting differently.
Going out to see clients, coming
home at five in the morning.
I never know where he is.
- His job has always been
demanding, though, right?
- Not like this.
These past few weeks,
he's been totally withdrawn.
He can't even look at me,
let alone touch me.
The other day, he came home
blackout drunk
with a busted lip.
I think he might be
gambling now. I just...
I don't know what to believe.
- When was that?
- Thursday, I think. Why?
- Okay, I'm gonna
tell you something
and I need you to understand
that it did not seem
like a big deal at the time.
- What do you...
What do you mean?
What are you saying?
- I saw Charles in the Slaphouse
District on Thursday.
- You what?
- He said he was meeting
a client.
He asked me not to say
anything.
- So you listened to Charles
over telling your best friend?
- He said he didn't want you
to worry.
I had no idea.
- Lucy, this is huge!
How could you not have
said anything?
- I didn't think there was
anything to say.
Obviously, I was wrong.
This might explain his behavior
for the last few weeks.
Cami, I'm sorry.
- I have to go.
- Hey. Let's figure this out
together.
- Honestly, Lucy,
I think you've done enough.
Lucy, talk to me!
- It was you!
You paid Dimitri.
I can't believe I trusted you.
- I've never even met Dimitri.
Lucy, stop! I love you.
- No!
- Lucy... I wasn't
expecting you today.
- I need to figure out
what the hell is going on.
- Okay, he hires you
to follow his wife,
so he has tabs on you
at all times,
then, he seduces you,
then hires Dimitri
to terrorize you.
- Yeah. I've been going over it
again and again.
And I just keep asking myself
"why".
- I think it all goes back
to this sick obsession.
It's clear that he had
this fixation with you.
- Yeah. But he had me.
- Yeah. Not until
after the break-in.
- He kept insisting that he'd
never seen Dimitri in his life.
- Hey, it's perfectly normal
to second-guess yourself
after such a traumatic event.
But, Lucy, you did what
you had to do.
Who knows what he might have
done to you?
I don't know.
The more I replay it in my mind,
the more I think he just
was genuinely confused.
Like, he had no idea about
the break-in or any of it.
- Yeah, well, the only way
to prove that
would be to ask Dimitri.
- August, there's a lot
that's not adding up.
Dimitri is the only one that
can answer these questions.
- Okay, you're the boss.
I'm going with you.
- Good.
- Nice place.
- Yeah, you should've been here
last week.
- What are you looking at?
- Nothing.
Huh, great.
- You know him?
- Yeah. Let's just say that.
- Well, look who it is.
- Yeah, good to see you.
- I should have known
you two were working together.
- Hi, Dimitri.
- What do you want?
- I need to tell me who hired
you to break into my house.
- I already told this guy.
His name was Clive.
- You mean this guy, Clive?
- What do I get
for ID'ing this person?
Why should I help you?
- If you don't cooperate,
I press charges
and you get sent away again,
for a very long time.
- I've never seen this guy
in my life.
- You're sure?
- Positive.
The Clive I met was shorter...
Trying to grow a moustache.
Leave me alone.
- It doesn't make any sense.
- It's... It's just not
adding up.
Hang on a sec.
- Lucy! You okay?
I'll be right out.
What have you done?
I killed him.
I killed the wrong guy.
- You thought you were
in danger.
Anyone else would have done
the same thing.
- He was in love with me
and I killed him.
How could I have gotten
everything so wrong?
- Wait a minute.
Maybe you were supposed to.
Hear me out.
Whoever got Dimitri
to break into your house
knew you were going
to find out it was Clive,
and then that you would
confront him.
- You think Adriana
would have wanted him dead?
- He was a very wealthy man.
People do bad things for money.
Really bad things.
- Got any pings on that guy
she went out for dinner with
the other night?
- None.
- What was the description of
that guy Dimitri actually met?
Can you see if there's
anything there?
- Alright. Will do.
- I'm gonna go to The Regent.
That's where he was staying.
See if I can get any info there.
- Okay and I'll go to Adriana's,
see if I find anything.
- Be careful.
- Yeah, you too.
- Lucy?
Lucy!
- Lucy saw you with him.
We'll deal with her later.
Did you get the passports?
- You are now...
Vanessa Armando.
- Do you think
I can pull it off?
- Did you...
drain all of his accounts?
- Now that Clive is dead,
it all belongs to us.
- Did you use the routing number
that Dean set up?
- Right... the routing number.
- Adriana, that
one's untraceable, right?
We cannot leave until
the funds are in that account.
- I'm sorry! I put the funds
in my account.
I didn't think it would matter.
- Well, it does!
You want people
to be able to find us?
What's your password?
- I think someone's out there.
- Adriana, your password.
Want some more wine?
- Of course.
- To us.
To us.
I love you so much.
I cannot wait to start this next
chapter of our lives.
Together.
Finally free,
without Cami or Clive.
Just you and me, together.
- Yeah, I don't think
that's gonna happen.
- What?
- He's changed
all his passwords.
- After everything I've been
through to get here.
The strings I pulled!
Clive is dead!
- Don't lie to yourself.
You wanted him gone.
If he would've found out
about us,
he would have left you
with nothing.
- The money.
- What are you doing?
- I'm stopping
the funds transfer.
- Hey. I can't let you do that.
- This isn't your money,
Charles.
What did you do?
But I love you.
Oh no. No, no, no.
- Hi, you've reached
Lucy Thompson of
Thompson Investigations.
Please leave a detailed
message and I'll get back
to you shortly.
It's me!
I'm sorry I overreacted
the other day.
I should not have blamed you for
what Charles has done.
It turns out he was hiding a lot
more from me than I thought.
I'm kicking him out!
I love you. Call me back.
Lucy. Hey!
Lucy!
Damn it!
- August! It was Charles
and Adriana.
I think he killed her.
Call me when you get this.
Cami!
- I'm here.
- Okay. Hey... Hey, listen.
I just watched Charles
kill Adriana.
- What are you talking about?
- He wants to kill me now.
Let's go.
- Lucy!
Cami.
- Get out!
- What?! No...
- Cami, no, I can explain.
Don't listen to Lucy,
she's crazy.
- I know you're cheating
on me, Charles.
And the gambling?
I know we're broke!
You are the reason
Clive is dead!
- No. Lucy is trying
to tear us apart.
She's always been jealous
of what we have!
- You're a murderer and
I need you to get
the hell out of my house
and out of my life.
Get out!
- This is all your fault!
- No, Charles.
This is your fault!
You're going to prison!
- Don't listen to her.
Just don't listen to her, okay?
I came back.
Look at this life we have, huh?
I did this to protect that.
I did it all for you.
- You're insane.
- You don't understand,
Cami, look.
Look, just forget everything.
Alright? Yeah?
I solved our money problems.
Okay? We can be happy together.
I love you.
- Okay, Charles... It's over.
- Charles, wait!
Stop!
911, what is
your emergency?
- Listen to me, listen to me.
You came back.
That's all that matters.
Hey, hey! You did
what you had to do for us.
Look at me.
I see that now. Okay?
Alright, baby?
For better for worse, right?
Yeah.
Lucy! Lucy!
Ah!
- You're okay.
Hey, it's okay.
- This guy was fast.
I was out of breath.
- I've got news!
They love it.
- Uh... Who loves what?
- The publisher?
- They literally want to buy
the rights to your story after
reading the first twenty pages.
Lucy, this book is going
to be huge.
- Seriously?
- Yeah. Our story is incredible.
People are going
to want to hear it.
- This is so exciting.
- How is the rest
of the book coming?
- It's going really well.
It's been cathartic putting it
all down on paper.
So, wait, what happens now?
- Well, the publishers are going
to send over a contract
and all you have to do is sign!
You are going to love
the deal I got you.
- I don't doubt that.
You're a shark.
I am, aren't I?
- So I'll see you
for dinner tonight?
- You know it.
Are you coming, August?
- Of course. I'll be there.
- Amazing. Love you.
- Love you.
- Wow.
Lucy, congratulations!
- Yeah, she thinks we've
really got something here.
- Yeah, so do I. And I, for one,
can't wait to read it.
- I have a feeling we're about
to get very busy.
- Yeah. I think so!
- Ready to dive in, partner?
- I will do you proud,
Lucy Thompson.
- I know you will.
Now, go back to work.