For the lady of the camellias.
And they're almost twice as large
as usual.
I shall have twice as many
as usual tomorrow.
Twice as man...? Oh, don't listen to her,
Barjon. I know what those things cost.
Aren't you willing to listen to her when
she orders hats and dresses from you?
They're an investment.
Of course, I order too many flowers,
hats and too many everything.
But I want them.
To the theater.
And there's no limit to your extravagance.
Now, you won't be young forever.
It's high time you settle something
about your future.
And I know the very man for you.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
Aren't you interested
to know who it is?
Oh, yes, who is it?
The Baron de Varville, one of the richest
and most elegant gentlemen in Paris.
One foot in the grave
and a wig on his head.
Not at all. Not at all. Quite the contrary.
He's young and handsome.
I heard from one of the girls in my shop
who heard from his valet...
...he's gonna be at the theater tonight.
That's why I wanted you to look your best.
Come here.
I want to send a note.
And I'll give you a handsome tip
if you get it to the right person.
Do you know the Baron de Varville?
- Yes, Madame.
- Good.
Well, that's done.
We go this way.
My dear, you're as good
as a baroness already.
Don't forget. I arranged it all.
- Where are we sitting?
- Box A, of course. I always ask for Box A.
The baron can't miss it.
Come, come, old dear, open Box A.
- Someone else is in there.
- What?
- Good evening. Let me see your ticket.
- Here.
- Why, this says Box B.
- I asked for Box A.
If you'd wear your spectacles,
you'd see what you get.
- None of your lip.
- Not so much fuss.
- Wait, who's in there?
- A friend of yours.
- Olympe.
Right.
Well, what's so funny about it,
I'd like to know.
How you arranged everything for Olympe.
That cat. If you think I'm going to let...
...a cheating, lying wretch like that
upset my plans, you're wrong.
- She's got to change places with us.
- Well, fight it out, ladies.
- My angel.
- Marguerite, darling.
Oh, how are you, my dear?
How beautiful we look this evening.
- Nice perfume. What is it?
- That's my secret.
- And how are you, you old robber?
- You're great for teasing, aren't you?
Is there any point in our staying out here
in this draft?
Oh, look here, Olympe, there's been
a little mistake about our tickets...
...and we want you
to change boxes with us.
Why?
I can't understand why you must sit
in this box when yours is just as good.
Well, you know Prudence.
She's a woman full of secrets.
Even changing her corset
is a great mystery.
Some things have to be a mystery.
But if you'll do what I ask you to do,
I'll send you that fur toque for a present.
It's a bargain.
During the intermission, I'll move.
Come here, Marguerite.
A note for Monsieur le Baron.
- Which is Box A?
- There, Monsieur le Baron. At the left.
Show me to my seat.
Doesn't Monsieur le Baron
wish to send an answer?
I'll wait and decide that later.
My dear, do you see that gentleman
standing up?
- Which one?
- In the second row on the aisle.
- Yes. Do you know him?
- I know who he is.
He's the fabulously rich de Varville,
Baron de Varville.
I didn't know that rich men
ever looked like that.
This one does. He's looking at us.
He's seen us looking at him.
I've changed my mind, Prudence.
You can keep your fur toque.
The Baron de Varville is on his way to this
box, and I'm going to stay and meet him.
But he's coming here to meet me.
- So that's what you had up your sleeve.
- I invited him to join us here myself.
Nothing could be better. Thank you,
my dear Prudence, for arranging it.
But having done so much,
you really must let me receive him alone.
- Unfortunately, I like him too.
- Why unfortunately?
Because his eyes have made love to me
all evening.
That's a lie. He barely glanced at you.
I never took my glasses from his face...
...except for an instant
to let him see mine.
Perhaps that was the instant
he smiled at me.
He did not smile at you,
and he won't meet you here.
- Then he must look for me somewhere else.
- Sit down, Marguerite.
Listen, Olympe, I appeal to your sense
of honor, if you have such a thing.
Oh, shut up, you old woman.
Get out before I have you dragged out.
Come, come, Prudence.
You really are a fool, Olympe.
You're the fool.
You know that Prudence
is nothing but an old vulture.
Vulture! She called me a vulture.
That one who'd pick
a dead man's pocket.
I'll tell you something else. If you don't
stop being so easygoing with money...
...you'll land in the gutter before
you're through.
Or back on that farm
where you came from...
...milking cows
and cleaning out henhouses.
Cows and chickens make better friends
than I've ever met in Paris.
Come here. Stop the baron going to Box A.
Tell him to join us in Box B. Hurry. Hurry!
Monsieur le Baron. There has been
a mistake, Monsieur le Baron.
The lady who sent you the note
does not wish you to go to Box A...
...but to join her and her friend in Box B.
So it is you. Do come in, monsieur.
But your answer, Monsieur le Baron.
You may say that for the moment
I am engaged.
- Are you following me?
- Yes.
You... Well, you did smile at me
a moment ago, didn't you?
Well, you tell me first whether
you smiled at me or at my friend.
- What friend?
- You didn't even see her?
- No.
- That's very nice.
I was wondering if you'd ask me to sit
down if I knocked at the door of the box.
Why not?
We really seemed fated to meet
this evening, didn't we?
Fate must've had something to do
with this evening.
I've hoped for it so long.
- You don't believe me?
- No.
The first time I saw you
was a year and a half ago.
You were in an open carriage
and dressed in white.
I saw you go into a shop
in the Place de la Bourse.
Yes, that might've happened. I went
to a dressmaker in Place de la Bourse.
You were wearing a thin dress
with miles of ruffles...
...a large straw hat, an embroidered shawl,
a single bracelet and heavy, gold chain...
...and, of course,
the camellias at your waist.
You have a marvelous memory,
haven't you?
The next time was at the Opéra Comique.
You were sitting in a box
with a fur coat on...
...and Gaston, a chap whom I know
who knows you...
...said, "Marguerite's been ill. "
And that hurt me.
- The next time...
- Tell me, if all you say is true...
...why have you never
spoken to me before?
- In the first place, I didn't know you.
- You didn't know me tonight.
No, but after you smiled at me,
I knew you wouldn't mind.
And now, since you've met me?
Now I know that I love you...
...and have loved you
since that first day.
Marguerite, my dear.
After what happened,
I had to have a brandy.
- And after that, two brandies.
- Yes, and then he made me have another.
Well, that's only four.
Suppose you go and have another,
Prudence, and then...
Well, then another.
- You don't want to get me drunk, do you?
- She wants to get rid of us.
She wants to be alone with my friend.
For once in your life
you're quite right, Gaston.
Who is your friend anyway?
Baron de Varville, this is my neighbor,
Madame Duvernoy.
- Baron de Varville?
- He, the Baron de Varville?
No wonder she wanted to get rid of us.
Well, I... I never said
I was the "Baron" anybody.
There's the Baron de Varville...
...sitting over there, big as life,
with that wretch, Olympe.
- Really?
- Certainly.
Well, this is rather funny.
- Funny?
- Yes, I quite agree with you. It is funny.
Oh, even if you're not Baron de Varville,
sit down.
I can't believe I'm wanted now that
my unimportance has been discovered.
Don't be silly. Who are you anyhow?
My name is Armand Duval.
I've never had any reason
to be ashamed of it.
- Armand Duval.
- Yes.
I'm not always sincere.
One can't be in this world, you know.
- But I am not sorry the mistake happened.
- Nor am I.
The baron keeps looking over here.
That must worry Olympe.
Well, as long as you don't wish to sit down,
would you go and buy me some sweets?
You can afford a pound
of marrons glacés...
...even if you're not the rich baron,
can't you?
I'll not come back with your sweets
too soon.
- What is your friend's name?
- I'm not sure which friend you mean.
The girl in the opposite box
whom you just spoke to.
Oh, her. Well, she's hardly a friend.
I know her, of course.
But she's not easy to get along with.
Ask anybody.
What did you say her name was?
And she has a reputation of being one
of the most extravagant girls in Paris...
...as well as one of the most insincere.
- I like sincerity, don't you?
- It's an admirable quality.
Well, I insist on it.
She's the kind who says one thing
and thinks another.
- Who?
- Marguerite, the girl we were talking about.
Marguerite.
- What is her other name?
- Gautier. Not that it's her real name.
She had some sort of very common name,
I hear, when she came to Paris.
There's no use boring you about her.
A friend of mine is giving a small party
tonight, if you'd care to come.
I detest parties. Thank you
for a very charming entr'acte, my dear.
Will I see you again?
I should think it's very likely, sometime.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
- I hope I don't intrude.
- No.
You're very welcome, baron.
I was delighted when I saw
that you were alone.
Oh, monsieur, I'm so sorry
I kept you waiting.
I had to go to two shops
before I found your marrons glacés.
It doesn't matter. I'm in no hurry.
But since nothing but marrons glacés
would do, these are very fresh.
- Will monsieur try one?
- Thank you.
Thank you, monsieur.
The coachman wishes me
to remind Monsieur le Baron...
...there are four horses to manage,
and they're restless.
Very well.
I must go.
I think I'll change my mind
and take you with me.
- The doctors warned me against Russia.
- But Russia isn't cold in summer.
Even so, the trip would be
too much for me.
I shall get tired. I shall get ill again.
And you'll be bored.
Now, what shall I give you
to remember me by?
- You can't give the only thing I'd like.
- What?
A tear.
- You're not sorry enough I'm going.
- Oh, but I am sorry.
Is there anything I can do for you
before I go?
Yes. I'm going to an auction
this afternoon.
- I would like to buy a pair of horses.
- I just gave you a pair.
Yes, but these horses belonged
to my friend, Eugenie Clivet...
...who died a few weeks ago.
And I know she'd like me
to have her horses.
Well, what of it
if you don't need them?
Olympe wants them.
She always wants everything I want...
...and I don't want her to have them.
Are you really as jealous of Olympe
as all that? I don't believe it.
I'll be frank with you.
I want Clivet's horses
because I want the coachman.
And he'd be miserable
without the horses.
- He must be very young and handsome.
- Oh, no.
He's quite old. He's older than Nanine.
But, well, he needs someone to take care
of him, and I know Olympe won't.
So much heart and so little sense.
I shall take a good look
at your new coachman when I come back.
- Thank you.
- Now, goodbye.
Goodbye.
Keep an eye on her, Nanine.
Two thousand two hundred and forty
for this magnificent pair of chestnuts.
They're the finest pair
in the whole of France.
Why, they're worth 5000 at least.
- Two thousand five hundred.
- Bid, Nanine, 3000.
- Twenty-five hundred once.
- Three thousand.
So that's what you came for.
I might've known it.
Three thousand and one hundred francs.
Three thousand seven hundred and fifty.
- Four thousand. Four!
- Four thousand.
Four thousand for this fine pair of chestnuts
which is easily worth 7.
- Oh, that's too much.
- Of course. Don't bid anymore.
- I won't.
- No.
Four thousand one hundred.
- Four thousand one hundred.
- Four thousand five hundred.
- Five thousand!
- Five thousand. Five thousand!
Five thousand francs for this magnificent
pair of chestnuts, ladies and gentlemen.
They can be sold any day for 10.
- Five thousand one hundred.
- Six thousand.
- Six thousand. Six thousand.
Six thousand francs.
Ladies and gentlemen. Once, twice.
Ladies and gentlemen, sold at 6000 francs.
Well, I hope they don't run away
and kill you. I hear they're none too safe.
Go settle with the auctioneer, Nanine.
Tell the old coachman
we'll take him with the horses.
- You really have a heart, Marguerite.
- Yes. It's going to cost her a lot.
- I hope mine never gets that soft.
- Don't worry, it won't.
It's a great mistake for any woman
to have a heart bigger than her purse.
Prudence, did you invite them
to my party tomorrow?
I thought the baron disliked parties.
He won't be there.
He'd be bored with my friends.
- Have you quarreled?
- Not yet, but don't give up hope, Olympe.
- Nichette.
- Marguerite.
How well you look. How happy.
It must be love.
- It is.
- Still the same young man?
Of course. And just think, Marguerite.
He talks of our getting married.
Just as soon as he's passed
his examinations and is a real lawyer.
- You seem to think that's very fine of him.
- But of course I do.
After all, I have no dowry,
and he's a gentleman and educated.
Even so, why should the mention
of marriage go to your head?
But, Marguerite, it's ideal to love,
and to marry the one you love.
I have no faith in ideals.
Amuse yourself if you wish.
But remember, you can always do better
than a penniless lawyer.
I never want to do better
than Gustave.
Well, well, time changes our minds,
as well as our hearts.
Perhaps you won't go on being
a little goose always.
Only, come and see me now and then.
Remember, you're my oldest friend
in Paris.
I will, Marguerite. Soon.
I often think of those days we worked
in the linen shop.
I'm so glad to see you today
and that you're looking so well.
I always look well
when I'm near death.
Armand Duval.
- Where are my marrons glacés?
- I ate them, Madame, six months ago.
What a pity.
However, I'm glad of this opportunity
of returning something belonging to you.
- Yes?
- I found it on the floor when I came back.
- And you kept it with you all this time?
- Yes.
- Always with you?
- Always with me, like an old friend...
...to remind me that I'm not
the Baron de Varville.
- That's not a very romantic reason.
- No, I kept it as a warning against romance.
How sensible.
Has it made you very cynical?
- Yes, very.
- Is that why you've never called on me?
- Perhaps.
- I'm sorry. One needs friends.
Well, I've been looking for you.
Monsieur, you can see for yourself,
she's quite well again.
Oh, no, Nanine.
Well, or would be
if she took proper care of herself.
Why would my health interest
Monsieur Duval?
Because he came every day
when you were ill...
...to ask how you were
and to leave flowers.
He's the one?
Tell her yourself.
He just said "a friend," so I thought...
- All right, Nanine. Wait for me downstairs.
- Yes, Madame. Monsieur.
- You might have asked to have seen me.
- Well, I knew there were so many others.
There were no others.
None during all those weeks
the doctors thought I might die.
Not even the Baron de Varville?
Baron de Varville chose
to be in England at the time.
No, you were the only one
that took the trouble to ring my bell.
- But now...
- Now I'm well again, and all goes merrily.
Would you come to a party I'm giving
tomorrow night? It's my birthday.
Aren't you afraid
you're not strong enough yet?
Oh, I'm afraid of nothing
except being bored.
- It's supper after the theater.
- Thank you, I'll come with pleasure.
And bring this book as a present.
Have you read it?
- I never read anything. What is it?
- Manon Lescaut.
- Who was she?
- A beautiful girl...
...who lived for love and pleasure.
It's a beautiful color.
It should be a very good story.
Yes, it is, but it's rather sad.
She dies in the end.
Well, then I'll keep it, but I won't read it.
I don't like sad thoughts.
However, we all die.
So perhaps this will be sold again
someday at an auction after my death.
- I thought you didn't like sad thoughts.
- I don't. But they come sometimes.
- Au revoir, Monsieur Duval.
- Goodbye.
Marguerite, my child, are we waiting
for someone, my dear?
- Or are we just waiting for supper?
- Both.
I was so afraid you wouldn't come.
- Here's the book I brought you.
- Thank you.
We were just about to sit down.
- Will you come?
- Oh, I remember you, young man.
- You're the bogus baron.
- Tactful as always, Prudence.
- You may all sit where you wish.
- Thank you so much.
Now, I'm going to sit next to Gaston,
and you sit over here.
Thank you.
Oh, Marguerite,
how charming this table looks.
- And how are you this evening, Madame?
- Very well, and how are you, monsieur?
Good gracious, listen to them.
Why so formal?
Why not? This is a very elegant soiree.
Well, elegant or not,
if I'm going to enjoy my supper...
...I've got to take off these tight shoes.
Help me, Gaston.
Can't you manage to hold it
a little higher?
There.
- What are those little fellas on that dish?
- Partridges, Madame.
- Put some on my plate.
- Some? How many do you think you'll get?
Partridges are not oysters, you know.
Well, they don't look
much bigger than oysters.
- What's the joke?
- The funniest story I've ever heard...
...in my life. I shall die!
- Tell me, tell me.
- Get closer.
- Tell me.
- Oh, no, tell me.
Well, no fair. Tell us all.
Tell me the story, Gaston.
I know what's coming, but you go on.
I want a laugh too. Tell me the story.
I'll tell you. You've probably heard
it before. It's as old as Prudence.
- What's that about my being old?
- I said that the story was as old as you are.
I'm 36.
Drink your wine, Armand.
He's as sad as a drinking song.
What's the matter? Are you shocked?
No, certainly not.
Only, I know all Gaston's jokes.
In fact, I told him most of them.
I'd sooner they weren't repeated
at your table.
Oh, come, come.
You must remember, I'm not a colonel's
daughter just out of the convent.
Bravo! Bravo!
I do this better than anybody.
Nobody can do it as well as I can.
- Slower, Charles, you're going too fast.
- You're getting tired.
If you don't stop playing,
Olympe will drop dead.
She can't keep that up forever,
she's not so young.
Faster, I'm just getting into the mood.
You'll drop, dear.
Well, go ahead and drop. I don't care.
- Sit beside me, dear.
- I'm not tired.
I appreciate you. I love you.
I love you.
Now, don't go away. I adore you.
- Play a waltz, Charles.
- I don't want to. I want to play a polka.
Very well, play a polka.
Dance with me, Gaston.
Dance, everybody.
Oh, it's you.
What's happened? You look ill too.
No, it's...
It's seeing you like this, suffering.
It's nothing.
- It lasts only a minute.
- You're killing yourself.
If I am, you are the only one
who objects.
Now, Armand, why don't you go back
and dance with one of those pretty girls.
Come. I'll go with you.
What a child you are.
Your hand's so hot.
Is that why you put tears on it,
to cool it?
I know I don't mean anything to you.
I don't count.
But someone ought to look after you.
And I could if you'd let me.
Too much wine
has made you sentimental.
It wasn't wine that made me come every
day for months to find out how you were.
No, that couldn't have been wine.
- So you'd really like to take care of me?
- Yes.
- All day, every day?
- All day, every day. Why not?
Why should you care
for a woman like me?
I'm always nervous or sick
or sad or too gay.
But I do care for you.
You know what you should do?
You should get married.
Come, come.
You're young and sensitive.
The sort of company you're in tonight
doesn't suit you at all.
- Nor you.
- Nonsense.
These are the only friends I have,
and I'm no better than they are.
However, I've given you
some very good advice.
Now, let's go back.
What on earth am I going
to do with you?
No one has ever loved you
as I love you.
That may be true,
but what can I do about it?
You should go away
and not see me anymore.
But don't go in anger.
Why don't you laugh at yourself a little
as I laugh at myself...
...and come and talk to me
once in a while in a friendly way.
That's too much. And not enough.
Don't you believe in love, Marguerite?
I don't think I know what it is.
- Oh, thank you.
- For what?
For never having been in love.
How funny you are.
That's right, laugh at me.
Perhaps your laughter will cure me.
Nothing else seems to.
I believe you're sincere, at least.
After all, when one may not have
long to live...
...why shouldn't one have fancies?
You see, I'm not laughing anymore.
Take this and come back to me
when it dies.
- How soon will that be?
- Tomorrow night.
Look...
...it's dead already. Now.
- That's impossible.
- It's not. Send those people away.
- I can't.
- I will. I'll tell them you're ill.
It's true. You're too ill to talk
with anyone but me tonight.
If they go, you must go too.
- What?
- Yes.
Come back later, alone, so we'll have
supper in here tonight.
Go in the other room, and I'll have
Nanine get rid of you all.
You're not sending me for
marrons glacés, are you?
How do I know you'll let me
in when I come back?
There. You can let yourself in
when you come back.
You're an angel.
I won't go, I can't.
Marguerite Gautier.
Stretch your legs, ladies!
Remember, the hat's full of money...
...and the one kicking it
out of my hand gets it all!
Out of my way, everybody!
Get back! I don't have to run a mile
to get my leg up.
Let me try.
Again.
- Madame Prudence. Madame Prudence!
- Hello! Hello, Nanine.
Madame is sorry,
but she must send everybody away.
Oh, what a pity. Just when we were having
such a good time too.
Bad news, everybody. Party's over.
- What?
- Marguerite wants us to go home.
She started to cough while dancing.
She was ill.
She's always ill
when anybody's having fun.
What's the matter?
Did she drink too much?
Don't be a cat, Olympe.
- Well, it's late anyhow.
- Let's go somewhere else.
Let's go to my place!
I wanna keep trying till I kick it.
What about something to eat?
I'm just beginning to be hungry again.
I think that I'll take some food.
Come get some, everybody!
Don't forget the cheese!
Somebody bring the cheese.
Forward march!
- But I thought you wanted your hair done.
- I do.
- Have they been gone long?
- Just about half an hour.
- Nanine, you told the servants to go to bed?
- They've gone.
- But I fixed supper for the two of you.
- Oh, good, Nanine.
Darling Nanine, perfect Nanine,
hurry up.
- Good evening, my dear.
- Good evening.
You've lost no time in celebrating
my departure, I see.
So you didn't go to Russia after all.
- I had an idea you wouldn't.
- No.
You may flatter yourself.
I can't do without you.
After driving most of the day, I turned
round and drove most of the night back.
What's this? More supper.
- For two. Whom were you expecting?
- You. Put it there, Nanine.
I have learned never to believe a man
when he says he's leaving town.
- Won't you have something to eat?
- I'm not hungry.
Then drink something.
Come and drink with me.
- I'm not thirsty.
- I am.
- Many happy returns.
- Thank you.
This part is so difficult.
- I hate all the sharps.
- I'm afraid your mind's not on it.
Why, you know very well
I've never been able to play it.
- But you play it beautifully.
- My one merit.
- Won't you play it for me?
- Aren't you tired? It's very late.
- Probably are wishing I'd go home.
- Please play.
Oh, good, Nanine.
Bolt the door. If the bell rings,
don't answer it.
- No, I won't.
- Have you two finished whispering?
I'm sorry. I was just giving
Nanine some orders.
I don't doubt it.
Now, play nicely.
Someday I shall get temperamental and
object when doorbells ring when I play.
Did the doorbell ring?
Does my music shut out
the rest of the world for you?
- Yes. You play beautifully.
- You lie beautifully.
Thank you. That's more than I deserve.
It's not half as much
as you deserve, my dear.
- I'll see who it is.
- No, I'll tell you.
Yes?
- But you won't believe me.
- No, I won't. Who is it?
Well, I might say that there is someone
at the wrong door...
...or the great romance of my life.
The great romance of your life?
Charming.
Well, it might have been.
Let your godmother take your veil.
Oh, no, just a moment.
I want one more look at her.
The way she looked when she
made her first communion.
God keep you always so pure
and happy, my child.
Come, come and sit down.
And now, children,
on this happy occasion...
...I ask you all to rise and drink a toast
to the happiness of this family.
- We certainly will, sir.
- Oh, of course, a toast.
- To health and happiness.
- Health and happiness.
Now may I propose the happiness of my
sister and my friend, Louise and Valentine...
...who've known each other from childhood
and are soon to be man and wife.
- Louise and Valentine.
- Thank you, thank you.
Now, Ma, you must go in for your nap.
- Take my arm, Mama.
- Such a happy day.
Well, my boy, I'm glad you got down...
...even though you weren't in time
to go with us to the church.
I came for a purely selfish reason, Father.
- You in debt?
- No, no, it isn't that.
In love?
- Wrong again.
- Well, what then?
- I want to travel.
- Where?
Anywhere. Everywhere.
I'm tired of waiting for the office
to give me a post.
If I ever do get one, the more I know
the world, the better.
Well, it mightn't be a bad idea.
Your income won't let you go very far
in any great style.
- I could use some of the principal.
- You will do nothing of the sort.
Your grandfather's legacy
mustn't be touched.
However, I have a few thousand francs
I can spare.
- You mean, you'll give me the money?
- I don't know where else you'd get it.
You're not such a bad son.
When do you want to start?
At once. If I get back to Paris
tomorrow, the next morning.
Well...
Ready, Marguerite?
But we planned to go to the theater.
Why aren't you dressed?
- I've changed my mind, Prudence.
- Oh, come now, get dressed. I'll wait.
No, no, no.
Look, how do you spell "apology"?
Good gracious, how should I know?
I'm no scholar.
Even so, you've been living in Paris.
Six years ago, I couldn't even
write my own name.
Here's a letter which just came.
Perhaps Nanine knows how
to spell "apology. "
She asked me that once before today.
Is it the same apology?
Oh, don't bother. It isn't necessary now.
If that young man has made you unhappy,
he's the one who should spell "apology. "
It's all my fault.
He's going away, Prudence.
Stop your nonsense. He won't go.
They never do.
No, I think he means it.
And perhaps it's better.
But he had no right to write
such things to me.
Of course he didn't. Now, come along.
Let's go to the theater.
But first you'll stop at his place
and find out if he's really going away.
Why on earth does anyone
live four flights up?
- You've come with a message.
- Yes, I've got to sit down...
...before I can talk.
- From Mademoiselle Gautier?
- Yes.
Girl's a fool.
She wants to know if you're really
starting out to see the world...
...as you wrote her yesterday.
- Yes, it's true. I'm leaving in the morning.
- Good.
You and Marguerite are safer apart.
Didn't I tell you to wait in the carriage?
Oh, so you really are going away,
Armand Duval?
Yes.
Wait down in the carriage
yourself, Prudence.
Oh, very well,
since I'm not wanted here.
No, I think I'd better stay.
I think you'd better not.
- Oh, don't!
- Haven't got much time if you want it back.
Oh, don't. Don't, Marguerite.
Oh, what a girl. What a tease!
You wrote me an unkind letter.
What did you expect?
I saw the baron's carriage.
- You were jealous.
- Of course.
Well, then you do right in going away.
Well, what does it matter
whether I go or stay?
I played the fool again, and you've
probably been laughing at me ever since.
I didn't laugh at all.
I was angry because you dared write
such things to me, but I didn't laugh.
You should have known
it was because I loved you.
You know, once I had a little dog,
and he always looked sad when I was sad...
...and I loved him so.
And when your tears fell on my hand,
I loved you too all at once.
There are things that you wouldn't
understand, so that's why...
Who's that pretty girl?
My sister Louise.
- And the other one?
- Another sister.
- And that's your mother, isn't it?
- Yes.
How happy she looks.
- Does your father love her very much?
- Of course.
Why, they must've been married
a long time.
Nearly 30 years.
And they loved each other
all that time?
Yes. You sound as though
you didn't believe it.
It's hard to believe that there's
such happiness in this world.
Marguerite...
...now you've put tears on my hand.
Why?
You will never love me 30 years.
No one will.
I'll love you all my life.
I know that now.
All my life.
Sleepy head.
I wasn't asleep. I was dreaming.
- Yes?
- Of you.
- And?
- We were in the country, alone, far away.
I wish we were.
- Marguerite, let me take you to the country.
- Yes.
- Any day you like.
- I mean, let me take you for a long time.
Until you're well and strong again.
- Oh, what nonsense.
- Why is it nonsense?
- It costs money to go to the country.
- I have money.
Yes, how much?
Seven thousand francs a year.
I spend more than that in a month...
...and I have never been too particular
where it came from, as you probably know.
- Don't say such things.
- Well, it's true.
Give up the baron.
I must give you up.
I've told you before
that you should forget me.
So you go on your trip around the world
and put me out of your mind.
I thought I meant something to you.
You mean too much already.
But you're young,
and your life is before you.
You know what mine
has been already.
- It doesn't matter.
- Doesn't it?
Marguerite...
...you need love more than
you need money just now.
You need care even more than love.
I can take such good care of you,
if you'll let me.
You wouldn't be happy with me.
No, probably not.
Nor you with me.
I'll leave Paris today.
I was...
I was only thinking of you, my dear.
I wasn't thinking of myself, really.
Then come to the country with me.
Well, if I should, for a little while...
...promise not to be jealous and not to think
things that'll make you miserable.
Yes, I promise.
- Swear?
- I swear not to be jealous if you...
If...?
- If you swear not to see the baron again.
- No, you see?
- You will only torture yourself.
- But if you swear.
One hour from now, you will ask me
to swear about something else.
- You can't be sensible, Armand.
- It's true, I can't.
- I want too much.
- So do I.
How can one change one's entire life and
build a new one on one moment of love?
And yet that's what you make me
want to close my eyes and do.
Then close your eyes and say yes.
I command it.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
I'm going to tell him
that I love somebody else.
I'm going to the country for the summer...
...and I'm never going to see him again.
- Are you crazy?
You may be a fool, but I thought
you were an honest girl.
It's because she's honest
she's telling the baron they're through.
What about the money she owes?
Who's gonna pay it?
I knew you'd ruin yourself
and everybody who trusted you.
- How dare you say such things about her?
- It's true.
Doesn't she owe me, me personally,
more than 17,000 francs?
Do you think I'd let her leave Paris without
having the law on her unless she pays?
I'm going to the country just the same.
And what do you think will happen when
the rest of your creditors hear about it...
...and come down on Armand Duval
for your debts?
- They couldn't do that.
- Wait and see.
They'll be after you in a pack.
A pretty holiday you'll have.
Why can't anything ever be perfect once?
What shall I do, Prudence?
You can ask the baron
for money for your debts.
- Now that I'm going to leave him?
- You don't have to tell him everything.
She's right, Madame. If you've really set
your heart on going to the country...
...you've got to get some money
from someone, somehow.
What is the matter with you
anyway, Marguerite?
Have you suddenly become
a sentimental schoolgirl?
There's the baron now. The sooner
this matter's settled, the better.
Oh, my dear baron, hail and farewell.
I do hope you will encourage
this new plan of Marguerite's.
A few months in the country would do
her a world of good.
I know the doctor insists on it.
- Really?
- Yes.
- She'll tell you about it herself.
- I don't doubt it.
Busy?
Hello.
Don't you think these accounts
are in a beautiful order?
Beautiful.
- Do you think me very businesslike?
- Very.
But why?
I decided that these bills ought to be paid.
I owe 40,000 francs.
Will you lend me the money?
No.
Oh, but what will I do?
Come to Russia with me, and you can
have as much money as you want.
If you are my friend, why won't
you lend me the money anyway?
Because then you might have
no further use for me.
Well, I don't think you're very generous.
Prudence tells me you plan to go
to the country this summer.
Prudence is a chatterbox.
Living quietly two or three months
in the country, alone...
...obeying your doctor's orders,
sounds an admirable idea.
But extremely unlike you.
- What can you do about it?
- I can deliberately put you out of my mind.
Why should you?
It's become a question
of either avoiding you...
...or taking you
out of this life altogether.
What will you do with me? Lock me in that
gloomy chateau you've got somewhere?
I might.
No one has to tell me...
...you've found a playmate for this
rustic holiday of yours, it's in your face.
But my consolation is...
...I am well rid of such a fool.
Here's the 40,000 francs you need.
But this is my last act of consideration.
If ever we meet again,
it will be on a different basis.
I never make the same mistake twice.
Thank you.
Quiet! Quiet!
Let her sleep.
Oh, no.
You look after the other luggage.
I'll take care of these jewels myself.
- Yes, Madame.
- Thank you.
Not very big.
- It's not very grand.
- It's heaven.
- Madame, are you ill?
- No, why should I be ill?
Because you're awake at this early hour
in the morning.
I'm not ill. I'm awake
and I want to get up, Nanine.
Am I dreaming? Are we really here?
We are indeed.
If I'm not mistaken, you'll soon wish you
were in your comfortable house in Paris.
Monsieur Duval alone will see to that.
This place is nothing but a hut.
There are no gaslights, and you have
to fetch water from a reservoir...
...and heat it on a stove.
You can't sleep at night
on account of the birds...
...and before sunup, there was a big noise
like more birds, only worse.
Chickens, I suppose.
And as for that linen on the beds,
it's so coarse, I scratched all night.
And I never slept better
in my life, Nanine.
How far is it to the inn
where Monsieur Duval is staying?
How should I know, Madame?
Now, come, Nanine.
He said he'd be over early this morning.
And I'm so hungry too.
What delicious air.
What a heavenly room.
Good heavens, you scared me!
Can't you knock properly?
Not when I've got me hands full.
A wooden shoe makes a better noise
than your knuckles.
- Good morning, Madame.
- Good morning.
The gentleman said you were
to have milk for your breakfast.
Madame likes coffee for her breakfast.
No, no, Nanine. Up in the country,
I like milk better.
At 10:00, when it's time to have another
bite, I'll do you a couple of nice, fresh eggs.
- What kind of cows do you keep?
- Jersey.
I thought so, they give the best milk.
What do you feed them?
Plenty of red clover, hay and bran mash.
That's silly. The cows get
all the grass they need now.
The thing is not to let them
run their feet off.
- If they want to, you've got to let them run.
- Oh, no, you don't.
I'll take them out walking myself someday,
and I'll show you how to manage them.
- Tired?
- Only nicely tired.
Let's go as far as the top of the hill
and see what's beyond.
Yes.
I don't care what's behind, do you?
No.
Look!
Oh, what a fine sight in this light.
- It looks like a castle of a king.
- Yes.
When I was a little girl,
I always wanted to see...
...what a great chateau
would look like inside.
You are tired.
I'm not used to long country walks yet.
Hello!
- Good evening.
- Good evening, monsieur.
- Are you going any distance?
- As far as the village.
- Good. Could you drive us part of the way?
- With pleasure, monsieur.
- Madame.
- Thank you.
We went much further than we realized.
By the way, whose chateau is that?
You must be strangers here, or you'd know
it belongs to my master, Baron de Varville.
Nanine? Nanine.
Put the pail down.
I'll carry it for you in a moment.
- Hasn't any letter come for me yet?
- No, Madame.
Take this book, and if it comes while
I am with Monsieur Armand...
...put it in the leaves
and send the book by Jacques.
- Very well.
- Armand must not know about this.
Yes, Madame.
Oh, give me the book.
I'll explain to Jacques myself.
- She has some good reason, monsieur.
- Yes, I'm sure of that.
Oh, there you are.
Isn't it the most beautiful day?
Is it so beautiful?
Well, the birds have noticed it.
- Why so silent?
- Why not?
Let's sit down here.
How good the earth smells.
Better than any perfume.
Look, I found a four-leaf clover.
My first good luck.
When I was little, I used to hunt for them,
thinking they would change everything.
Why so gloomy?
If you'll smile, I'll give it to you.
- No, you keep it, it's yours.
- Excuse me.
- This is the book Madame was looking for...
- Oh, yes, thank you, Jacques.
- So you're reading Manon Lescaut after all.
- Yes.
- No, I won't let you.
- Why not?
Because she was unscrupulous
and faithless, a liar and a cheat.
Well, you used to like her.
She loved him just the same.
He was no better than she
to share her love with others.
- Beggars can't be choosers.
- She shouldn't love a poor man.
You're hurting me.
Give me that book.
Here's the letter you were expecting.
Read it.
You've been selling your jewelry.
Only a ring. So Nichette can have
a wedding dress and a small dowry.
Forgive me.
- Don't I always when you are jealous?
- You're an angel.
Why don't we give Nichette
a real wedding here.
- May I?
- Of course.
Let's write Nichette this moment
and tell her we'll give her a wedding.
- Will you come and spell the hard words?
- Yes.
Amen.
- "With this ring, I thee wed. "
- With this ring, I thee wed.
- "And I plight unto thee my troth. "
- And I plight unto thee my troth.
Amen.
- "With this ring, I thee wed. "
- With this ring, I thee wed.
- "And I plight unto thee my troth. "
- And I plight unto thee my troth.
Amen.
Congratulations, my boy!
My dear! Oh, what a pity all Paris
can't see that dress.
It's the prettiest one
we've ever turned out of the shop.
- Oh, congratulations, my dear.
- Thank you.
Why is everybody crying?
Wasn't it beautiful?
Wasn't it all beautiful?
- Who are you?
- I'm the butcher, Madame.
Darling Marguerite.
- Oh, thank you. Thank you so much.
- My little Nichette.
You've made me feel like a princess
with a fine wedding gown...
...and a dowry and such
a beautiful, beautiful wedding.
- I must kiss the bride too.
- And I, the happy bridegroom.
- Ready at last. Come along, come along.
- Don't hurry me.
Wine used to go to my head
and make me gay...
...and now it goes to my legs
and makes me old.
- Get along, get along.
- Goodbye.
What did you and Prudence have
your heads together about so long?
I won't tell you yet.
Of course, she thinks you're a fool
for wasting yourself on me.
Perhaps you are.
What did Gaston mean by
"an appointment you'd lost"?
Nothing. Some chap was given
a post by the foreign office...
...that Gaston seemed to think I wanted.
- Are you sure you didn't?
- Yes, quite sure.
It meant my leaving France.
Shall we...? Shall we go inside?
We might go to the top of the hill.
- Look at the baron's chateau?
- No.
Are you going to spoil a day like this
by being jealous?
No, of course not. Only...
...I always know he's there.
But I'm always here.
Don't ever leave me.
I never will.
But you...
- I can't bear our summer to end, Marguerite.
- Nor I.
- Could you go on living like this?
- I couldn't live any other way now.
Listen, I've written my father,
asking him to turn my money over to me.
- Oh, why?
- So I can make plans for our future.
And you won't have to live in two rooms
five flights up like Nichette either.
You'll have a little house
in the garden, all your own.
I'm leaving for Paris tomorrow to see
the lawyer who made my grandfather's will.
- Do you know what I asked Prudence to do?
- No, what?
Sell everything, pay everything.
So I could take a flat like Nichette's
with what I have left.
Really? You mean you'd give up
everything for me?
Everything in the world. Everything.
Never be jealous again. Never doubt
that I love you more than the world...
...more than myself.
Then...
...marry me.
- What?
- I married you today.
Every word the priest said
was meant for us...
...and in my heart,
I made all of the vows to you.
- And I to you.
- Then...
No, no. That isn't fitting.
Let me love you. Let me live for you.
Don't let me ask any more
from heaven than that.
God might get angry.
Oh, why does anybody want
to keep bees, anyhow? They're so fickle.
If they want to fly away, let them.
They'll fly away when they
get the swarming fever...
...unless we make so much noise
they settle down again.
They're going to settle in that tree.
Look.
Every time I eat a mouthful of honey,
I'll think what loons we look doing this.
Who knows the bee song?
All together now.
Please don't think us mad, monsieur.
Did you want to see someone?
- Mademoiselle Gautier?
- Yes.
I was told at the inn
that I'd find my son here.
- Your son?
- Armand Duval.
Yes, Armand Duval is very often here,
but he's in Paris today.
- Do you wish to come in?
- Thank you.
I'm sorry your son isn't here, monsieur.
Well, it's just as well.
I didn't look forward to seeing him
with any pleasure, under the circumstances.
As a matter of fact, I'm glad to be able
to talk to you directly and frankly.
You see, I know
what's been going on here.
You don't think me worthy of your son.
You're right, I'm not.
No. No woman is worthy
of a man's love...
...who's willing to let him ruin himself
for her, as you're doing.
I don't know what you've heard,
but it isn't true.
Armand has told me himself...
...that he wants to take his modest fortune
out of my hands at once.
The reason is obvious, isn't it?
Can you deny he wants the money
for you?
Whatever the reason, I hope
you won't let him have it, monsieur.
I wish I could believe you were sincere.
A few years ago,
I lived on bread and soup.
I can manage very well without
taking anything from Armand.
I still say what I came here to say.
This thing must end at once.
You might as well
save your breath, monsieur.
How long have you
known Armand, Madame?
Three months and 12 days, monsieur.
Three months and 12 days. And how long
do you expect this thing to last?
You have never known love
to last, monsieur?
Never, when it was
unsanctified by marriage...
...unblessed by children or social ties.
I shall love Armand always, and I
believe he shall love me always too.
- Always, eh?
- Always.
Hasn't your own experience taught you
the human heart can't be trusted?
I think I know my own heart
better than you can, monsieur.
And I can trust it not to change.
No woman, unprotected as you are, can
afford to give the best years of her life...
...to a man who, when he leaves her,
will leave her with nothing...
...and who is certain to leave her
in the end.
I don't suppose you can understand
how any woman...
...unprotected, as you say I am,
can be lifted above self-interest...
...by a sentiment so delicate and pure
that she feels only humiliation...
...when you speak of such things.
I realize now that you
do love him unselfishly.
But even so, I say it can't go on.
- But it will go on!
- Armand is a young man...
...with his way to make,
with a career waiting for him.
And in his case, he can't serve
his best interests by being tied...
...to a woman he can't present
to his family or his friends.
- Armand is no different than other men.
- Oh, come, Madame.
Be honest.
Haven't you found him different?
Haven't you found him
more sensitive, more loyal?
Or am I prejudiced
because I'm his father?
No. No, no. Armand is different.
And so you see, as long as Armand loves
you, he'll not enter rooms that you can't.
But a man can go back.
He can always go back.
Monsieur...
...suppose I told you I have a feeling
I shan't live very long?
Well, then I'd scold you for being fanciful
and a little foolish.
What you probably feel
is the melancholy of happiness...
...that mood that comes over
all of us when we realize...
...that even love can't remain
at flood tide forever.
- Without Armand, I'm doomed.
- With him, you're both doomed.
Without a profession of any sort,
what can he do?
Unless he sinks so low
he's willing to let some other man...
...foot the bills for his life with you.
You don't know Armand.
You wouldn't say that.
No one knows the man he might become
if he loses his self-respect.
But I think that's too high
a price to pay, even for love.
I want Armand to enjoy life,
not to be sacrificed to it.
You see, my son is as dear to me
as he possibly can be to you.
Yes, but you have others
who are dear to you.
I have only Armand.
You don't know how I've changed.
And he taught me that love is not
always selfish, nor goodness dull...
...nor men faithless. No, no. You can't
expect me to give up such love as his.
Think what's best for him.
Think what you'd want for him
if he were your own son.
Then think how you're killing
his right to a normal life.
Try to realize that everything
you're ashamed of in your own past...
...would only taint his future.
You tell me that you love him.
I believe you.
That's why I'm able to stand here,
a man who's getting old...
...and ask this great sacrifice of you...
...as humbly as I'd ask
a great favor of a queen.
I can give you nothing in return,
except my thanks and my respect.
Please give him up.
- What shall I do?
- Talk to him. Tell him he must leave you.
- I have talked.
- Leave him.
- He'd follow me.
- Tell him you don't love him.
He wouldn't believe me.
No.
I know only one way.
But I shan't tell you what it is.
I knew I was too happy.
What are you going to do?
Don't let yourself think of it.
I'll send him back to you tonight.
How can I ever repay you
for all you're doing for me?
Make no mistake, monsieur.
Whatever I do, it's nothing for you.
- It's all for Armand.
- I thank you just the same.
And I shall never forget
what I and my family owe you.
Goodbye, monsieur.
Don't reproach yourself.
You've done only what Armand's father
should have done.
Only, don't let him know it.
He might hate you.
And I don't want that to happen...
...because he shall need all the courage
and comfort you can give him...
...for a long time, I think.
God bless you, Marguerite Gautier.
Did the gentleman go?
But, Madame, what's the matter?
I want you to take this letter
and give it to Baron de Varville yourself.
But I thought you were so happy
at last with Monsieur Duval.
I was.
I don't know what's in it...
...but I know the very thought
of this one makes you shudder.
Are you sure you want me to take it?
Yes, yes. Go now, Nanine.
And pray for me.
Pray for me that I'll have the strength
to go through with what I have to do.
Oh, your hands are like ice, child.
Tell Nanine what you're going to do.
Make my love hate me.
Make him hate me.
Oh, God help me.
Hello. I'm back.
Oh, I didn't hear you drive up.
Why are you all dressed up?
Not going to a ball, are you?
No. I wish I were. You don't know
of any balls I might be asked to, do you?
- If you're serious, I brought an invitation.
- Really?
From Olympe. There's a new gambling club
opening. She suggests we go together.
Where did you see Olympe?
She dropped in the shop while I was
talking to Prudence about your affairs.
I didn't ask you to discuss my affairs
with Prudence.
And I did ask her not
to talk to you about them.
Marguerite, you're angry.
Do you realize that
we're almost quarreling?
Well, everybody quarrels.
It keeps people from getting bored.
Something happened today.
What was it? I want the truth.
Well, this morning,
the bees left the hive...
...and we had to bring them back.
This afternoon, I washed my hair.
Those are the two exciting events
of my day.
The first time I leave you,
you change completely.
I come back to you happy,
with good news.
What do you call good news?
Have you been left a large fortune?
No, but I find I can do
as I please with my small one.
Well, don't you touch it.
Why, you'll be rich one month
and then have nothing.
If that's what you're afraid of,
you needn't worry.
We have something better to do than play
at being rich, even for a month.
Nichette and Gustave are already
looking for a house for us.
They're the sort of people
that think two rooms wonderful...
...three rooms a mansion,
and more than four rooms wicked.
What's the matter?
That's what I'm wondering.
Oh, darling, darling.
I'd begun to think you didn't love me.
Perhaps I don't really.
Yet only last night you were ready
to give up everything for me.
Well, that was last night, you know.
People say things they don't mean
sometimes at night.
Well, life is something besides kisses
and promises in the moonlight.
Even you should know that.
Yes.
Wasn't one summer all you wanted?
So you're going to leave me.
Yes.
- I could kill you for this.
- I'm not worth killing, Armand.
I've loved you as much as I could love.
If that wasn't enough...
...I'm not to blame.
We don't make our own hearts.
I guess that's...
That's true.
You're no more to blame because yours
can be faithful only a few weeks...
...than I am because mine
will be faithful as long as I live.
Yes, that's how it is.
It's as if one of us had died,
Marguerite, suddenly or I dreamed it.
Where are you going?
Baron de Varville is expecting me.
At last I shall see what a great chateau
looks like inside.
Marguerite.
And this, Madame, is the newest and finest
of all the private gambling clubs in Paris.
I hope you're impressed.
Must be a pleasure to lose money in such
a charming place. I wonder who's here.
Everyone who's anything to lose,
or nothing.
Am I dreaming, or do I see
a flock of birds?
No, it's Olympe.
- Hello, darling. Good evening, general.
- Good evening, general.
Would anybody like an omelet?
Stop that, you nasty thing.
Pardon us. The general wants to play.
So nice to have seen you.
- Well, what I could say about that one.
- There's Armand Duval.
Armand, my boy.
Hello, Prudence.
- How well you're looking.
- I return the compliment.
I... I think I ought to warn you.
Marguerite is coming here tonight
with the baron.
Well...
These things can't last forever.
Your little adventure was costing
Marguerite more than she could afford.
- It cost her nothing.
- Oh, what a child you are.
Who do you think furnished the money
for Marguerite's debts before she left Paris?
What do you think would've happened if
she hadn't left you...
...when her money was gone?
And now?
The baron has promised
to put her affairs in perfect order.
Good.
Then you don't really hold it against her?
No, why should I? The past is dead.
Heaven rest its soul, if it had one.
You have more sense
than I gave you credit for.
Hello.
- Armand.
- Hello, Charles.
- Hello, Gaston.
- Hello.
Well, when did you get back to Pa...?
To Paris?
You've dropped your fan.
I said, you've dropped your fan.
- I don't feel well. I'd like to go home.
- I insist on your staying. Come.
I'm so glad you've come, dear.
Good evening, baron.
- Good evening.
- Of course, you know each other.
- Monsieur Duval?
- No.
You're late.
- We went to the theater.
- What was the play?
- Manon Lescaut.
- Oh, yes.
The story of a man who loved a woman
more than his honor...
...and a woman who wanted luxury
more than his love.
You should have found that
very entertaining.
Isn't that your tune, Marguerite?
Madame, you've dropped your fan.
- Thank you.
- Any gentleman would've done the same.
Aren't you playing, baron?
- Where is the baccarat table?
- Yes, Gaston, where is it?
- Straight ahead.
- I play for high stakes.
Good. I should like to make
a fortune tonight.
- Come, Marguerite.
- I'd rather not play, if you don't mind.
You can watch.
I can't watch, Prudence. Armand may lose.
He may lose everything, and it's my fault.
You needn't worry, dear.
He doesn't blame you at all.
That isn't true. His voice is too cold
and his face is too pale.
Monsieur le Baron wins.
- Can I get Madame anything?
- No, thank you.
Yes. Will you take a message
to Monsieur Armand Duval?
Tell him I would like to speak to him.
- How will I know the gentleman?
- Well, he's playing at the first table...
...and he's the youngest
and handsomest man there.
I'll find him, Madame.
- Nine, the right side wins.
- Congratulations, monsieur.
Well done, Armand.
Twenty thousand francs.
- Twenty thousand?
- Place your bets, gentlemen.
Armand wins again.
He drew nine three times.
Well done, well done.
Let it stand.
- You'll lose it all.
- Let it stand.
- Good. You owe me revenge.
- Take it if you can.
Only, I warn you,
lucky in love, unlucky at cards.
That also means
lucky at cards, unlucky in love.
- We shall see.
- Make your bets, please, gentlemen.
Card.
No card.
- Eight.
- Seven.
Baccarat!
You've won a fortune, Armand.
Make your bets, gentlemen.
Make your bets.
Pardon me.
You sent for me, Madame?
Yes. I want to beg you,
leave this place at once.
- Why?
- Baron de Varville is not a patient man...
...and you're in the mood
to quarrel tonight.
You don't want to lose
your rich admirer. I understand.
Your own fortunes would fall with him.
Armand, he's not to blame
for what happened. That I swear.
Then how could you do what you did?
I'll tell you. Because your heart is a thing
that can be bought and sold.
I know, you gave it to me
for a whole summer.
When it came to a choice, the jewels
and carriages he could give you...
...were worth more than my love,
my devotion, my life.
Yes, that's true.
I'm a completely worthless woman,
and no man should risk his life for me.
For that reason alone, I beg you,
leave this place at once.
I will.
I will, on one condition.
That you'll go with me.
No.
I came back to Paris to tell you
that I despise you, and I do.
But I love you too. Say you'll go away
with me. We'll forget the past.
- We'll never turn back.
- No, no.
I doubled my fortune tonight
at his expense.
And when that's gone, I'll work,
I'll beg, I'll borrow, I'll steal.
But I must be with you always, always.
When I hear you talk of such a future,
I realize I'm right in doing what I did.
Look, do you suppose
we could ever be happy together...
...even if I were free to act as I choose?
- You are free.
I've given a solemn promise
never to return to you.
To whom?
- To someone who had the right to ask.
- To the Baron de Varville?
- Yes.
- So you do love him.
Dare to tell me that you love him,
you're free of me forever.
I love him.
Come in! Come in here, all of you!
You see this woman? You know her?
Then listen to what I'm going to say.
I accepted her favors
because I thought she loved me.
I let her make sacrifices when there
were others who had more to give.
But bear witness, I owe her nothing.
Take it. Go on, take it!
Buy camellias. Buy diamonds, horses
and carriages! Buy moonlight! Buy a grave!
I congratulate you, monsieur. You know
how to treat a woman as she deserves.
Like the cheat this one is.
You shall answer to me for this!
Send me word when and where.
- Come, gentlemen, let's continue our play.
- Come, come, the game is continuing.
Place your bets, gentlemen.
Please, please make your bets.
He's safe.
Thank God. Oh, thank God.
But the baron is wounded.
That means Armand must leave the country
to avoid arrest. He's already on his way.
- My letter?
- I'm sorry. He sent it back.
He wouldn't open it.
Who's here we know?
- Oh, there's someone now.
- Come in.
- Armand!
- Armand Duval!
- Well...
- Do sit down.
- When did you get back to Paris?
- About a week ago.
- Why hasn't anyone seen you?
- Where have you been, anyhow?
- All sorts of places.
- It's good you didn't kill the baron...
...and have to stay away for years instead
of months. Have you seen Marguerite?
- Oh, I'm sorry, I meant...
- Well.
How does Paris look to the traveler?
The same as it looked six months ago.
The same girls singing the same song
on the same stage.
And I'm still wearing
the same dress, alas.
Don't hint.
Nobody's going to buy you a new one.
Only, Marguerite isn't here.
However, I suppose
there are worse places.
- I said, Marguerite isn't here.
- Don't shout. We all heard you.
- Do you know she's been ill, Armand?
- Stop teasing Armand, Gaston.
Can't you see that he isn't interested?
- Aren't you?
- No, not particularly.
After all, why should he be?
It's nothing new.
Marguerite is always ill
or pretending to be.
You really have a nasty tongue,
haven't you?
Why, if you mean to insinuate
that I haven't been a good friend...
...to Marguerite Gautier, ask Prudence
what I've done for her. Just ask her.
It's true. That angel has been buying
Marguerite's things, all of her jewelry...
...one after another.
- Look.
- Why?
- So she could raise some money.
Since the duel with the baron,
he's refused to see her.
Shut up, Olympe. I know more
about that than you do.
Marguerite won't see the baron,
or any other man who might help her...
...in spite of all my motherly advice.
- Well, that's what you say.
Only, this... Last week, I bought this.
Look.
Oh, you couldn't get it for 5000
at the jewelers. How much?
Two hundred Louis. Am I smart.
Shall we go around afterwards
and ask how she is?
No.
I couldn't.
- Hello, Nanine.
- Monsieur.
- How is she tonight?
- Oh, I don't know, monsieur.
The doctor tells me nothing.
Oh, forgive me, monsieur,
but these are bad times.
- There must be something I can do.
- There's nothing anybody can do...
...but watch and wait.
- Well, I'll watch and wait...
...while you get some rest.
- Gave yourself all the good cards.
You'll have to get out of here,
my men.
We're here for the creditors,
by order of the court...
...to see that nothing's taken out of
the house, and here we're going to stay.
There's a passage outside.
Wait there instead.
This room still belongs
to Mademoiselle Gautier.
- Our orders are to see...
- You can see nobody goes out that door...
...with a piano in his pocket
as well there as here. Get out.
Get out.
Lie down.
I'll call you the minute she stirs.
- Is it morning?
- Yes, dear child.
- Any letters?
- No. It's too early for the postman.
Who are you?
Gaston.
Nanine's sleeping. I made her lie down
when I looked in after the theater.
Dear Gaston.
So you've been here all night?
Well, I was thinking of taking you
for a drive, or maybe for a bit of lunch.
You still make me laugh.
Not today. Some other time.
All right, another time.
How kind you are.
You know, I used to think
you were such a gay fellow...
...with no other thought but for pleasure.
Forgive me.
But you were right.
Here, drink this.
It'll do you good.
Nothing will do me good anymore,
Gaston, except Armand's return.
- Armand's return?
- Yes.
That's what I'm waiting for.
That's why I live.
- He will come back, won't he, Gaston?
- Of course he'll come back.
How could he come to Paris
without coming straight to you?
Here, drink this.
I feel better already.
It's all right, Nanine. She's awake.
- Poor Nanine. Were you tired last night?
- Oh, a little, Madame.
That Madame Prudence is here
on her way home from a party.
I'll get rid of her.
So that's why you ran away from us,
you naughty boy.
Hello, my child.
Why, I expected to find you dying,
and you look better...
...than I've seen you look for months.
How are you?
- Much better.
- You certainly look better than I feel.
Oh, heavens, what worries I've had
this past week.
I couldn't, by any chance,
borrow some money from you, could I?
If you don't know how little money
there is in this house, you should.
Well, I've simply got to get 200 francs
from somewhere.
I didn't intend to ask you for it. In fact,
I didn't intend popping in on you like this...
...but as I passed your door,
I just remembered you still owe me some.
- I didn't know, Prudence.
- I can show it to you on my ledger.
If you look around,
you'll find my purse somewhere.
You'll see I haven't
but a few francs in the world.
Why, it's full.
A thousand francs.
Well, I'll just help myself.
Did you know Armand Duval
was in Paris?
Armand?
- When did he get back?
- Why, almost a week, I gather.
Gaston told him you were ill,
but he didn't seem terribly interested.
Oh, men are funny. Goodbye, my dear.
Goodbye, Gaston. Goodbye.
- Gaston?
- Yes?
- Thank you for filling my purse.
- That was nothing.
- Will you do me one more favor, Gaston?
- Of course.
Send for the priest.
Where is she? Let me see her.
Make her see me.
Oh, my dear boy, if you only knew
how happy, how happy...
- Nanine? It's not too late?
- No, no, let us hope not.
Let us hope you'll make her well again.
No, no, no, wait.
Let me prepare her first.
Madame.
I've good news, Madame.
There can't be any good news now.
But there is. Only, you must be calm.
You mustn't get excited.
- He's here, Madame. He's come back.
- Yes...
...he's back.
- But he won't come to see me.
- But he has come. He's here.
He's here, Madame.
He's here?
- Are you telling me the truth?
- Yes, yes.
- Only, be calm, and I'll call him.
- No, no. Not yet.
He mustn't see me like this, Nanine.
- Help me to the mirror.
- You mustn't think of getting out of bed.
Brush my hair. Get me some rouge.
Help me, Nanine.
No, no. What will the doctor say?
Oh, what does it matter?
I must look my...
Nanine.
Nanine. I beg you, Nanine, I must...
You must help me, Nanine. Come on.
I beg you, Nanine. I beg...
Come, Nanine.
Oh, I shouldn't do this.
You don't think he cares how you look.
He knows you've been ill.
You always said, "He'll come back,"
didn't you, Nanine?
Yes.
- Sit here.
- Yes.
Sit here.
- There. Here are all your things.
- My camellias.
Nanine, I'll even have camellias.
I'll be beautiful again
when I'll be well again, won't I, Nanine?
Of course.
I can't wait. Call him now, Nanine.
Call him now.
Yes.
Monsieur.
- Marguerite.
- Armand.
Marguerite!
- It's you. It's not a dream.
- No, no, it's not a dream.
- I'm here with you in my arms at last.
- At last.
- You're weak.
- No, no, I'm strong.
It's my heart. It's not used
to being happy.
Oh, how pretty you are.
I've been in the street half the night,
walking under your window...
...just as I did when I first knew you,
wanting to come up but not daring to.
I felt so guilty.
I didn't know how ill you were.
I've been everywhere trying
to forget I loved you.
And when I came back a week ago,
I was still determined to forget you.
Forget you, as if I could.
- Forgive me.
- Forgive you.
And to think I couldn't see
into this heart I knew so well...
...and see that it was
sacrificing itself for me.
No good can come to either of us
without the other. I know that now.
- I know that too.
- Nothing shall ever separate us again.
The future is ours.
My whole life belongs to you.
I'll take you far from Paris, where there
are no unhappy memories for us.
Where the sun will help me take care
of you and make you well.
We will go back to the country,
where we were happy all one summer.
Oh, if only we could. If only we could.
We can. We will,
as soon as you're well enough.
Well, I'm well now. Call Nanine.
- Nanine?
- Take me today.
Nanine? Nanine, help Madame to dress.
We're going to the country today.
Don't worry. I'll take good care of her.
You must come along too.
We're going to the country, Nanine.
Get my things out.
Don't stare at me, Nanine. Go.
I can't...
Nanine? Nanine.
Nanine, get the doctor, quickly!
The doctor?
If you can't make me live,
how can he?
No, no. Don't say such things, Marguerite.
You'll live. You must live.
Perhaps it's better if I live in your heart,
where the world can't see me.
If I'm dead, there'll be no stain
on our love.
Don't think such things, Marguerite.
Even if we can't go
to the country today...
...think of how happy we were once,
and how happy we shall be again.
Think of the day you found the clover,
and the good luck it's going to bring us.
Think of the vows we heard
Nichette and Gustave make...
...and that we're going to make
to each other.
This is for life, Marguerite...
Marguerite?
No. No, don't leave me.
Marguerite, come back, come back.