Hello! You are here by yourself?
Alright. Let it down.
Bring it down slowly.
Slowly.
Give it to me.
Slow down.
It's too fast for them to shoot.
No. It's like a construction site.
You take it down, and that's all.
How many floors today?
Every floor.
I'm going to wash my hands.
Wash my hands so that...
Yes, everything, including the frame.
Hey, hey.
Let's film this guy more.
Shoot him more
- Still won't shut up.
- At first,
I didn't remember
you were Sakchai's daughter.
What? Really?
This is Sakchai's daughter.
I don't remember at all.
It's been so many years. How's miss Leka?
- She's getting old now.
- Really?
- Can she walk?
- She manages.
You live with her, right?
Do you still live with miss Leka?
She changed a lot.
Completely different.
I remember her
as a little girl with glasses.
Her face changed after she's grown.
I think every cinema bans cats.
But the multiplex cinemas in the shopping
malls might not have such problems.
In the Siam cinema projection box,
there's a sign on the door to the rooftop
that says, "keep cats out."
One day, I found a cat
staring at me at my bedroom door,
which means it would have had to walk
through the entire projection box.
We stared into
each other's eyes for a while
before I kicked it out
so no one would notice.
Even with a label saying,
"do not feed the cats,"
Auntie Cha-Um, the office janitor,
would just keep feeding them
on the rooftops anyways.
It's stuck. I can't take it off.
Do we still have to drive the cats out?
No, not anymore
Does your dad know
that they're tearing down Scala?
Have you talked to him?
No calls?
I meant to call him too,
but I got too busy.
I think it was in late 1973.
It was 40, 45 years ago.
Around 1974.
In the beginning,
the Scala had 1,200 seats.
It was the biggest one.
Siam Cinema had 900 seats.
The Lido Theater had 1,000 seats.
This cinema had the most.
I think it's the end
of that October protest.
So I started working here
at the end of 1973.
It was December, I remember.
But I actually was working
at Samyan cinema first.
- Samyan?
- Samyan.
It's the place where...
There were Samyan cinemas
next to Hua Lamphong temple.
You didn't know?
It's a cinema screening Chinese movies.
There are the Samyan and Rama cinemas.
I worked there for over a year
before moving to Lido in 1975.
I remember seeing you
and your father always arguing
when I was working at the Siam Cinema.
At first, you guys were able to
talk normally, and soon started arguing.
That's why Ms. Leka always said,
"If you can't take care of her,
give her to me. I will do it myself!"
That's what she said.
He was an ill-tempered man.
He did not want your mother
to see or meet you.
It's like he doesn't want you
to contact each other.
So he had to...
That's why you never saw her.
I don't have a picture of her either.
Back then, what should I say?
Taking pictures wasn't easy.
Uncle Nao was
a projectionist at Siam cinema.
It was at the Siam cinema projection box
where I first met him.
I don't remember
when I started living in the Siam cinema.
Before I knew it,
I was already running around the place.
But the Lido and the Scala,
I didn't really visit so much back then
unless there was a film I wanted to see
that was not shown at our cinema.
Although the Scala
may look prettier than her sisters,
I didn't feel that they were
so different on the inside.
Go, go.
Stop.
They've been here since 8:30 a.m.
They didn't have the scaffoldings.
They just started taking them off.
Yes, but...
Yes, someone's assisting him.
Yes, it seems all right now.
At this corner
of the Siam cinema projection room,
there was a door to our bedroom.
Our bed lied underneath
the huge air tubes.
My sheets were the same fabric
as the curtains at the cinema's entrance.
I remember because I liked to run
and brush these curtains with my hands
while waiting for The Royal Anthem to end
so I could enjoy the film right away.
They can't start pulling the curtains down
because it might rip something.
- They're expensive curtains.
- There's a procedure!
- They're fireproof.
- No, it's...
- No, just remove the hoops!
- Right.
- Ready?
- Okay!
- I will do it in slow-motion, okay?
One, two, three.
Maybe it can be recycled
into a prosthetic leg.
- No, it's metal.
- It can't be.
- It's metal?
- Metal!
It will rust.
- I thought it was aluminum.
- You sure?
Damn, it's metal.
- You want to get tetanus?
- Right.
- Where's Yod?
- Come here.
- Why don't you turn the light on?
- Pull it.
Can we rest a bit?
Let's take a break.
How about pulling this way?
No, you have to go in an angle that way.
The rope broke.
Even the rope broke.
That's the last of it.
Just move the rest of the curtains.
Are you making a review video?
No, more like a documentary film.
It's sad, isn't it?
Some say they used to come here
when they were a child.
People in their 30s
saying they used to come to the Scala.
Some older folks came here,
just realizing that it's being demolished,
and would say they came here since
they were in their teens.
Well, times changed.
Things have to change too.
What was new became something newer.
Your side down, that side lifts.
- That side first.
- Lift.
Don't lift yet! Don't lift yet!
If you're not ready, just don't do it.
Wait, wait.
No one below to catch?
- No.
Did you see that court order?
The opposition party won the vote
but did not get a seat.
Just because
he makes small merits with the monks.
Now the election committee just revoked
his seat in the parliament.
How much did Yod win in the lotto?
Three hundred?
- This?
- This one first.
Take it here.
Where to go?
- Where?
- Right here.
It's just a frame.
So, I went to work with uncle Saiyud
at the Siam theater.
Back then, all the Siam staff had quit.
I think it was Sompoj, right?
Sompoj.
I was sent to help Sompoj,
and then I came back here.
I remember seeing you
walk to school back then.
THIS SITE, THEREFORE, HOLDS A HISTORICAL
IMPORTANCE IN THAI FILM HISTORY.
THIS PLAQUE WAS INSTALLED HERE
ON WORLD AUDIOVISUAL HERITAGE DAY.
OCTOBER 27TH, 2019
It was only after the cinema closed
that I know how to change the lights.
- Let me see.
- And now I'm an electrician.
You still got it.
Yes, but getting soft now.
Just learning to be an electrician now.
How disappointed my parents would be.
They said that to Gen.
That's all you get
from working in Bangkok?
Hold this, then. Yes, climb up.
- Pull?
- No, you hold it from the right. Yes.
Hang on, give me a second.
Big hammer go up.
Hold it like this
- Hey.
- Blackout again?
- Blackout again.
- Just let it go. I can't see.
- Okay.
I can't see. Can you see, Gap?
Who hit the light switch?
The cinema employees were both Bangkokians
and people from other provinces.
Most of them are probably
from the Northeastern region.
When I first came,
I couldn't understand their dialect much.
I started to understand after a while.
Back when there were still
a lot of employees,
at the end of the day, we would turn off
the air conditioners, close the doors,
and spread out the sheet
to sleep in front of the screen.
The air remained cool
until the next morning.
We can talk about this...
I love him because he said...
it's not about gender...
Don't know who won the lottery.
PEKING DUCK
Gen and Nao.
And...
Lee and Apaiwong.
How about Arun?
Nao and Yo.
- Arun?
- Arun is reporting for unemployment.
I attended primary school
at Wat Pathum Wanaram.
Most of my friends are descendants of
the people who work around the Siam area.
Some of them have homes
in the slums next to the school.
One day, when I was in fourth grade,
a friend shouted
that my house was on fire.
We saw a huge smoke
rising from Siam Square.
But I think the smoke
was most likely coming from the Lido.
After school,
I hurried back to the Siam cinema,
and turns out it was safe.
After the fire, the Lido was renovated
into a three-screen multiplex cinema.
Oh, your camera is set up already.
- Have you eaten yet?
- No.
No? Not hungry?
I'll eat later.
DO NOT ENTER WITHOUT PERMISSION
I just bought bread
but gave it all to the others.
You can use the toilet too.
Come, have some hot Ovaltine.
It's still warm.
Oh, thank you.
Someone brought me this cookie.
It's quite good. Crispy and yummy.
It's their snack.
Aunt Sarai brought it for them.
They won a lotto, so they brought some.
They actually won the lotto.
They are so cute. And clever too.
They will give whatever you ask for.
They're cute, aren't they?
Back then, the aunties in the office
would bring food just like this.
Auntie Ree, the head of the ticket office,
liked making stewed eggs,
while auntie Leka, the accountant,
always brought steamed buns.
I spent most of the time with those
office aunties while Dad was at work.
At first, it was them
who brought me to the cinema.
Now that I've grown up,
I prefer to go alone.
OUTSIDERS ARE PROHIBITED FROM ENTERING.
BIRDS OF PREY
I'm almost 60 years old.
Who would hire someone this old?
So there is a saying
that over the age of 50,
one can only be a security guard.
But I can't stay awake that long.
Too exhausting.
So I have to stay as long as possible
before everyone departs back home.
Your father
started working here before me.
Did my father use to work at Scala first?
Your dad worked
at the APEX company right over there.
He was...
a programmer. He booked films.
His duties were different.
Your dad's office was over there.
APEX was there.
He took the film
to the censorship department,
then to the film labs,
and then to the cinemas.
But I started as an usher.
I used to wear the yellow jackets.
I'm that old.
From usher to the chief.
It took me 51 years.
Back then, we were just like any teenager.
We ate, drank, and hung out,
just like any normal teenager.
And your mom worked
at the snack bar in her yellow uniform.
The rope can't take the weight.
It'll cut your hand if you pull it.
- This is dangerous work, you know.
- Be careful.
We all came after it opened.
How could we know?
Even Gap's dad didn't know.
He came after the cinema opened.
- After the cinema opened?
- Yes.
Who knows who built this screen.
But the guy
who brought the chandelier might know.
- Right, the owner of this thing.
- Girl.
- Yes, the chandelier's owner.
- I saw...
I saw him on the last day
of the screening. He could barely walk.
Yes, he is that generation.
Pull it away, Nao, Yod.
Pull away. It's stuck here.
Go sideways.
Hey, do you mind if I ask you something?
Have you met your mother?
- No.
- No?
- Not since you were very young, right?
- Have you ever met my mother?
Yes, I used to visit her at her house.
The house near the mosque.
I remember your mother had very fair skin.
- She is from Phetchaburi, right?
- I don't know.
Don't you know?
I've seen her live there.
Disassemble this first.
- Come here first.
- Shall I disassemble it?
Can it disassemble?
Or should we move it like that?
It can't.
Move it.
Where's that cat that likes taking photos?
Probably got startled and ran away.
There were two large windows
in the Siam cinema office.
From there,
you can see almost everyone downstairs.
Next to the window was a table.
There were six phones on the table.
When it rang and no one was around,
I would answer
and give some general information,
such as the showtimes.
One day,
auntie Ree brought me to that window.
She pointed down to the popcorn cabinet
and asked if I could see my mom.
"She's standing right there."
I think I was becoming short-sighted then.
All I saw was a blurry shape of a person.
Auntie Ree also told me not to tell
my father about what had just happened.
I was very curious
what would happen if he found out.
So I told him
after he came back from work.
He just left the room immediately.
I never heard about my mother ever again.
It's burning.
I can't fix this.
You full already?
Thirty-nine years.
If this was a big company...
by now, I would have been
compensated enough to be rich.
Why did you choose to work here?
I didn't have an education.
I didn't pursue an education back then.
I only finished the 4th grade.
At that time, 30 or 40 years ago.
Without any educational background,
I have to do whatever I can.
I thought about leaving,
but there weren't any other jobs.
I had no education or credentials.
Nothing to build upon.
I had no choice. Nowhere to go.
So I have to stay as long as I can.
Long enough until I became the chief.
From usher to the chief.
Oh, didn't see you there.
It's so dark today.
- Isn't that a 50-Satang coin?
- Wow, a coin.
Move the light, move the light.
There's my one Baht.
Got only a Baht today.
Yesterday, I found a ten Baht coin.
Like picking coins
from a Krathong at the festival.
Is that a cigarette butt?
Since when?
- Around 30 years?
- It was legal 30, 40 years ago.
People in the past were able
to smoke cigarettes in movie theaters.
The ban on smoking in cinemas
was only passed in 1979.
Before that,
they hadn't banned smoking in cinemas yet.
Please tell
those three-fingered protesters
to go to Ratchadamnoen Road.
No, they already changed their plans.
They are coming here.
See? They turn the police into clowns.
After 10:00 p.m., the protesters go home.
What can the police do?
Spend 200 million Baht
to chase protestors like this?
- They took the soldiers from everywhere.
- And who knows how many soldiers came.
- What a waste of money.
- Yes, a waste of money. They said...
Be careful not to talk about politics.
Cut it out of the film, okay, Gap?
I guess I've already sworn a lot anyways.
- I can't even catch my breath.
- Again? Watch your head.
Watch yourselves. Watch yourselves.
Don't pass through yet.
How reckless.
Put it down, now.
Let it go.
We'll see it later.
Why don't you just let it go?
It might hit someone.
Well, that's their fault.
This person looks like uncle Vinai.
Since COVID-19,
I can hardly recognize people's faces.
I often ran into him
when my father took me for breakfast
at the Chula University's
Dentistry faculty Canteen.
Besides the canteen,
there was an alley behind Bangkok Bank
just next to Siam Cinema
and the allies by the Scala,
where people
who work around here ate regularly
since the price is not so expensive.
The rest are more restaurants
for tourists and shoppers.
Come on, breakfast.
Rice noodles.
Grab a plate and join me.
Not eating? Are you sure?
You'll regret it.
I had a banana.
All right.
If I remember correctly,
my first time visiting the Scala
was when my aunt brought me here
for the owner's birthday party.
It was a Western-Chinese-style restaurant.
The recommended menu was Peking Duck.
Sometimes, the head of the cinema
would bring the Scala's Peking duck ribs
to fry with garlic and pepper
and ate it along with liquor
on the Siam cinema rooftop.
Later, a Siam Skytrain station was built.
The platform is as high as the rooftop,
and the passengers who waited
for the train could see us all.
Since then,
I rarely went out to the roof again.
Put it up.
He worked too much.
He has pain in his legs.
Where were you yesterday?
I was sick.
Stomach ache?
At least, I have land at home upcountry.
My house is there.
I'm here just for work.
I have a house here, too,
but my land is back there.
What province?
Kalasin.
It's far. Have you ever been? I guess not.
You might get lost.
In the cinema, there was a row
of chairs called spare chairs.
It was a row of chairs reserved in case
of any ticket problems,
such as duplicate seat numbers.
They are among
the most expensive seat in the back rows.
Any employee who wanted
to watch a movie could sit there.
I sat there as well.
In the past, some movies were so popular
that they had to add extra chairs.
I had to wait until fewer people came
before I could get back to my row.
Sometimes they forbade me
to see certain films.
But I would see it anyways just by
sitting quietly behind the projector.
Gap, who is the protagonist of your film?
Or is it all of us?
And that's the last person.
The last chair.
The last chair is done.
Lately, people don't come
to see movies like before
Now they rent to watch at home.
Or see a movie at the mall.
Sometimes there was
only one person watching.
When this started to happen more often,
they would have to cancel whole showtimes.
The head of the cinema would then
have to apologize and refund the audience.
There's a huge air tube
above your bed in the Siam theater.
The big air conditioner engine
is down there.
It's an air vent.
So cool air gets in here
and goes over there. That's what we used.
But at Siam,
that room is actually a cold room.
That's why
there's a big tube over your bed.
Yes, I know it's Yai's car,
but he'll drop by and shop first.
OUTSIDERS ARE PROHIBITED FROM ENTERING.
No, I mean it's Yai's car, not a big car.
- He's not come yet.
- No, he's coming later.
It's a homonym.
- So it's Yai's car, not a big car, huh?
- Okay, I get it.
I know, I know.
But they don't.
They don't understand.
Big car and Yai's car.
It's different.
They'll get confused.
The bread is moldy. Don't eat it.
MONEY IS NOT VALUABLE.
IT'S ALL USED UP ON BILLS,
ON KIDS, AND ON FOOD.
It's 9:00 a.m. already.
Take the air conditioner out now.
That's good soil.
- That plant helps with Gastritis.
- Oh, right.
Would be good with curry.
Do you want some turmeric?
No, my land is all covered in concrete.
And mine has no sun. Nothing grows.
You can grow it again. I think...
That's Nodding Clerodendrum.
But don't take it.
Yan must think it was Chom's plant.
So he doesn't want to risk it.
- Remember how Chom gets mad?
- When he curses, I can't bear to listen.
- I can't catch up with what he says.
- Is that a Santol?
- No, no need to take that.
- Would you like this turmeric?
No.
Why would I? It will just turn into junk.
- Take this one.
- Don't have.
Why take out the clothesline?
I still have to do laundry.
- Put the clothesline back now.
- Calm down, I'll fix it.
Take this right away.
You can put it back. Calm down.
After the Tom Yum Kung financial crisis
in 1997,
Chulalongkorn University, the landowner,
increased the rent exponentially
every year.
The initial ten-year lease
was changed to a one-year lease.
A movie that used to screen
for over a week.
Now they have to
show multiple movies in one day.
The popcorn that used to be sold in front
of the cinema is no longer being sold.
They sell only snacks instead.
The younger employees
would quit to find other prospects.
My dad got a new job.
Auntie Ree left
to look after her grandchildren.
As for me, I moved in with auntie Leka
not long before the coup d'état in 2006.
That is such a white shirt.
He's snooping around.
Ning, see? He walked this way.
Ning, go check the other camera at
the stairs for me, but at this exact time.
Here, the stairs, this camera.
Camera number 28, then.
Here. Play backward.
Let me see the time first.
He's wearing trousers.
Is he a driver trying to wake someone?
- Here. Right here.
- Well...
Come, come.
He looks like Mr. Apaiwong.
What?
I was on duty there.
Stop and play.
- This camera.
- At 5:29 a.m., who's that?
- There's the phone. There.
- Looks like Miss Wang.
- Who is that?
- She went down the stairs.
Only three milk left.
I didn't drink it.
Drink it, then.
If you're afraid it'll run out, drink it.
One bag of sticky rice
is not enough anymore.
How many do you need, then?
Five Baht, right?
Ten Baht per.
What sticky rice costs five Baht anyway?
When was the last time
you had a five Baht sticky rice?
I can buy at this price
because of those government apps.
It was only ten Baht.
No way it's ten Baht without that app.
So that's five Baht.
The government pays five Baht.
- What is this?
- What? What's up?
It says,
"You've got a pillow. Let's go to bed."
Let's shop.
- Oh, shopping, huh?
- Again?
So that the officers can follow up
and arrest
the criminals for further prosecution...
And that's uncle Gen's house.
Want some bananas?
Down with Feudalism, Long live the People!
Take this first.
And then see
what all we can load on the truck.
Yod. The coil, take it.
Okay, just put it down.
Has the truck come yet?
Not yet.
Can't wait for the rope.
- Be careful, don't rush. Take it easy.
- The middle.
Okay, right?
That piece is for you anyway.
Put it down.
- Go, go.
- Take the papers.
Wrap them with the papers.
Wrap them with two sheets of paper.
Got to sleep today.
- Drive to...
- Wait, wait.
Shit.
The whole fucking thing came down.
One evening in May 2010,
I heard the news on television
that the Siam cinema was on fire.
There were red-shirt protests rallying
at Ratchaprasong Intersection
demanding Prime Minister
Abhisit's resignation since March.
It was the last day
of the military crackdown.
Live ammunition
was used to disperse the assembly,
which resulted in at least 99 deaths.
To this day, no one knows
who burned down Siam Cinema.
Later on, the Siam cinema
became a new department store.
Auntie Leka didn't go back
to work ever again.
When the Lido's lease expired in 2018,
the remaining staff from both cinemas
went to work at the Scala,
the last standalone cinema.
I beg them not to remove the handrail yet.
How am I getting up there, then?
We said to do it later.
Miss Peak, hello.
Hello.
They're here. Don't step on the wire.
Careful not to trip.
Here they come. Good.
Have you seen your father lately?
I just realized you are his daughter.
So, have you seen him recently?
So you lived
with miss Leka after that, right?
Please tell your father
that Peak misses him.
I used to be close to him.
Tell him I am the Lido's accountant.
We used to be close.
What do you do for a living?
I make documentaries.
Documentaries?
Sometimes, I take photos at weddings.
Is it okay?
Is it hard to make a living?
With everything going on now, it's hard.
I ask because I see people
selling things on live streaming.
Is it hard?
Well, not really. Any camera will do.
Phone cameras?
Yes, Front camera phones and internet.
It's all about the product, right?
I'm tired.
What are you going to sell?
That's just it. I don't have any products.
Prayut, get out! Prayut, get out!
Prawit, get out! Prawit, get out!
Brothers and sisters.
Free our friends.
Draft a new constitution.
Abolish 112.
Prayut, get out! Prayut, get out!
Prayut must get out!
THE SIAM CINEMA'S FIRST FILM SCREENING
WAS ON DECEMBER 15TH, 1966
IT BURNED DOWN ON MAY 19TH, 2010.
DURING THE MILITARY CRACKDOWN
ON RED-SHIRT PROTESTERS.
THE LIDO CINEMA'S FIRST FILM SCREENING
WAS ON JUNE 27TH, 1968.
IT CAUGHT FIRE ON MARCH 16TH, 1993
AND WAS LATER RENOVATED
INTO THREE-SCREEN MULTIPLEXES.
SCALA THEATER'S FIRST FILM SCREENING
WAS ON JANUARY 31ST, 1969.
ITS FINAL FILM SCREENING
WAS ON JULY 5TH, 2020.
AFTER DISMANTLING
THE CINEMA'S KEY COMPONENTS
AND CLOSING DOWN THE BUSINESS,
THE PROPERTY
RETURNED TO CHULALONGKORN UNIVERSITY.
THE REST OF THE BUILDING WAS DEMOLISHED
ON OCTOBER 31ST, 2021.