I'll take the suitcases
to the bedroom.
I thought you could stay
in the room that was mine
and I'll stay
in your grandfather's.
All right?
THE SEVENTH SEAL
- Thank you so much.
- You're welcome.
Excuse me,
you are from the church, right?
Are you new around here?
I just arrived.
- What's your name?
- Raquel.
And you?
- I'm Ana Helena.
- And I'm Laura.
- Nice to meet you.
Do you know if there is any other
activity besides the ones on the wall?
Yes.
We do many activities
to spread God's word.
We have a service,
that is actual led by my mom.
We have a group cell
at my house.
Have you been touched by God?
Yes, a little... I am new to this.
So it's worth it.
I think so too.
Then you meet everybody.
Ok.
I'll get your number, ok?
I felt something interesting
about you.
ANA HELENA ADDED YOU
TO THE GROUP "YOUTH MINISTRY”
GIRLS, THIS IS RAQUEL.
WELCOME!
RAQUEL, WE WANT TO TAKE YOU
SOMEWHERE TOMORROW. CAN YOU COME?
BRING YOUR SWIMSUIT!
Wow.
Help!
Darling, are you all right?
You are too hot.
Are you feeling well?
Do you want me to prepare
something for you, maybe a tea?
No.
- Can I turn off the light?
- Don't, leave it on.
Rest now.
Good night.
God is thirsty for healing.
And we go, like:
opening our path, opening our path.
Because our path is illuminated.
Our path is the word of God.
- We have a direction. Am I right?
- Amen!
In Matthew 26:41,
"Watch and pray.
So that you will not fall
into temptation."
Do you know what that means,
brothers?
That even though we're being watchful,
Evil will want to prevail.
The power of Satan.
The force of darkness.
The power of the serpent.
But we have the power of light.
Which is much stronger
than any other force.
And we will use that.
We will use this against Evil.
That's right, my daughter!
That's right!
- And I want an amen!
- Amen!
- And I want Glory!
- Glory!
Don't cut it into rings.
Cut into small squares.
- It's better.
- Ok.
We have to take advantage of this
situation to the fullest, my daughter.
We can't suffer
any loss from this. At all.
I invited some friends.
You did?
How nice! Which friends?
Some people from the church.
Oh, from the church...
Dad, people from the church
also do groceries, right?
I know. That's right.
It's all right.
But...
Don't talk too much
to these people, okay?
Why? They are cool.
Okay, they're cool.
But college friends
can also be nice.
By the way,
how's this matter going?
I don't know yet, dad,
but I'm looking into it.
It's good to think about this.
Think about your future.
Cut this one too?
Very tiny, okay?
- Did it light up?
- Yes.
- Hello, Elisa!
- How are you doing, Dulcidio?
Let me do it. Go down a bit.
Wait, look!
I think it's cute.
Do it on Raquel.
Come here.
We love using it as makeup,
you know?
Did you see how well
they are getting along?
- Yes, that's true.
- Yes.
Hermes, you can count on us
for anything you need.
Because this period
of transition is not easy.
Thank you, Elisa.
I think about Raquel...
After everything that happened to Vera.
We are made of love
I think he is cute.
I think he is cute, and hot...
What is this, Laura?
God is watching.
As for Raquel...
She is watching nothing, see?
- What?
- Gustavo.
His family owns
Monte's Newspaper.
Yes, Monte's Newspaper.
- That only prints bad news.
- Liar.
There's nothing to it.
It only runs here
and another couple of cities.
Oh yeah? God is watching.
Vera!
- André, now I can't talk.
- Wait. Let me talk.
I'm trying to talk to you
and you don't answer me.
I don't answer because
I don't want to talk to you.
But I'm your boyfriend!
You're not my boyfriend, André.
We broke up!
Open that door!
Genesis.
Corinthians.
Proverbs. Hosea.
Deuteronomy. Judges.
Raquel.
Savior
The special name for our Lord
Savior ow ow ow
The special name for your Love
Savior
The special name for our Lord
The special name for your Love
Now I know why God sent me
and why he sent you too
to this place,
to this suffering.
This is all part of God's plan.
We are not lost men, Assos.
Our lives are not insignificant.
We have a mission to accomplish,
which cannot be done anywhere else.
Oh, my brothers!
How glad I am to live with you.
Because that's God's plan.
I'll write it all down.
Hey, we're going to have a party
at the Church. Want to come?
Raquel?
- Raquel?
- What?
- Oh, sorry.
- Okay, I'll clean it.
WHO WROTE THE WORD OF GOD?
To the woman, he said,
I will greatly multiply
your grief and your conception,
and with grief
you will bear children;
and your desire shall be for your husband,
and he shall rule over you.
And the head of Christ is God...
But the woman
is the glory of man.
Now, as the Church
submits to Christ,
so also wives should submit
to their husbands in everything.
Ephesians 5:24.
I'm not doing well these days,
you know?
But it's okay.
I think she was right.
I mean, she must be right.
I guess...
- Hi.
- What happened?
You know that model contest
that I said I was going to do?
- I passed.
- Wow, how cool.
But then the pastor said
that I better not go.
Yeah, Pietra.
Because this is not for you.
- That is not a serious profession.
- But what's the problem?
- You will stray from the path.
- But why?
Laura has some news.
- If you don't tell, I will!
- What?
- Come on Laura, tell us!
- Don't need to gossip about it!
- What is it?
- Tell us!
We got engaged.
- Really?
- Yes.
Damn, congratulations!
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
The pastor gave the blessing
and everything.
Now the challenge
is to wait for the wedding.
Congratulations.
That's so cool.
Thank you.
Tamar.
How many people
have you brought to the church?
I always try to bring
people in, Anice.
How come you never succeed?
- That's offensive.
- Jesus brought twelve, remember?
But I am not Jesus!
But we, as a church, must
seek that, to be like Jesus.
Yeah, right.
Laura, you go...
Oh, God...
What's your biggest fear?
My biggest fear?
- C'mon, Laura!
- Calm down, I'm thinking!
Of a car running over me.
- Is that your biggest fear?
- It is, why?
Okay,
I just hope this isn't a lie.
Because the universe conspires!
Oh, really?
I thought it was something
more interesting.
The end of times, Lucifer,
spiders, something like that.
- Well, it's my fear..
- Uhhh...
Why did you come to Monte Megido?
Because my father was born here.
No, what she meant was...
What happened
for you to come here?
She already answered,
her father was born here.
Okay, why did you come back?
- We wanted to start over.
- Start over what?
You never wanted
to start anything over?
It's your turn to answer, Raquel.
I already answered,
we came to start over.
Yeah, she already answered.
Now she asks the question.
Fine.
Ana Helena.
Do you believe in everything
that is written in the Bible?
Everything written
in the Bible is divine.
Go, Suzana.
Your turn, Tamar.
But do you think
we should be submissive?
We who?
Women.
For you to understand what the Bible
says about the woman being submissive,
you first have to understand
what true submission is.
And submission is a rule
for every Christian.
But it was a book written many years ago
and was written only by men.
There were many writers,
but the authorship is from God.
Yes.
Ok, but...
What's in the Bible
is much more than just written words.
God speaks in parables.
Behind each word is a message.
And that message is only deciphered
if you've contact with the Holy Spirit.
Do you believe that women
brought death and sin to Earth
because it's written like that?
Raquel, you already asked
a lot of questions.
It's against the rules.
What rules? Who wrote the rules?
Me.
- Ana Helena!
- Wow!
I think the Bible
should be revised.
Revised?
Yes, if it has been rewritten
so many times,
why would it be
any different now?
I advise you to pray.
ARE YOU OKAY?
YES...
I AGREE WITH YOU.
AND IT'S NOT JUST ME...
WHAT IF WE START A NEW GROUP?
WHAT ABOUT THE CELL?
IT WILL BE DIFFERENT.
BUT DID YOU DECIDE THAT NOW?
I THINK THAT...
I'VE BEEN RECEIVING SIGNS.
Hi, Elisa.
Hi, Raquel. How are you?
May I help you?
Coffee. Do you have it?
- There.
- Oh. Thank you.
All set.
- Need bags?
- No, thank you.
So... I was worried.
There you go.
- Thank you!
- No problem.
Hi.
And the grocery store
is doing well, right?
Yeah.
It's good to think
about that too.
- Come back soon.
- Good afternoon.
Do you wanna talk?
Talk about what?
I don't know.
There's something bothering you?
Raquel, I'm worried.
Why?
You know, darling...
Unfortunately, I no longer
have the bookstore.
And not only I don't have the bookstore,
many debts appeared in its place.
So our life depends on this.
It depends on this city,
these people.
We have a home here.
We have a store that can
rebalance us financially.
That's what we have, Raquel.
I have no other option.
You need to help me.
I will help you, dad.
That's good!
And...
There is also something
you need to know.
We're in a small country town.
Here, when you tell someone
you've heard or seen something,
that person will tell another,
that will tell another...
And suddenly, everyone is
talking about you.
And depending on the way
as the story goes,
you lose control
of what they say.
You don't want people to be talking
about us out there, do you?
So you have to be careful with
what you say, my daughter.
Vera, if you think
that I'll just leave here,
you can forget about that, ok?
André, please, go away!
There is no one here!
Did you cheat on me
with that bastard?
Are you completely crazy?
Dad, pick up! Please, pick up!
André is here.
He's completely out of control.
He jumped the front gate!
I'll burn this house down!
He said he's going
to set the house on fire.
If you're with someone else,
just tell me...
I'm not seeing anyone! Enough!
- I want to see him face to face.
- There's no one here!
- There is...
- Stop!
First we start identifying
the verses, right?
CIRCLE OF RENOVATION
Which we will comment on.
Then we cut them
and organize according to the Books.
We take blank sheets,
we glue these sections,
and we comment below
with our observations.
- Cool.
- Ok?
Deuteronomy 22:20.
"If, however, the charge is true
and no proof of the young
woman's virginity can be found,
she shall be brought to the door
of her father's house...
and there the men of her town
shall stone her to death."
Judges 19:24.
"Look, here is my virgin daughter,
and his concubine.
I will bring them out to you now,
and you can use them
and do to them whatever you wish."
Corinthians 14:34.
"Women should remain silent
in the churches.
They are not allowed to speak."
Deuteronomy 22:5.
"The woman shall not wear that
which pertaineth unto a man,
neither shall a man put
on a woman's garment
for all who do so are abomination
unto the Lord thy God."
If a man marries a woman...
Leviticus 15:19.
"When a woman has
her regular flow of blood,
and her impurity
is upon her flesh,
her monthly period
will last seven days,
and anyone who touches her
will be unclean till evening."
Timothy 2:12.
"I do not permit a woman to teach
or to assume authority over a man.
She must be quiet."
Genesis 2:18.
"Then the Lord God made a woman from
the rib he had taken out of the man,
and he brought her to the man.
She shall be called 'woman, '
for she was taken out of man."
Ephesians 5:22. Peter 3:1.
Proverbs 30:20.
Exodus 22:18.
Ecclesiastes 25:26.
"All malice is small compared
to a woman's malice;
let the lot of sinners
fall on her!"
BRAZIL IS RANKED NUMBER 5
IN VIOLENT DEATHS OF WOMEN
THE DAUGHTERS OF MARY MAGDALENE
WHO WAS MARY MAGDALENE?
WHY WAS JUNIA LEFT OUT?
NEW MESSAGE FROM ANA HELENA
RAQUEL, ARE YOU COMING
TO THE SERVICE TODAY?
IT WILL BE IMPORTANT TO YOU.
In Apocalypse
22:18-19,
"For I say to every man
to whose ears have come the words
of this prophet's book.
If any man makes
an addition to them,
God will put on him
the punishments
which are in this book."
And that's why, my friends,
for that and exactly for that,
that when someone comes,
calling herself a prophet,
it's very important that we analyze
these words according to the Bible.
To see if it's true
or if it's false.
Because it is our guide,
am I right?
It is our guide. Amen!
Now I want to ask you something.
And I want to see who will know
how to answer me.
What happens
to those who insist
on false prophecies?
- What happens?
- Sinners!
Apocalypse 22:18-19.
God will punish these people.
There's no way out of it!
There is no excuse!
Because, in the Bible, it says:
"Every tree that does not
bear good fruit
is cut down
and thrown into the fire."
- I want an Amen!
- Amen!
Praise God!
Hermes, I really need
to talk to you.
Sorry, Elisa,
it's just that I'm a little...
Is Raquel there?
- No, she's not.
- I will not take too long.
I promise. It will be fast.
Look at this, Hermes.
Do you know what this is?
No.
That's where your daughter is taking
a lot of teenagers.
Taking the girls
to the middle of this bush.
Without any security.
Have you wondered
what could happen?
Someone may appear there.
The things they can do to them.
And they're praying
for God knows which devil.
And who told you that?
It doesn't matter who told me.
It doesn't matter,
the whole church already knows.
And then they keep questioning me
because they know that I know you.
Ok, Elisa.
I'll see what this is about.
Pietra is dating a boy
that nobody knows who it is.
Tamar is missing classes
almost every day.
And everyone is missing
church too, right, Elisa?
Oh Hermes, please.
Try to put yourself in these parents'
shoes, at least once in your life.
We don't know what
they are doing there,
if they are making rituals,
sacrifices...
Look...
You have to do something.
This girl is going to get
in trouble.
I'm warning you!
Is this a threat?
Hey, girls!
Hi, Elisa.
You came!
Good!
We are just passing by.
Are you okay?
- Yes.
- Yes...
To sweeten your day.
Here.
Let's make a toast!
Want some?
You have to drink it!
Fine.
DJ Robinho, pump the beat
To get the crowd jumping
Only who is a Christian
Jump from one side to the other
And clap your hands
Only who is a Christian
Because Jesus freed me
To live a new story
I'm free to have fun
Prejudice isn't my thing
Whichever beat
Because God created it all
Only who is a Christian
Jump from one side to the other
And clap your hands
Only who is a Christian
But if you mess around with me, young girl
I won't look
If you mess around with me, young girl
Because I'm anointed
I got the oil
Don't mess with me Don't come
There's no legality
I'm consecrated
I'm over watching
I'm in that way
I stopped the abuses
Cut the hype
I'm telling you
Hear me out, girl
Those who are easy
Have no value in this life
Whoever say
The flesh is weak, listen
If the problem is weakness
Sin is not vitamin
But if you mess around with me, young girl
I won't look
If you mess around with me, young girl
Because I'm anointed
I got the oil
Sorry to ruin the mood, guys.
But I have something
very important to say.
One thing that can save
the souls of all of you.
The Evil.
Evil does not appear to be bleak.
Macabre.
It doesn't look like a monster.
Evil has beauty.
Evil is manipulative.
That person who lets Evil in,
that person needs help.
Now, if she denies help,
if she denies it, there is nothing
that we can do.
It's very dangerous.
We can't let them...
Let them destroy us!
Now, my question is:
What do we do with all this evil?
What do we do
with these evil angels?
Laura!
Don't let her do this, Laura.
Don't let her!
She's doubting our faith!
I never doubted anyone's faith.
- Liar.
- Why am I lying? I never doubted.
Stop this.
Go away!
I believe in God too!
- Out!
I'm also from the Church!
- Get out of here!
- Get out!
Go away!
Guys, I never wanted
to doubt anyone!
I never wanted to doubt anyone's faith!
I'm also from the Church!
- Get out of here!
- Get out!
I believe in God!
I believe in Jesus, guys! Please!
I'm writing it for the Good!
For the Good, guys!
I also believe in Jesus!
I'm writing it for women!
Go away!
She is not one of us!
Timothy 2:18.
Help!
TAMAR
OF COURSE SHE SEES THINGS, GUYS!
Raquel?
What happened?
- Raquel, my daughter?
- Mom?
No, no. It's me, your father.
What are you feeling, Raquel?
Raquel, talk to me.
No, Raquel. No, no...
It is not time for that now.
We will write everything again.
The exams are all normal.
In addition to what you already told me,
Raquel, any other discomfort?
What can this be?
Look, she organizes her thoughts
in an absolutely logical way.
I have no way of giving you an accurate
diagnosis with so little observation.
I wanted to show you something.
What is this?
It's just a notebook!
I know it's a notebook,
and what's inside?
Do you have anything
to tell me about this?
How come not, Raquel?
I think you do.
She lost her mother in a very violent
way and the two were very close.
At the time I thought it was good
for her to find strength in faith,
in a religion that is...
But then she started
doing some weird things...
Look, it would be very important
that you do therapy.
Doctor, I'm sorry.
Raquel did therapy for a while.
And...
Anyway, wouldn't there be
something parallel to therapy?
Something more immediate?
Because...
I don't know what to do.
()
WHO IS IT?
YOU DON'T KNOW?
NO.
AREN'T YOU THE PROPHET?
I NEVER SAID I WAS A PROPHET.
I'LL GIVE YOU A HINT...
WE ALREADY KNOW EACH OTHER.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
TO TALK.
I CAN'T TALK NOW.
TELL ME, WHAT DO YOU WANT?
THE POSSESSED GIRL
FROM MONTE MEGIDO
Heretic! Liar!
Liar! Witch!
- We don't want you here!
- You are bringing the darkness!
SHE CAME TO CURSE THE CITY.
SHE HAD A VISION!
LET'S PRAY FOR HER SOUL!
SHE MUST BE SICK...
SHE OPENED
THE DOORS FOR THE EVIL!
HER NAME IS
RAQUEL HERNANDES REIS.
Witch!
- Where is he?
- Where is who?
- What are you talking about, André?
- You're crazy!
- Confess it already!
André, please. Go away!
Go away, there is no one here!
No! Let me go.
Let me go, André! Let me go!
Go away! Get out of here!
Get out!
Help... Help me.
Police emergency line.
Officer, please!
Send help! I beg you, please!
My mother's ex-boyfriend
is very nervous!
Ok, he's nervous.
And what is the occurrence?
Please, officer.
He's assaulting her!
Give me your address.
- I'll go check your room!
- No, you don't, André!
I can't talk anymore!
Yes?
- Hi, Hermes!
- Hi.
Is Raquel around?
No. Raquel's not here.
- We know she's here.
- Nope. I'm saying she's not here.
I already said she isn't here.
Can we wait here for her then?
Unfortunately, no.
Can you, please, excuse me?
Ok?
Have a good day.
We are concerned about Raquel.
I appreciate your concern,
but she has already started treatment.
But what happened, Hermes...
I know this is none
of our business.
The truth is that some things, Hermes,
need another type of treatment.
Because they are
not common things.
They are things
of a spiritual nature.
Sorry, Elisa.
I don't believe in this.
We can think
in a more symbolic way.
It's so simple what
I'm talking about, Hermes.
Look, there are those
who work for Good.
There are those
who work for Evil.
Because they are being
dominated by that force.
I really appreciate your concern.
Just one thing.
Do you know the Ritual of Healing
and Deliverance?
Sorry, but I'm not interested.
Come on, Hermes,
we're already here.
I think you could pay
a little attention, it won't hurt.
Okay, what is it about?
When we realize that there is
something wrong with a person,
a change in behavior,
a change in their eyes,
in the soul,
it could be that this
comes from another place.
Of the other side.
A dark side.
It's very dangerous.
You don't want that for Raquel,
do you?
Sorry, but I don't understand
what you're talking about.
Raquel needs to be exorcised.
It's not exactly that,
that's not the word.
Raquel went to the doctor because
this is the treatment that I believe,
and this is the treatment she's
going to do for now.
So I ask you to please
respect our decision,
and don't look for us again.
We can take this evil away
from Raquel!
Please!
Hermes, the enemy might be
using her.
And you are responsible.
- Excuse me.
- You will regret it.
Get out of my house, please?
What happened?
I was at home.
With Gustavo.
We were watching a movie.
And then we started
to kiss and...
He put his hand under my skirt.
I didn't want it.
I started to scream.
Telling him to stop.
But he continued.
My brother came home.
Gustavo started shouting at me.
Calling me a slut.
Telling my brother that
he had caught me with another guy.
My brother believed him.
My father came home,
and started to beat me.
I ran away.
Am I bothering you?
Laura.
I came here to apologize to you.
I don't know what happened
to me that day.
Let's go home.
I'll take you.
I regret that.
Come with me?
We can talk about it.
No, Laura. Stop it.
Come back with me, please?
Let me go. I won't go.
- Laura!
- She said she won't go.
You're fucked.
Witch. Motherfucker.
Your call is being forwarded
to voicemail
and is subject to a charge
after the signal.
Take care.
Bye.
Good morning.
Go to hell!
- What is this?
- You are not welcome here.
This is no place for profanity!
Are you crazy?
Go away from here!
- Hell!
- Get off here!
You are not welcome here!
Out of here! Go away!
Out! Leave us alone!
- Get out!
- Hell!
Leave! You are not welcome here!
You are taking our peace away!
SATANIC CULT IN THE CITY
OF MONTE MEGIDO DEFIES THE BIBLE
HERETIC BITCH!
Raquel!
Raquel, come here!
You called
the police emergency line.
At the moment
all our attendants are busy.
Shit!
Who did this?
Who did this, Raquel?
I don't know.
And what is God's plan
for a situation like that?
What?
Tell me, Raquel!
To forgive.
To forgive?
Forgive!
Forgive what, my daughter?
Huh?
Do you think that forgiving those
who destroy our home is to do good?
That's it?
They don't know
what they are doing.
And you don't know either.
You also don't know what you do.
Look!
Can you see the absurdity
of this situation, Raquel?
Can you?
I don't know what else to do.
Everything was like this
when we arrived.
I don't know how they got in.
The door was open. It was a mess.
Things thrown on the floor.
They left everything upside down.
- Did they steal something?
- There was no time to see...
Dad!
NEW PATHS CLINIC
PSYCHIATRY AND REHABILITATION
ABOUT
COMMITTED TO CARING
Raquel, it's time.
Get up!
Come on. Get up.
Calm down.
- Go on. Hurry!
- Go, go, go.
Vera!
- Vera!
- Close it. Faster!
He's coming! He's coming! Faster!
Vera!
Open the garage!
- Vera?
- Come on, mom!
- What the fuck is this?
- Run, Raquel!
What the fuck is this?
- Shut up!
- Let me go, André! Let me go!
- André! Let her go!
- You must think that I'm a fool!
Don't hurt her, please!
Give me that key!
The party is over.
You want to go out? So let's go out!
Raquel, get in the trunk!
- No! André, leave her out of this!
- Shut your mouth!
- For God's sake! Leave her out of this!
- Silence!
- Leave her! I'll go with you!
- Can you be quiet, dammit!
Raquel, get in the goddamn trunk!
Or I'll beat you up!
- Do it, darling!
- Ok, I'll do it!
I'll do it! Calm down!
For the love of God!
André, what are you doing?
Don't you want to pray?
Then pray!
Stop.
- André, I'm sorry.
- You don't trust me.
You are right, I'm sorry.
I'm so stupid!
I'm so stupid! I don't know why
I left you, André. I love you!
- You're talking bullshit now.
- I mean it. I love you!
André, please believe me!
André...
André, you are right!
- André, slow down for god's sake!
- You have exhausted my patience.
- Look at me! I love you!
- Stop it! Take your hands off!
- Let's try it again, please!
- Take your hands off!
- Please, you're going too fast!
- Take your hands off the wheel!
Watch out!
- Good evening, brothers!
- Good evening!
How are you all tonight?
- Good! Thank God!
- Thank God!
But I hope you leave here
better than when you arrived.
Because today is
the night of healing and deliverance!
It is my favorite night
because tonight God works
His miracles.
- Praise the Lord!
- Hallelujah!
What is the cure you are
looking for today, brother?
What cure do you need?
What do you need to experience
before the Lord, brother?
Look.
Do not waste your illness.
Do not waste, as the disease is
an opportunity for revelation, brothers!
Amen!
It is through disease, be it physical,
emotional, spiritual...
It is through sickness
that God works in us!
- Praise the Lord!
- And He will work on you!
Work the healing on you!
Praise the Lord!
Tonight, God will do something
extraordinary in your lives.
If someone needs to cure
the pain of guilt,
because guilt hurts, brothers.
Blame for wrong doings,
blame for blasphemy,
blame for any crime,
it doesn't matter!
It doesn't matter
because God knows you!
He knows each one of you,
your life, your struggle.
And it is through Him
that we will heal!
We will heal from
everything that affects us.
Today is the day that God
will work a miracle.
Tonight!
So I want to pray for you!
He is touched
by your struggles, brothers.
And He wants to help you.
Let's all stand up.
Lord!
Merciful God,
perform a miracle tonight.
Give this young woman
a righteous path to follow.
Keep the tortuous paths
of blasphemy away from this girl.
Take the enemies away from her!
The enemies! The evil angels!
Take it from her, Lord!
The Demon in her body!
Take it away, Lord!
Get it out of her, give her mercy, Lord!
Heal her wounds!
Bad thoughts about others!
- Mom?
- Raquel.
Raquel, my daughter!
Oh, thank you God!
- Thank God! Are you ok, darling?
- Yes, I think I am.
- Where are you, mom?
- I think I'm stuck. I can't get out.
Bastard.
Look at the shit you've done.
Help me, please, André.
I'm stuck here. Help!
- You need help?
- Please, get me out.
What are you going
to do with that?
For what? What are you going
to do with that, André?
I want the truth...
What you're going to do with
that stone? Drop that stone, André!
- Drop that stone!
- Look what you've done!
No, please! For God's sake!
I'll do anything you want!
Women are a dangerous thing,
aren't they? Make anyone go crazy.
Help!
Mom!
Mom, mom, mom!
Help!
- Help!
- Please!
- Let me go!
- Nanci Batista de Oliveira.
Stop! Stop! No!
- Please, stop!
- Get out of here!
Ana Gabriela Bandeira.
- For God's sake! Stop!
- Stop! I'll do anything you want!
Simone Furtado.
Ester Barros Coutinho.
- Elenir de Souza.
- For God's sake, stop!
- Enis das Dores.
- Anita Fernani.
Clarissa Moraes da Luz.
Joana do Carmo.
Thaysa Vilas Boas.
Luciana Leandro Carneiro.
- Helen Mendonça.
- Bárbara Alvim.
- Marta...
- Caruza Monteiro.
Sumira Assunção.
Ana Maria de Barros.
- Keila de Paula Queirós.
- Yasmim...
- Camila Goulart.
- Marcele...
- Beatriz Cunha.
- Thaís Alexandre.
- Marta...
- Débora Diniz.
Gisele.
- Jade...
- Larissa Moraes da Luz.
Ana Maria Duarte.
Help!
Vera Hernandes Reis.
"AND TO THE WOMAN WAS SAID:
ON BEHALF OF ALL THAT PASSED,
AND THOSE WHO ARE YET TO COME,
A NEW ERA MUST BEGIN."