Nice work!
That takes the cake!
Hey, come help me.
Hurry up, we'll carry it together.
What are you daydreaming about?!
Oh, I see.
Lewd things, again.
That's not it,
you uncultivated woman!
Can't you see what this is?
No? Can't you see?
It's a Foujita!
Foujita, the painter!
He sells quite well,
that Japanese fellow.
This painting is well known, too.
Kiki is his model.
- Who?
- Kiki, I'm telling you!
Come, I'll show you something.
Stop that!
Don't move!
I'll give you Kiki's eyes.
They call her
the Queen of Montparnasse.
Back when she had no money,
she'd use matches to do her make-up.
Look at me now.
How beautiful!
I don't want to look like a whore!
Master, Kiki has been delivered.
Some wind today, huh?
Master, what's wrong with you?
Wait, wait, wait!
Here's your receipt.
Master, what are you doing?
What's the matter?
Oishii saké-san.
Your Japanese pronunciation
is very good.
But that is not a Japanese name.
It means "the good saké."
No! Is that so?
That's weird.
You know, about my painting,
the first buyer was Japanese.
And that was his name.
I remember it perfectly.
Oshi.
Sakai.
That name exists.
Oishii saké.
Yes, that's it.
But, Fernande,
you don't paint anymore?
Did you stop?
It's not that...
I don't paint anymore.
Why?
No, it's nothing.
You can paint here if you want.
I reckon it's not
the most comfortable.
I will sell your paintings,
you know.
You must apply yourself.
You've forbidden me
to enter your studio.
You see?
I keep my promises.
It's bad faith on your part.
You say I'm free,
that I can do what I desire,
but you come out on top.
In the end, I come out a slut.
Is that what you wanted?
Very well.
You're wrong.
I don't force you to do anything,
you don't force me either.
We each make our choices.
The stairs of life
can be taken a step at a time.
Selling your paintings
made you really arrogant.
Did you forget
who made you successful?
Did you forget everything
I did for you?
And remember who showed you
how a French girl kisses!
Fou-fou!
Where are you going?
Do you know where van Dongen is?
At La Rotonde.
But, it's on the other side.
Yes, yes.
I know.
Hot wine!
Get your hot wine!
Good evening, daddy Libion.
Today I posed for Man.
He's good looking, Man.
Daddy, daddy.
Everyone who's pennyless
calls you daddy,
so won't you buy me a round,
daddy?
Can the gentleman paint?
Can the gentleman pose?
For the Queen!
Kiki!
Come and teach these beginners
what it takes...
to be a good model.
There is nothing to learn.
At first sight,
there is nothing to learn.
This is why
there is everything to learn.
Here, Youki,
tell them the story of Utrillo.
Me?
Get undressed.
One day,
Utrillo descended from Montmartre
to sketch Kiki.
Of course,
Uncle Utrillo descended from Montmartre,
with his bottle of wine.
"I..."
"I never show what I draw."
But the moment he turned his back,
Kiki looked at what he was drawing.
It was a landscape.
Nice one!
Bravo! Bravo!
For a sketch, that was a sketch!
She was naked.
And she was an appetizer
to go with his wine.
Bravo!
For a good pose,
you should stand like this.
Be beautiful.
And just not care.
There's nothing to learn.
However,
if you want to know how the
Montparnasse art was invented,
that, I can teach you.
And it concerns us all.
Fou-fou, come help me.
Oh, a new cocktail!
For starters,
a generous dose,
a generous dose of Zadkine.
Anyone here can guess where
this gentleman came from?
Russia.
Russia!
Good answer!
And next, next I'll add,
three drops of van Dongen.
For that sweet juniper taste
from the Netherlands.
Then what, Fou-fou?
You haven't put any beer yet.
Yes!
And a polish beer, Kisling!
Na zdrowie!
Ah, excuse me, Kiki,
I have French citizenship, given to me
by the bullet that injured me!
I am critically French, Madam!
Bravo!
Me,
I was rejected from the legion.
With Zadkine,
we ended up making bandages
for the Red Cross.
So, Fou-fou, they don't have
any saké at La Rotonde?
Yes, yes!
Of course they do!
Kiki!
Did you put some Soutine?
So, a double dose of vodka...
from Belarus for Mr. Soutine.
- Soutine!
Wait! Wait!
Let us not forget,
the only French painter here,
in the end, is Utrillo.
Quick, wine!
Bravo, Kiki!
Drink the Montparnasse art.
The full moon?
The wolf.
Not very original.
And you?
Water.
Why?
It's as if the moon
started to drip.
That's a feeling I know well.
Under the Mirabeau bridge...
flows the Seine
And our loves
Must I remember them
Joy always followed pain
The night falls...
and the hours ring
The days go away
I remain
This is a poem for the exiled,
don't you think?
Did you meet him?
Apollinaire.
Yes.
At the Bateau-Lavoir,
with Picasso.
In fact, it is where
Apollinaire met Marie.
He fell in love instantly.
How can you pierce the carpet
with the needle...
in that position?
I'm not piercing.
The needles are bent...
so I use them like a hook.
Did you bend them yourself?
But, of course.
You're so strange.
Tell me.
I was wondering.
Can I call you Fou-fou as well?
Of course!
But that means scatterbrained.
It's not a very nice word.
I know "scatterbrained"
means "a bit twisted"...
like the needles.
It's me.
Why not?
Everyone calls me Fou-fou.
That way, they remember me.
Is it important
that people remember you?
Very important, sure!
I am a foreigner here.
Even if my drawings are good,
do you think they'll notice me
if they don't know my name?
How many years already?
Ten.
I was 27.
Five years for me.
After my aunt died in Belgium.
No, I'm not sad.
I never wanted...
a life like everybody else.
A life like everybody else?
What do you think, Fou-fou?
You call that a life?
An existence like ours?
What?
Live in a hotel?
No.
It's not that.
I'm finished.
Today, I baked bread.
Can you find
what I cooked yesterday?
Come on, take a guess.
Master, can we strike a pose?
No, no!
Sono mama, sono mama.
"Sono mama" means
"don't move" in Japanese.
Therefore, sono mama.
Do you understand?
Your standing posture is too bulky.
Too bulky!
Pretend that you just landed,
that you just touched down.
Free your senses.
Spread your arms.
Yes, good!
That's it. Gently.
Marie, is your ear bothering you?
No.
One!
Two!
Three! Go!
Good morning.
Don't go so fast.
Slowly, slowly.
I'm terribly sorry,
a studio was finally available,
but I'm afraid
others beat you to it.
No, it's me who's sorry.
So many of us showing up
without notice.
You'll see, it's small...
inside too.
Please, take a closer look.
Everyone is trying their best.
Yes!
Over 200 painters...
are in the hive.
In total, there might be tens
of thousands in Paris.
Do you think you can win?
This place's nickname,
is the Villa Medici of Poverty.
While this is not as respected
as the Medici residence is,
I still cannot feel luckier.
Paris is incredible!
They accept any foreigner
regardless of their nationality.
By the way,
Soutine came back yesterday.
He had to throw rocks
at Chagall's studio.
He broke a few windows too,
that fellow.
He overdoes it a little,
even if he doesn't like him.
The fact is, Soutine doesn't live here,
he's just passing by.
Where's he staying?
At everyone's.
Modigliani did the same.
Hive.
Cube.
Fauve.
Shul.
Various kinds of bees
have built hives.
However, you are not
supposed to follow them.
Bravo, it's coming together nicely.
Very good.
Good.
I was in Paris several years ago.
Is that so?
There is a poem I like.
Can I read it?
It's quite long, but I'd like
to read the beginning.
Go ahead.
"Cathedral in the Thrashing Rain,"
by Kotaro Takamura.
O another deluge of
wind and rain
Collar turned up,
getting drenched
in this splashing rain,
and looking up at you:
it's me...
me who never fails to come here
once a day
It's that Japanese
This morning,
about daybreak the storm suddenly
went violent, terrible,
and now,
is blowing through Paris
from one end to the other
I have yet to know
the directions of this land
I don't even know which way
this storm is facing,
raging over the lie-de-France
Only because even today
I wanted to stand there
and look up at you,
Cathedral of Notre-Dame de Paris,
I came, getting drenched,
only because I wanted
to touch you,
to kiss your skin,
the stone, unknown to anyone
O another deluge
of wind and rain
Though it's already time
for morning coffee,
a little while ago
I looked from the Pont-Neuf,
the boats on the Seine
were still tied up
to the banks, like puppies
What do you want from me,
ogling me like that?
How can I draw without looking?
Take it.
It's yours.
Thank you.
When you pull out a sketchbook
and draw a rough sketch,
it is the same as drawing
a portrait.
How many times have you
visited the Louvre?
I recognize it.
I think I know him.
He's a famous artist.
I have gone there for three years.
When I felt I couldn't even
draw a flower properly,
I hung around the Louvre,
found something most similar to the image
I had in my head and copied it repeatedly.
Every human
has to try hard in this life.
Aren't you Foujita,
by any chance?
Ah, yes.
Oh, dear!
I saw a wax figure of you in a display,
your spitting image.
Tell me, Mr. Foujita,
can you draw me as well?
It's already done.
Say, how did you guess
my underwear?
Do we have to do this much?
There are two Foujitas.
Thanks to this, the real Foujita
becomes known to the public.
What's up?
There is a painting from
Mr. Foujita's collection
of landscape paintings
from his early career.
It shows a distant view
of the outskirts of Paris...
in a dark tint.
Can we view this painting as a departure
from your great white backgrounds?
My white...
isn't meant to separate
shadows from light.
My white...
is a color in itself.
The beautiful fair skin
of European women,
must be caressed by the gaze.
Caressed by the gaze?
I'm speaking about the painting,
of course.
Ah, yes.
The vision is the sense
that measures the distance
to the subject,
whereas the touch...
records the memory of the hand.
A painting should convey...
not only the distance
perceived by vision
but also the perception of touch.
That which we feel close to.
That's how I understand it,
anyway.
You're probably right.
But for me,
only my hand moves.
And the question is to know,
if this line here...
is alive.
Are you Youki?
Yes.
Mr. Picasso.
You're prettier than this painting.
If I buy them,
will you miss them?
Obviously.
But I'm here for that.
For people to buy.
I attach myself to objects,
to their form.
But only when they're free
from the hands...
that used them.
Strange, isn't it?
Not at all.
Arigatõ.
It's pretty.
Don't you think so?
She's going to win!
Look!
Did you see?
A drink, gentlemen?
Well, thank you.
How nice of you!
How am I supposed to sell them now?
You're so cheeky!
But I like them.
I never asked to sell them.
Yes, I see that.
- Good morning.
The roof can be opened.
It's astonishing!
Fou-fou.
What are you doing tonight?
I have work.
A thousand things to finish.
I wonder,
can I go out alone?
Of course!
Go wherever you want. Go.
Do you have enough money?
Yes.
Thank you.
Kiki sings at Le Jockey tonight.
Ah, dancing?
That's a professional obligation.
Fun comes first.
The women were wearing laces
And especially adorable
frilly skirts
And when we walked behind them
We had to guess
what was underneath!
They only showed
the tips of their boots
But as soon as it began to rain
They rolled them up,
the naughty ones
"Oh no, rain!"
In order to be seen!
Ah! How beautiful was my village
My Paris, our Paris
We only spoke one language
That's enough to be understood
We danced the polka,
the waltz and the mazurka
It may have been a little silly
But the boys and girls dancing,
they were so innocent
Maybe that was true happiness
Ah! How beautiful was my village
My Paris
Our Paris
Introducing the lady!
- Are we going?
- Let's drink.
Let's go!
Be careful, Kiki!
Be careful!
Careful!
Like that, like that.
The more I provoke scandals...
and act scatterbrained,
the closer I get to myself.
My paintings are
that much more beautiful.
Fun only lasts the night.
It's pointless.
And that's why I love it.
I love it...
because its meaning fades
very quickly.
I will make a tatoo...
on your white skin.
What's the matter?
Why not a painting?
Melancholic?
Of course,
I'll continue to paint.
However,
thanks to the beauty
of your skin,
my paintings...
will sell even better.
They'll sell...
better than you imagine.
Okay.
What do you want to tattoo on me?
On you,
a mermaid.
And on me,
at first,
a watch, here,
that will always point to noon,
to ensure my good health.
I must tattoo a lion as well.
One that will protect you forever.
Wow, I didn't know you
were that famous.
I am sorry!
I was the one who decided to
stay here on a whim, that's all.
Right now,
the newspaper reporters...
must be struggling to find me
searching inns one by one,
from the best to the worst one,
in that order.
Mister.
Is that a sword battle?
Your voice is too loud.
You told me that a sword battle
would take place in Attu Island.
It's a sword battle because swords
are involved, right?
I don't like drawing something still,
after all.
I draw people in close proximity,
to such extent
that I can even touch them.
In war, the situation is similar.
The only problem
is that I have to use...
special drawing technique
because of the shaking.
This time,
I merely bet my life in order
to test my capabilities, that's all.
Anyway, I ended up creating
a satisfactory piece of work.
For the first time,
I learned firsthand...
that drawings can move
people's minds.
Today...
was an unforgettable day.
Are you still lost?
But...
If you cannot finish it
with one piece,
just buy two.
Are you satisfied?
Women look prettier when
they spend money on accessories.
You know, Master,
this here...
has stripes, though.
You call me "Master"
only in this kind of situations.
But...
I think that one looks good too.
I definitely saw that kind of color
on a Mexican traditional cloth.
Oh, dear.
I have an extra.
You're welcome.
Your fourth wife,
Miss Madeleine, is that right?
Hey, hey!
I know it because
I am your fifth wife.
Everyone can tell by your drawings.
But,
why is there no drawing
of your first Japanese wife?
Before I went to Paris,
I was just a student.
Say,
if Ms. Madeleine...
were a fabric,
which fabric would she be?
Velvet, maybe?
How about Ms. Youki?
She was fair-complexioned,
wasn't she?
Silk, maybe?
Please, stop.
Say,
how about me?
We don't have enough
material right now.
What do you mean by that?
I have one with stronger tips,
but it's hard to find soft ones
that will fit your style.
Ever since Mr. Fujishima
passed away,
I've heard that Mr. Foujita became the
president of the Army Art Association.
It must have been hard.
Please, provide your contribution
for a senninbari.
- Please, contribute.
Every oil painter...
goes to Paris to learn more.
Paris is under German control
right now.
Nobody can learn arts
in Paris anymore.
There is no doubt about it.
This is the best opportunity...
to stay away from those imported art styles
influenced by Impressionism.
The Great Depression...
made Paris a sad city in no time.
Nowadays,
the trend in the art scene...
moves from Europe to the U.S.
Don't you think?
Even if a country has no history,
matured capitalism...
can make flowers bloom anywhere.
I want you two masters...
to come up with an idea
that will better fit
Our Great East Asian Vision.
We have to end this
White Domination over Asians.
Master Miyamoto.
We have to, at least,
win the war on paper like this.
I see.
I'm trying.
Do you know the God-of-War
Squad Yamasaki?
It surprises me that they even built
Yamasaki Shrine for that.
It's not a big deal.
I am very happy that the Army...
made up the narrative.
Drawings are all about falsehood,
so narratives actually makes
them better.
I don't think falsehood...
is a bad thing in itself.
I understand.
Good drawings...
will last longer than
the narratives themselves.
What do you think about taking
a walk before going home?
That sounds good.
We lost the Midway Battle,
that was the total opposite of the
announcement by the Headquarters.
The U.S. already took control of the
air superiority over the Pacific Ocean.
Even Tokyo is in danger.
The walls have ears.
I should be careful.
Is it okay for us to enter?
Thank you very much.
Please, go inside.
I am glad that I came.
It's not even an important event.
Why are you here?
Why did you suddenly scream,
"Kamakura"?
It's fine.
I can leave for Chiba now,
if you want.
Would you like to visit your grave?
Why would I do...
such a thing?
I have seen...
for almost twenty years...
Jesus Christ nailed on the cross.
Last night, our soldiers ferociously
attacked the enemy's mobile unit...
on the eastern coastline
and destroyed half of them.
The battle gave us...
several tactical benefits,
such as the following.
Firstly...
- Goodbye, master.
- Goodbye.
Mr. Seiroku.
Thank you for your help the other day.
You saved me.
Is Mr. Skillful Painter okay now?
Being in the countryside helps.
But I am not sure what the future brings.
Please, let me know
if you need any help.
Thank you very much.
Seiroku! The tea is ready!
Mr. Yatsu, that's enough.
Beans should be...
managed carefully all the time.
- Ah, Bo! Welcome back.
- Welcome back.
I am back.
Welcome back.
Is your name Bo?
Not really.
It's my fault. I've called him
like that for a long time.
Are you really going to walk in that?
I was honored to receive it...
from the country
as a major general.
I have to wear it sometimes.
Otherwise, it's the same
as disrespecting the country.
Drawings are tasteless.
Drawings gradually...
get more serious and different from
the taste of the general public
once you start digging deeper.
Whether they are tasteless or not,
everyone has to get over
this kind of phase.
You didn't show me
the military boots yet.
What?
It doesn't have to be
an official issue?
A pair of getas will do?
Those getas are brand-new.
When you wear new shoes
after dark,
foxes will ridicule you.
I am surprised that
you believe in that kind of myth.
Let's go get ridiculed.
Once you do this,
they will become used getas.
Who would have ever thought
that farmers would ever receive rice
from Tokyo people?
That's right.
It's strange.
I am a strange one.
Also, you need to use crushed rice
for rice flour.
Why would you crush decent rice
into pieces?
You are committing a sin.
I'm sorry.
I had to share
with my neighbors anyway.
That's how it is supposed to go.
We are desperate
for food right now.
I guess human beings
will get happier than the Moon God.
Let's have a break.
Okay?
I have never celebrated
the 13th Night Ritual before.
Only the 15th Night Ritual, then?
In the past, the 13th Night Ritual used
to be called Mochi Tsukimi by people.
When you finish the 15th Night Ritual,
you see a half moon.
The moon on the 13th night
is more beautiful...
because it hasn't reached
the 15th night yet.
The air is crisp.
What a beautiful moon.
Are you okay with the house
without decorations?
Yes.
Drawings don't look nice when
the engawa is not shown properly.
Master! Master!
I still think this is weird.
You are not supposed to do it.
I need the stamina to keep drawing.
I am doing it right without any problem.
If I don't put proper efforts,
I will die one day.
In Tokyo,
I used to work 14 hours a day
in my atelier.
Hey!
Aren't you Suzuki?
Oh, master!
I didn't recognize you!
The home front has more
things to do than drawing.
Thank you for your service.
I will tell the village chief.
Please, go see him immediately.
Thank you very much.
We lost all ammo due
to the airstrikes.
I can see that.
I am just glad
that you didn't get hurt.
Thank you very much.
Gramps!
I need to use some tools!
You don't need them, do you?
And also,
is it okay for me to repair...
the roof of the unused warehouse?
Hey! Keep crushing!
You finally took them all out!
Which temple is it?
The Jiganji Temple.
It's a decent one.
Master!
Today,
two of our villagers
received conscription cards.
I hope Kanji
won't receive it this time.
I think Mr. Kanjiro officially left
the military in Manchuria.
Conscription can take place
more than once.
Tsuneichi,
who received the card today,
is almost fifty.
Kanji's older brother...
died four years ago.
As a brother,
Kanji made
his older brother's wife as his.
They did not have any children.
I thought it was better
for the family...
that they didn't have children.
But in the end,
the wife ran away from home.
Some people even spread
malicious rumors about that.
She was a beautiful woman.
Three of them had been
very close with each other.
That must...
have made Kanji suffer deeply.
In the night,
someone called me out.
He even shouted my name.
So, I got out.
There was no one.
That kind of thing
continued for days.
People told me that foxes did that.
If that is so,
foxes don't know the concept of time.
If they cannot answer...
when I ask for the time,
it means that it was
a fox who did it.
I see.
So, I asked them,
"What time is it?"
How interesting.
And the answer was?
They jumped once,
"Time is time."
They told me.
I also like the story
of a ghost train.
In the Meiji era, a railroad was built
on the outskirts of the village.
One night,
a train crossed the rice field.
Another train came
from the opposite direction.
The train operator got scared
and stopped the train.
The other train stopped as well...
and disappeared.
That kind of thing kept happening.
One day,
he turned off the light...
and kept advancing,
honking its horn.
The train disappeared
right before it was about to crash.
On the next day,
due to the train crash,
several foxes were found dead.
These fox tales,
don't make much sense.
But I can easily guess...
what kind of emotions the villagers hide
in their minds when they tell them.
Even I don't know exactly...
who started that story.
Was it the train operator?
Or perhaps a villager?
We will never know.
As the story moves
from one person to another,
it changes.
The emotion of each person
who delivers the story,
changes it forever.
And at some point,
the subject becomes ambiguous,
and the story
becomes everybody's story.
Foxes, just like humans,
live around the mountains.
They are the Gods
of Rice Farming too.
Every rice farmer hopes
that today...
will be a peaceful day
just like yesterday.
One wonders if they...
really wanted modern-day civilization and
enlightenment forced down by the government.
Come back safely.
Don't die!
Yes!
We are living a crucial moment.
Even if you go to the battlefield,
nobody can guarantee your safety.
The reason why
I brought you here today...
is that I want to hold
the art exhibition...
we've been looking forward to
despite the big battle approaching.
First, look at the material in front
of you and think of an image.
Master.
Can you come?
It's an intense shower.
It is indeed.
It's already been three days.
Unlike in the cities,
there is no place to go
when it rains in the countryside.
Just like a small child,
I really want to go outside as soon
as possible. That's what I thought.
Since I came to the village,
my hearing has improved a lot,
catching every single sound.
I can even hear various kinds
of sounds from the roof,
soft ones,
loud ones.
It is fun to guess which part
of the roof gets hit...
when I hear a certain sound.
They are impressive.
Painters.
What happened?
I am just putting a flower like this.
That's all.
I think this war painting...
might be the last one.
I saw a billow of smoke
in the mountain.
Are there some people living
on the opposite side of the river?
A charcoal maker entered
the mountain a long time ago...
and has not come back ever since.
With his family?
No, alone.
Can I cross the river?
When you walk several miles
toward the west,
the river gradually becomes
narrower.
And you will find a big cut
at some point.
You can reach the opposite side
right away using that cut.
What is inside the basket?
Salted fish.
Are you selling them?
Yes, since my father's generation.
I am just doing
what my father used to do.
Since my father's generation.
I am just doing
what my father used to do.