Jackpot. Bust it up, dog.
No, no, no. Not right now, yo.
I think it's the cops.
Come on, stop being scared
and bust the window out, man.
I'm not being scared, man.
This is what we came here for!
Bust them out!
- I'm just saying it's going be to...
Shh. Somebody's coming.
We'll handle this later.
Hey, Elizabeth, it's me.
Ahh!
That's going to leave
a mark in the morning.
You go, check his
wallet, check his wallet.
Where's the money at, big boy?
Here we go. Here we go.
Yo, yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
What else you got for me?
What else you got for, huh?
There's a couple hundred, boy.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I'm seeing flash.
I'm seeing some flash.
Shit!
- You know what I can get for this, huh?
Thanks, big dog.
Do you know what happened?
I'm not sure.
Oh, my head.
Can't imagine
that feels too good.
Mister...
- White.
- Jackson White.
Mister White,
you seem like a decent guy.
Can you tell me why you're
face down in an alley?
Just...
This isn't how I thought
my life would turn out.
But do you ever feel like you're
not the man you want to be?
You know, I wanted to do
something that mattered.
I want more.
Can we focus on tonight?
October 27th.
It's my birthday.
My 30th birthday.
You were drinking?
Yeah, there was a party.
My client...
What, what do you do?
I'm a music manager.
Hmm.
He sang a song about my fiance.
How can we contact her?
Why do you keep doing this?
What do you mean?
My ex fiance.
Liz!
I screwed it up.
Did you have any arguments?
Anything out of the
ordinary happen?
Not really.
Why did you sit
down with Gammons?
L.A.'s a small town, James.
Dude, I don't want to
talk about this tonight.
I left early.
What happened at the party?
Is there something
you're not telling me?
Just talk to me about it.
I feel like he's got
a lot of big clients.
He can do something.
His company has a
lot of big clients.
He's a promotion away
from answering phones
and making fucking coffee.
My biggest client James,
I think he's going to
sign with another manager.
Just remember I was your client
before I was your friend.
Jackie boy,
it's your gray haired daddy.
I wanted to call you earlier
but, well, happy birthday.
I miss you, buddy.
It's
Elizabeth. Leave a message.
Hey, Elizabeth.
It's me, Jackson.
I haven't spoken
to you in a while.
Um, call me if, if you a, if...
That's the
last thing I remember.
- Go home.
- We'll be in touch.
Jackson White's office.
It's me.
Dennis wants
to see you first thing.
Where are you?
I'm going to work
out of the house today.
Jesus. You've
got three meetings and a lunch.
Reschedule them.
What do I tell Dennis?
Uh, car trouble.
Look, we need to find something
for James immediately.
I mean, right now.
Find out who's looking
for opening acts
and put it in an email asap.
People we know or everybody.
Everybody,
Stefanie. Everybody.
He's moving more units
in the Pacific Northwest.
He's getting more airplay.
I mean, this guy is
the next John Mayer.
It's the same act.
Another girl with a guitar!
Crisis control.
It's what I do, man.
It's what I do.
It's what separates
the men from the boys.
I pushed them into Thursday.
Friday you have a
9:30 staff meeting.
Lunch with the
head of the T Recs,
you need to stop by the War
Presidents' video shoot.
When do I sleep?
Oh shit, I'd got to get this.
It's a Carolina number.
Uh, I'll talk to you tomorrow.
Good work today.
Say hi to your dad for me.
Yeah, will do.
What do you want?
Who?
Oh, Foster!
Hey, man, I haven't
spoken to you in a while.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
Cancer.
Sir?
Sir, excuse me.
I don't want to wake
you up, but we're here.
Oh, come on.
This is great.
Hello?
You forgot a bag.
Anyone back there?
Sir, I'm sorry.
We don't have you listed
in our passenger manifest
for Flight 319.
One second.
How is that possible?
How do you think I got here?
Do you think I walked?
No.
Astral projection maybe?
Your name is White.
Yes. Jackson White.
My assistant made the
reservation last evening.
And it's W-H-I-T?
I'll call you back.
My ticket. My driver's license.
My baggage ticket.
Okay.
That's odd, sir.
We, we just don't have
you in our system.
You know what?
I don't like how
you guys operate.
Have a good day, sir.
They've lost my luggage.
They've got Barney Fife
behind the desk. Find it.
You wouldn't believe the
rental car they gave me.
Yeah, I'll
call the airline first thing
and I'll get back to you.
First thing? Call them now.
Okay. I'll call
them right now. I'm sorry.
Listen, listen, you don't
need to tell me we're behind.
I know.
Yeah, well I need copies
of concert gate receipts,
their published songs
and other paperwork
pertinent to the group's income.
I also need you to find out
who produced their merchandise
and if the cost for...
No, no, who produced
their merchandise.
And if the cost of
production was subtracted
before profits were divvied up.
Yeah, get back to me asap.
Yeah, no, no cell
phones. I got it. I know.
Uh, it's Chris White's room.
You know where that is?
319.
Thanks.
Hi.
Welcome home.
I'm not sure you're
supposed to be doing this.
Well, I'm not supposed
to do a lot of things.
I missed you, buddy.
Missed you too.
You didn't have to come.
How long are they
going to keep you here?
I go home tomorrow.
Sure about that?
Mm.
What do you want?
I was going to
crack the window.
I got it.
Oh, that's right,
you don't smoke.
You shouldn't either.
One thing has nothing
to do with the other.
Dad, come on.
We're in a hospital.
Everyone else give me shit.
I don't need it
from my kid, too.
Apparently you do.
Everybody else doesn't
want you to die.
They say you've stopped eating.
I'm not hungry, kiddo.
And you're just gonna
light up whenever you...
You hear about Dunbar?
Tony Dunbar?
Mm-hmm. Miami moved
up to draft him.
Riley thinks he's the hardest
worker he's ever seen.
Really.
Mm-hmm.
He got 32 in San Diego game.
Baron Davis guarding him.
What does he know?
What? He's a good coach.
He needs a haircut.
He doesn't have any more hair
to get cut.
Jackson White.
Hey.
I'm really glad you called.
Of course.
It's no problem.
This is real.
Sorry, it's just
that I haven't spoken
to anybody since I got here.
It's okay. I'm glad you came.
Yeah.
So, you're his doctor?
One of them.
Surgical resident.
How bad is it?
You should be careful up there.
I thought you
weren't going to come.
Who are you?
Let me give you a hand.
Nah, it's all right.
Bit of a mess.
I haven't had people
over for a while.
Don't be ridiculous.
Have a snack.
Someday soon this
will all be yours.
Is the picture
always like that?
What do you mean?
Are you running the
cables through RCA's
or an S Video cord?
Huh?
How old is this TV?
Oh, Dad.
No wonder it looks
like a snowstorm.
You're using a coaxial cable.
Looks fine to me.
That's ¢cause you
don't know any better.
You know what you need?
What's that?
High def.
Yeah, baby.
This remote is for
the television.
You only need to turn the
power on, then forget it.
This one is for the cable.
It controls the DVD
and surround sound.
This is the main remote
you'll have to know.
Okay.
What are you...
Dad, Dad, no.
You didn't have to
do this, you know.
It's the absolute
least I could do.
All right, what
does this one do?
You know, back in my day,
you just hit a button...
You have no idea.
You hit a button
and it comes on.
Now why is this not working?
It's not working.
Batteries.
That was your job.
No...
I told you, aisle four.
It was the only
thing you had to do.
Just walk up to the
set, hit a button.
That's it.
Isn't it time for my medication?
You going to ask
every fifteen minutes?
Only during the commercials.
Nice.
This guy.
This wasn't the first time.
The hospital, I mean.
Foster told me.
Why didn't you say anything?
It would have sounded serious.
I didn't want you to worry.
You didn't want me to worry.
Cancer is kind of a big deal.
I'm fine.
I just uh...
You what?
I don't want to fight.
Fuck you!
I want to fight.
Jackson!
No, no, no.
Last night we're in the
hospital and I let it slide.
But you lied to me.
I could never lie to you.
Every time we
talked it was a lie!
Every time you didn't tell me!
I thought we were
closer than this.
We are!
Ashville Democrat.
Are you looking for
marketing opportunities?
What are you doing?
Homework.
Can you do it
somewhere else please?
Why?
Because this is
my dad's office.
This is his desk.
That's his chair.
And that's his pencil
you're chewing on.
The office is empty.
Besides, the guy who
used to work here got...
I'm sorry.
You're turning my dad's
office into a study hall?
Sorry, that's my son.
We're all just so broken
up about your dad.
Maybe he'd come for
a visit sometime.
Maybe. I'll ask him.
Well, I've got the Cobra
and life insurance forms
if you'd like to look them over.
Okay.
Mister Sheldrake...
Yeah, I know sir. I haven't
had a chance to get to him.
Uh, no, no, I had
to reschedule that.
Sir, I'm doing the best I can.
Well, I hope I have a
job to come back to.
Are you really
going to threaten me
while I'm packing
up my dad's office?
Fuck!
Clearly this
isn't a good time.
Sorry.
Don't be sorry.
I'm Kat.
Jackson.
From New York?
L.A. but close enough.
Is there something
I can help you with?
Oh, I...
I interned here this spring
and I heard about your...
I heard and,
I want you to give this to him.
Thanks.
I'll make sure he gets it.
You want to get lunch?
Uh, no. Thank you.
You already eat?
No.
Well, you got to eat.
That's true.
But not with me?
No, not with a
complete stranger.
And not when my world
is falling apart.
Your dad said you were a snob.
Excuse me?
Not in a bad way.
Just the prodigal son
who leaves his hometown
and doesn't look back.
Hey! Need a hand with that?
Familiar with
the term stalker?
Yeah, men tend to
get attached to me.
Well, why aren't you
bothering one of them?
He talks about you.
A lot.
We'll be quick.
I think I put that...
Okay.
It's amazing.
I like your song.
You look and I, and
maybe I'll, I'll steer.
- Very funny.
- Please.
You got it?
Yeah? Yeah?
I got it. Thanks.
Whoa!
Enough with the emailing.
I'm just gonna...
It's Thursday.
The music industry doesn't shut
down because you want sushi.
Well, that's a crime.
Now put it away.
Just one more and I'll put
the Blackberry away. Okay?
What? What are you doing?
What? Wait!
Kat! This is a street!
I'm, I'm sorry.
What are you doing?
Where's the owner?
I don't know.
There's no tags.
Then who do we call?
He hurt his paw.
We're taking him to the vet.
All right.
Asheville.
Where good taste goes to die.
I do not think that would fly
with the Chamber of Commerce.
You've always thought you
were better than anyone else.
I don't think I'm
better than anybody.
Well, maybe just a
little bit better.
I can't believe they
can just lose a bag.
What if I had something
irreplaceable in there?
What would be irreplaceable?
I don't know.
Uh...
I'm sorry. I
don't have a 32-33.
I didn't even ask for black.
What about the French cuffs?
Let me check in the back.
Should have gotten them
the first time.
Did the airline lose your
manners with the luggage?
I'm almost done.
I can't believe that
nobody in this town
sells True Religion.
You sure I can't
get you anything?
A new watch? A
haircut? Anything?
Consider it an early
Christmas gift.
Or a late one from last
year for that matter.
Well, I'm Jewish, Dad.
I can't keep up with the dates.
It's December
25th. Every year.
Isn't that confusing?
With Yom Kippur and Passover
jumping all over the calendar?
Does this look all
right from the back?
You look a little
fat, but yeah.
I don't really wear suits.
Well, you should.
You look good.
Huh?
So what do you think?
The navy or the gray?
Yeah. I like this one.
Shouldn't we get something
a little more practical?
We both know I'm only
going to wear this suit once.
Yeah.
It's going to
be the white suit.
You said I could get
anything if I agreed to this.
Anything at all.
Then I want this
shirt as well.
Oh, Dad, that's revolting.
Does he got any
idea on this contract?
This cracks me up.
My snotnose little kid
is buying me a suit.
What's that?
What?
You upset?
No, no.
It's okay, it's okay.
Dad, I love you.
Yeah.
I love you so much.
I promise, I swear to you
it's going to be okay.
No. There's
nothing they can do.
I'm dying.
There's nothing they
can do about it.
I'm so scared.
Come here. Come here.
So let me get this right.
Your life's ambition is to
not become your parents?
Totally.
They think that human life
is defined by its
consumer potential.
Right. And what do you think?
I don't know.
But I want what I do
to mean something.
I'm not sure that one
life can mean anything.
One life can change the world.
Wait until you're
in the real world.
You'll see.
What does that even mean?
This isn't real?
The real world is where
you're no longer driving
Daddy's BMW and you have
ramen six days in a row
because entry level job
roughly translates to
"We can pay you as
little as we like."
Your priorities shift.
Not mine.
Don't patronize me.
I got this friend, right?
He thinks his novel is
going to change the world.
He's now 28 years old
and he still works at
our childhood camp.
What's your point?
My point is, he spends
so much time dreaming
that he's pissed his life away.
And we used to be so close.
Now I don't even know
what to say to him.
To a guy who still
lives for a fantasy
that's never going to happen.
Dad?
Is it seven already?
Yeah.
Oh.
Here, dad.
Thanks, darling.
Give me five minutes.
Wow!
This is just amazing.
It's amazing.
You still like it
medium rare, right?
I don't know what to say.
I really appreciate this.
But?
I don't have an appetite.
I'm sorry, Jack,
if I'd known you'd gone
to all this trouble...
It's okay.
No, I mean it.
This is great.
They said they would like
to see you at the office.
I don't want them
to see me like this.
Dad, you're sick.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
Mm.
And one of the interns
wrote you a letter.
Who?
Her name is Kat.
Katherine Morrison.
I like her.
Enjoy being home?
Sure. You want another one?
Yeah.
I got it.
What's on schedule
for tomorrow?
I was going to
run by the camp.
Ben's working there
full time now.
That's about it.
He wrote a book.
Ben?
Yeah.
Is it any good?
It's very good.
It's about me.
How much of it?
All of it.
I didn't even realize until
about a hundred pages into it.
It's about a politician
who loses his soul.
He sells out his friends,
constituency and
religion for power.
Haven't spoken to him since?
I was supposed to head down
to the music festival in August.
But that didn't happen.
It's good you're
seeing him again.
You can't leave things unsaid.
What do I say?
As a rule,
the Jewish faith does not
address the afterlife.
We are asked to
focus on the present.
There's a reason the
Mourner's Kaddish
doesn't mention death.
It's a celebration of
the time we spent...
Is she sleeping?
Is she sleeping
or is she just...
Is she thinking?
She's very pensive.
Or is that sleep?
Sleeping Beauty!
Jordan! Wake up. Thank you.
How could you, how could
you sleep through this?
Okay, forget it.
Girls, can we see
your art projects?
I uh...
I am a loser. Thank
you. Well done.
Let's see...
He must be stoned.
Rachel?
Earth to Rachel?
Are you?
Who's the guy in the back?
Jackson White everybody.
Yeah, uh...
I'll come find you.
You're, you're Ben's friend.
Yeah.
Are you going to bust us?
I don't work here.
No, I'm not going to bust you.
You guys want to shoot a round?
You want some of that?
Oh!
How do you know Ben?
We went to camp together.
What's your name?
I'm Jackson White.
Wait.
Holy shit. You're a legend.
No way.
You're the Rocket?
Well I suppose I was.
I'm him.
Dude, I heard
you dropped 40 points
on Camp Barney one year.
43.
Hello. He's open.
Uh-oh.
He's open. He's open.
You still got it.
Still got it.
So what brings you
to Hendersonville?
Just visiting my dad.
Everything all right?
Yeah.
How's Elizabeth?
Or as we say behind her
back, the Japinator?
Uh, you know, she's
as difficult as ever.
Are you all right?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm great.
It's good to hear.
Because you look like shit.
Nine months out of the year
I got this whole
place to myself.
It's great.
I read. I write.
Sleep till noon.
I'm up at six.
On a good day.
Ouch. Sorry.
I'm hooking up with girls,
I'm way too old for.
Does it ever get old?
Not yet.
Uh, no. I, I...
Adulthood you know,
it's it's overrated.
It's all uh, tuition and
erectile dysfunction.
Adulthood's uh...
It's working out
for you, though?
Well, you know I was thinking
of becoming a camp counselor.
You still thinking
about grad school?
I'm thinking about it.
Doing anything about it?
It's great.
All right?
I read your book and
I think it's great.
I don't know how I
became Sammy Glick.
Look, Jackson, man.
I never meant to hurt you.
Sometimes the
truth just hurts.
Hey,
Ben, we need you at services.
Shit.
Uh, hey, sorry, I got to...
Yes. Yes, yes.
On my way, over and out. Yes.
Well, I, I should
hit the road too.
Yeah. I...
The real world beckons.
So, uh, we still friends?
Always, brother.
Always.
Good.
Be well.
You too.
315, 317, 323.
Where the hell 319?
Can I help you?
I don't know.
Is this 319 Cypress?
Yeah.
Is that you, Jackson?
Uh...
Sorry I didn't tell
you about my roommate.
I just thought it
sounded so collegiate.
Well, you're in college.
Hey, oh, look at
your little paw.
What's your name?
Ophelia.
Ophelia?
I'm telling you, I have band.
Do not leave my sight.
Jackson.
Alright.
That's inside.
Oh.
Dance with me.
Sorry about your mom.
Dude, what the fuck?
Come on, Jackson, Matt.
Matty P.
Six. I was the sixth
man for Reynolds in '95.
Matthew Price. Holy shit.
What, what, what's going on?
Living out by the
Biltmore, I'm selling ins...
What about you, man?
I'm a manager for musicians.
Fuck, dude.
It's so fucking good to see you.
Yeah.
Yo, Trent! We got...
We got the fuckin'
Rocket over here, dude!
Give him a fuckin'
beer! Let's do it!
You know what?
This is great. My
friend's in a band.
Wow, you're married?
Separated actually.
Um...
Separated really.
You're not married.
Not with who you're
with tonight.
Walking in here with Kat.
You were always a pimp.
She's legendary.
She really goes down.
And you're going to
have a good night.
What did you say?
Okay, you know what?
I see where this is going and
I'm about six inches taller,
so you're gonna want
to take it outside
or I'm going to do something.
Do it.
Good choice.
Take it outside.
Go outside, go outside.
Hey uh, we, we should go.
Okay. Is everything all right?
Yeah. Um...
Let's just, I want to
show you something.
Who wants a fucking beer?
Who wants a fucking beer!
All right.
I almost feel like you should,
you should close your
eyes as we're walking up.
Yeah, ¢cause this
looks really exciting.
It's a pretty
scary part of town.
Are we close yet?
At least there's
no lines. This here.
Oh, shit!
This is the place?
No way.
You've got to be kidding me.
What are you?
Kat.
Good evening Asheville!
So why did you leave school?
I flunked out.
You know, by the time I
realized how poorly I was doing,
it was too late.
I went from walking on to the
best basketball team in America,
to living at home
in sixteen months.
And the first few
weeks weren't so bad.
You know I got a lot of
calls, a lot of emails,
but people moved on.
Everyone but me.
I sat in my room
for weeks on end.
I didn't know how to
get out of that house.
And this town was
my personal prison.
Hey, everyone's home
town feels that way.
And we came here
for my 21st birthday.
Ben, Foster, everyone.
Nobody knew I was
going to kill myself.
But at that point,
I don't think anybody
would have been surprised.
It's funny how
therapeutic suicide can be
when you decide to end it.
Every worry, every
responsibility just fades away.
So we started
drinking at dinner.
And when we got here we were,
you know, we were hammered.
And by the time
Whiskeytown came on,
I was counting my final hours.
And the most amazing
thing happened.
Ryan Adams.
He climbed on to the stage
like a drunken troubadour.
He was young, sad and fucked up.
Just like me.
His songs were brutally
honest confessions
of his failure and pain.
And he sang about all the things
I thought I wanted to kill.
It was the first time
in my life I thought
that everything might be okay.
And I wanted to be part
of the art form that
celebrated imperfection.
I recognized that it was
our most human quality.
I left him here.
All alone.
I was all he had and I just
left him here to die.
You know what?
You lived your life.
No.
That's what you had to do.
Your dad knows that.
You have to decide
on radiation soon.
It'll be unpleasant but you
got to fight this thing.
That it, Doc?
That's it.
All I know is
we're coming here
for all your
doctor's appointment.
Shut up and drink your beer.
Remember, it's
basketball season.
Let's talk about
something important.
Who do you guys
like this season?
I like the Bobcats.
I think they're going
to surprise them.
Adam Morrison may need a
haircut but the guy can play.
It says here the Knicks
might resign Allan Houston.
You kidding me?
The guy's legs haven't
been right for years.
I'm just reading the article.
I mean look,
the guy can shoot.
He's no Adam Morrison though.
Sure he can shoot.
He set the SEC scoring record.
Come on, he's human though.
I mean, the body falls
apart after a while.
You told me that.
At least he knew
when to walk away.
I'll be back in a minute.
Hey, do you need any help?
No.
Are you sure?
I can still wipe my own
ass, thank you very much.
And I don't intend on
sticking around till I can't.
I'm cancerman.
He's not a superman.
He's doing well.
Yeah, he is.
He's not eating well.
Well, oxycodone,
it's not really good
for the appetite.
Look, I can't prescribe it,
but marijuana does help.
How are you?
I'm alright.
It's unhealthy to
keep it all bottled in.
You know if I didn't
have Allison...
You know what I love about
our friendship, Foster?
What's that?
We don't need to talk.
Some people want to analyze
and nitpick life down
to nothing, but not you.
You've always understood
my not wanting to talk.
You let everything be okay.
Are you sure you don't
want any more, Jackson?
Oh, no, I'm fine.
Four servings is
really sufficient.
Mind if I turn
on the television?
Oh, no. Go right ahead.
This reminds me,
ESPN Classic's playing the
Georgetown game from '82.
The championship?
Yep.
You can watch
anything you like, Mr. White.
Ah.
Some people might
think it's crazy
to watch a 25 year old game.
No one's ever accused
me of being normal.
Ain't that the truth.
Yeah, we split Mom's
painting room into offices.
Just finished in March.
It looks good.
I never would have
recognized the place.
Thanks.
Your dad loved this ball.
I swear he must have
told us about Hank Aaron
every time I came here.
Look, Jackson.
You got to deal with this.
I told you I'm fine.
No, you're not fine.
How would you know, Foster?
Because it torn me apart
when my parents
were in that crash!
You selfish son of a bitch.
I'm sorry.
I didn't want to bring that up.
No, go ahead.
You're the one
that wants to talk.
Tell me what an asshole I am
for not coming to the funeral.
What?
That's not what you want to say?
No, it isn't.
Yes, it is. Say it.
Tell me how much I suck at life.
I couldn't leave my job, Foster.
I'm sorry I couldn't
finish school.
I'm sorry I didn't
become a damned doctor.
Fuck you!
What? You don't think
I see it in your eyes?
You're judging me.
You always have.
Hey.
You have no idea how
much I care about you.
How much I value our friendship!
Hey, we haven't been
close since college.
You think that's
my fault, Jackson?
Look, Jackson, I've tried.
I've tried for seven
years to be your friend.
And I'll try for the next seven.
But now that means
getting in your face.
Because you can't push
this off any longer.
You can't keep running
from everything
that makes you feel pain.
You might find out
the pain isn't so bad.
It means that something
matters, Jackson.
Elizabeth left me.
I figured.
It's just that
I'm falling behind at
work and my dad's dying.
And I'm going to be
all alone in the world.
What about Kat?
She's nice.
I'm not used to that.
And she lives in
Asheville and I don't.
I think she's good
for you in any regard.
I think it's worth
making an exception for.
What is?
Love.
Have you ever been in love?
I love my dad.
I know you love your dad.
That's not the question.
I don't know, I
mean I've told girls
that I loved them before,
but it's never been...
Well, it's always
been safe and easy.
Just regular sex with
someone I care about.
Everything but that feeling.
What are you laughing at?
No. Nothing. It's just...
If we hadn't spent
the last hour fucking,
I'd swear you weren't a man.
I'm not a man?
No, not so much.
Men just want sex.
Wow.
That's all I want.
Yeah, I know.
You're...
I'm what?
I don't know.
Guys my age they
just close their eyes
and go straight ahead
like I'm not even there.
Well that sounds
incredibly romantic.
But your eyes are open.
I can't take my eyes off you.
I like that.
Yeah, me too.
What is it?
What?
It's the, I'm sorry, it's
the music. I kind of...
You don't like James Cooper?
It spoiled the moment.
No, I hate this song.
It's amazing. I listen to
it every night before bed.
Do you know what it's about?
Okay, well, I know
it sounds sad,
but it's about this guy
who's in a relationship
with this girl
who keeps on hurting him.
And then by the end of the song,
he lets you know that
he's going to find someone
who deserves his love.
And he says,
close your eyes, come to me,
tomorrow's where
you're meant to be.
Her tears are wet,
complexion streaked
the love that you
have yet to meet.
You okay?
Yeah.
I feel like I'm
behind enemy lines.
Your mom was
uncomfortable here too.
Is that why you broke up?
It's never one thing.
We were meant for
certain people.
She wasn't my soul mate.
But she gave me you.
I feel like he's
looking at me.
Like he knows I'm Jewish.
God doesn't have an ego.
He doesn't care what
religion you are.
Tell that to the
Christian right.
Why do you have to
judge an entire faith
on its most irrational faction?
Let's go, okay?
I'm fine, okay. Let's
just get out of here.
Whoa, whoa, what happened?
Nothing. Okay? Just...
Did he do something to you?
No. It was my fault, okay.
There is nothing you could
have done that could...
Hey!
I hit him, okay?
With a golf club.
Many, many times.
So let's just get out of here.
Sorry about the room.
Taking you back
to my dying father
seemed even less you know...
Cheers.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, you know, I have
to tell you something.
And I'm not sure how
you're going to take it.
I'm really worried that
you're going to hate me.
No matter what it is...
Just don't speak for a minute.
When you showed up, my life
was really complicated.
Kevin has been my fuck
buddy for some time now.
Even when I've had
other boyfriends, I
I don't know, with you,
I just don't want to.
And he doesn't understand?
No.
He understands, I just...
I freaked out.
God, you're going to hate me.
I'm not going to hate you.
Not yet.
Wait until you see
who I really am.
I'm a whore.
You're not a whore.
This is what I'm
trying to tell you.
Men use me for sex all the time,
and I let them use me.
You are not a whore.
Every time I say
"Never again" and...
It doesn't matter.
But it does matter.
Not to me.
It does matter!
What good is my love if I've
given it to so many men?
Oh, this is a bad idea.
I shouldn't have
told you, I just...
I don't know. I thought if
I got it out of me that...
I don't, I don't
know what I thought.
We should go.
We need to go, okay! Come on.
Please, I just want to go.
Come here.
I know you've been hurt.
Over and over and over again.
And you still managed to
see the best in people.
Have you got any idea
how amazing that is?
You made me find something.
Let's go get it.
They'll look for
a nurse this week.
You're sure you have to leave?
I got to find a new job
before I lose all my clients.
That bad.
I was holding it
together with Scotch tape
and baling wire before this.
I'm so proud of you.
I was terrified when you
got back from Durham.
I didn't sleep for months.
You never said a word.
You don't tell those
things to your kid.
You pulled yourself back up
and carved yourself a life.
I wish I understood you.
Don't waste time trying.
You're going to wake up
one morning and be me.
Life happens. No matter what.
You uh...
You'll get credit for
what you don't deserve,
blame for things that
weren't your fault.
You just have to stick
around for the rest.
Eh...
Eh.
Let's shoot some pool.
How'd it go with Ben?
Okay, I guess.
Tell him you love him?
It didn't come up.
He probably knows, but
you'll regret it anyway.
You should say it.
You certainly say it a lot.
I love you a lot.
I know.
You do?
It's the only thing
I've ever been sure of.
Nice.
One more game?
What can I say? The
man likes to lose.
Rack ¢em up!
Oh, I can't get
comfortable anymore.
Open the glove compartment.
This?
Medical marijuana.
What's your disease?
What kind of father
do you think I am?
I like this song.
That's enough.
Leaving for the night?
Yeah.
I told Kat I would stop by.
You're seeing a lot of her.
Yeah.
Okay.
Jack.
Yeah?
Thanks for coming down here.
It means a lot to me.
I love you.
I love you too, Dad.
You know, I was thinking
we could turn this
couch into a bed.
Sheets, blankets,
the whole nine yards.
That won't be necessary.
I could bring
your bed down here.
It was just a thought.
The professor is
completely biased
against anything
made in this country.
And I'm like, "Come on,
you teach American film."
It's so frustrating.
You know, why does
something has to be
in another language or just
incredibly obscure
to be artistic?
Are you listening?
You know, sometimes
the most simple,
direct things are
the most beautiful.
Kat...
I love you.
What?
I'm sorry.
I had to get that out there
or I was going to burst.
You don't have to say anything.
Okay, say something.
You're the most amazing girl.
But?
I've got to go back to L.A.
And this isn't right for me.
I wish I had met
you five years ago.
I wish I could be that guy.
I can't. Too much has happened.
You understand?
Too much has...
I know this is a bad time but
it's really essential that
you call me for Peter back.
They're not going to cover our
September or August expenses.
You need to call me back.
We're talking business affairs.
It's signed.
Have a drink. Celebrate.
Not tonight.
Is everything all right, Jeff?
It'll be fine.
He and Jackson were close.
Did you regret it?
I don't believe in regret.
I believe in mistakes.
Regret makes it sound like
you can actually do
something about it.
This isn't even my robe.
Come on, Kat!
Open up, Kat!
For better or for worse,
my actions have
made me who I am.
Writing that book
was a terrible idea.
But if I hadn't done it,
I'd be a different person
and I'd be in a different place.
I'd be with a different girl.
I'd be with no girl.
Dad!
Yes. I'd like to report a...
My dad is dead.
Why don't you watch
where you're going?
You got something to say, boy?
What'd you say?
Ugh!
I wasn't ready.
I wasn't ready to see you back.
Stay.
Stay in Asheville.
I can't.
I love you.
And you love me.
You can't say it
and that's okay.
But I know you do.
My life is here.
This is your life.
No.
Me. Ben. Foster.
Alison. We love you.
You're so fixated on this idea
of what you think your
life should look like
that you can't even see
what's really going on.
Right now! Here!
This is your life.
And it¢s going to hurt
for a little while.
But you just have
to do it anyway.
I'm not going to leave you.
Jackson.
What is this?
Tragic news from Los Angeles.
Asheville
native, Jackson murdered
in late Saturday evening.
Son of longtime
Democrat columnist...
Huh?
Thanks, big dog.
Hey!
Give me...
Get down! Get back down!
You want to play
somebody with a gun?
What's his name, man?
Dude, dude, dude, dude.
Jackson White,
man. Jackson White.
Let's go man. Let's go, D.
Jackson.
Look at me!
Yo, come on, D.
30 years...
Suspect is still at large.
It's okay.
Go.
I love you too.
I know.
Jesus.
Looks like a...
How many days?
Keep him behind the yellow line.
What's the
official time of death?
3:19am.
No!
Now do you know what happened?
I'm dead.
For a few weeks now.
We should go.
Are you God?
I'm afraid not.
An angel.
Just think of me as a friend.
I've always been
looking out for you.
I'm not the only one.
Just listen to the
people who surrounds you.
I'm not sure that one
life can mean anything.
One life can change the world.
You might find out
that pain isn't so bad.
That means that something
matters, Jackson.
Can't leave things unsaid.
Are we still friends?
Always brother.
Always.
You might be meeting
someone who lets you know.
But he's going to find
someone who deserves his love.
I'll never get to say good-bye.
You already have.
Did you ever lose someone
whose absence shook
your very core?
Then one day you felt
a flood of warmth
and the pain was gone, leaving
only those memories of love.
Everyone makes this journey
and your love never
leaves this earth.
Foster and Alison will help.
They become a family, united
by their love for you.
And Kat?
It's harder for her.
She'll never meet her soul mate.
Most people can deal with
a lesser lot in life.
You see them everywhere.
Living life out of habit.
She's not that resilient.
She'll wake up one morning
with an inexplicable sadness
she can no longer carry.
Kat! No!
Don't worry.
She will find you.
Same way you found her.
In this world or the next.
It doesn't matter.
We all find our love.
Jackson.
You have to finish this
journey on your own.
But you're going to be okay.
It was such a
pleasure to know you.
This is where we say good-bye.
Wait!
What happens now?
You live.
Live.
Welcome home.