I have cancer.
Of course not. It's an ulcer.
You're complaining.
Give me a glass of wine.
- It isn't good for you.
It's good for your heart.
There's nothing wrong with your heart.
- That's what you say.
It's cold here.
It's June.
Shall I fetch you something else?
Yes?
Alex?
- Yes.
It's Aram.
Shouldn't you pick it up?
It's not nice to hang up
on your brother, Alex.
It's been a long time.
- You can say that again.
Mum is severely ill.
What's wrong?
- Her stomach.
Do you still live at home?
Yes. But I have to go away
for a few days.
Christ, Alex.
Do it for mother, not for me.
Will you come?
Yes.
Who was that?
That was my brother.
You have to get dressed.
Won't you tell me your name first?
You should go to bed.
My name's Sandra.
Drive on or we'll have an accident.
Go on, ask.
What?
You want to know
what I'm doing in your car.
You must have your reasons.
Everyone has their reasons.
Well ask then.
What are you doing in this car?
It's none of your business.
It's my car.
It's my life.
Let me drive.
- Do you have a driving licence?
No.
Don't you trust me?
Are you sure it's here?
Yes.
Completely?
- Completely.
I'm not sure.
It looks so quiet.
That's right,
there's no one around.
Are you sure?
We'll go inside,
take that thing and walk out.
I think it's guarded.
I told you before.
Eugene said there's no one here.
And you're sure it's here?
Why visit your mother so late?
- She's ill.
What's the matter with her?
Something about her stomach.
Is your father there?
He's dead.
Does your mother live all alone?
No. My brother lives at home.
Oh. It's not there.
Are they expecting you?
- Yes.
And the key is always there?
I haven't been here for a long time.
How long?
Long.
You don't know how long it is
since you saw your mother?
Alex?
Jesus Christ.
Just keep breathing calmly.
I don't understand.
What don't you?
The only way he could shoot me
was through you.
I don't understand.
And where's Eugene?
He should have been here long ago.
Maybe he won't come.
Eugene always keeps his word.
You don't want anything, girl?
It's good for your heart.
And you, Alex?
- No. Thanks.
It's up to you.
I'm so happy you're home again.
Are you warm enough?
It's June, Mum.
- It feels cold.
It's a pity Aram has to work.
You don't want any coffee?
I want to sleep.
We've been up all-night.
What does Aram does for a living?
- But haven't seen your mother for years.
We've been up all night. I'm exhausted.
I never see you.
I want to enjoy having you here.
I'm staying a while.
- Really?
You're staying a while?
- Yes.
How long?
- That depends. A while.
Until you get better.
- There's nothing wrong.
Aram said you were ill.
I cough up blood.
- That's not normal.
You should see a doctor.
- I thought so, but Aram refused.
He doesn't like doctors.
I may have cancer.
We'll go to the doctor tomorrow.
I'm sure my stomach won't kill me.
My heart is weak, like my mother's.
We'll check that too.
Sweden, Holland, Germany, Britain...
All monarchies, except Germany.
Your turn.
Jesus, Buddha, Mohammed or Bhishma...
Or who?
- Bhishma from the Mahabharata.
It must be him.
- That's right.
I don't think he's coming.
- Of course he is.
He must have heard what happened.
He won't come.
So you are Sandra.
And you are Alex.
I never met an Alex before.
You're my first Sandra.
What's your brother like?
Why doesn't he take
your mother to the doctor?
My mother used to go every week.
There was always something.
Where the hell are we?
- Home.
You can meet my mother at last.
I'm thirsty.
- I'll get you something later.
I'm thirsty now.
- When you're lying down.
What happened?
Nothing to worry about.
Who's that?
- Wouter. Nice to meet you.
You have to see a doctor.
We don't have to do anything.
- And certainly not see a doctor.
He can't lie on the sofa.
Why not?
- He'll get it dirty. Take him to bed.
He can lie in Alex's room.
- No, Alex is there.
Is he back?
I want the sofa.
- With his new girlfriend.
I say.
- I'm thirsty.
Do you have any Chinese beer?
- No, sorry.
Christ almighty!
You know I drink Chinese beer.
I thought you'd be away for days.
I haven't gone shopping yet.
Excuses! A good housewife
always has beer for visitors.
We never have visitors.
- What about me, goddamnit?!
I've been back five minutes
and I'm already regretting it.
How are you?
Why did you take photos of me?
I'm a photographer.
Is it nice?
- Delicious.
I thought as much.
Everyone sleeps here all day.
Shall I wake up Alex?
He was very tired.
Isn't it nice and quiet;
just the two of us?
Did you quarrel?
Oh my god, what happened?
No. We've never quarrelled.
This is nice?
- Great.
What are the pills for?
Nothing special.
If you can't tell your mother-in-law,
who can you tell?
It would only worry you.
- No, really.
Epilepsy.
- Oh God...
It's nothing to worry about.
I take my medicine.
Medicine?
- Against attacks.
Attacks?
No need for hysteria.
It's years since I had an attack.
The pills take care of that.
Does Alex know?
It hasn't come up yet.
May I use the bathroom?
Good morning!
- Good morning.
I should say good afternoon.
I'll make you some hot chocolate.
- Great!
Hot chocolate for the late sleeper.
If you say please, at least.
Please at least.
No, just please.
- Just please.
We are in a good mood.
- Stop that!
Who are you?
You must be Alex.
How do you know who I am?
Right description: identical,
but with a loser's look on his face.
Who said that?
- Me. You heard.
Which is the odd one out:
Jesus, Mohammed, Buddha or Bhishma?
The last one.
You're guessing.
You don't know who he is.
Bhishma was invincible and
could decide when he would die.
Who told you about me?
Where's my brother?
What are you doing?
I'm blowing the milk back.
- I can see that. Throw it away.
What's wrong with the milk?
- Throw it away, I said.
Sandra?
Aram is here. With a friend.
Then I can meet him.
What did I give you
for your birthday?!
Oh yes.
Don't look a gift horse in the mouth.
Especially when you need the gift
and the giver is present.
I don't know how it works.
- I explained it four times!
Pour a glass of milk.
Give it to me.
That's not difficult, is it?
Think you can do that next time?
Who's this then?
Another late sleeper.
Good morning.
Would you like hot chocolate?
Where is Sandra?
Hello little brother.
Hi, Aram. How are you?
- Oh, fine so far.
Would you like some hot chocolate?
- Yes.
If you say please, at least.
- Please at least.
Where's Sandra?
- Who the hell is Sandra?
Alec's girlfriend. She takes pills.
- Pills?
Against the attacks.
- What kind of attacks?
She has attacks of fury.
- Really?
She told me herself.
She foams at the mouth without the pills.
I didn't notice that.
- She keeps it secret from you.
It's because of the children.
- Children? We don't have any.
All you have to do
is add some cocoa...
How are you?
Bad.
Are you in pain?
What did you think?
What are we doing here?
Waiting for Eugene to call.
- Shouldn't you call him?
That's not a good idea.
You're not professional. Get focused.
Leave your brother out of it.
Two birds with one stone.
You're messing up.
What's the matter these days?
You were to be away for a few days?
- Yes.
But I didn't want to leave
those boring sleepy fossils.
How can a fossil be sleepy?
What?
A fossil is dead.
So it already dropped off.
What are you trying to say?
You can't say "sleepy fossil".
Just like white snow.
It's a pleonasm.
Are you saying I'm stupid enough
to utter a pleonasm?
You think you're cleverer than me?
Did you know "white snow"
was a pleonasm?
Try to think one up with Alex.
What you mean?
- A pleonasm with Alex. Dot dot Alex.
I'll help you.
Dumb Alex.
Come on.
- Now you, damn it!
Boring Alex.
- Good. Another one.
Cowardly Alex.
- Stinking Alex.
Disgusting Alex.
Unmannered Alex.
Send in the next.
Hello doctor.
Sit down.
Did you come along anyway?
- I'm Alex. Aram's brother.
Alex lets me come to the doctor.
I checked your mother last week.
Nothing wrong with her heart.
She's completely fit.
- It's her stomach.
Are you cold, or what?
I'll be honest.
I'm Alex's brother.
You're Aram?
- Well...
So Alex did mention me.
- Not that you...
Are his twin brother?
Half an hour older. It's strange.
We don't meet for years and
then have about the same haircut.
Wasn't I good to you?
Wouter, this is Sandra.
Sandra, Wouter.
Hello.
- Hello.
Aram?
- Yes?
Wasn't I good to you?
You always were.
- I always asked you on a job.
I appreciate that.
And you know who I ask for?
Who for?
- I ask for you.
You're a real Christian.
- It's nothing.
No, you're really good to me.
- It's nothing. You're capable.
No, I really appreciate it.
- Unnecessary to repeat yourself.
You're right, sorry.
- Yes, quite unnecessary.
It can give you heart problems.
There's nothing wrong
with your heart.
The pills can give me palpitations.
It says so.
Just take them.
They're good for you.
Alex?
- Yes?
Couldn't you work in the garage?
You know I'm not very handy.
Your father would have loved it.
It hurts.
- Pain is in the head.
I'm dying.
He has to go to a doctor.
- I don't have to go anywhere.
Sandra, can you get a drink?
Are you afraid of death?
No.
I know what you think.
I bet you don't.
You think Wouter
should see a doctor.
What do you have
against doctors?
Anyone can be a doctor.
Anyone can be ill.
Pain and illness are in your head.
Don't you know a nice story, Alex?
He always told those lovely stories,
just like his father.
I'm right out of nice stories.
- Goodness, I wonder why?
Alex's father was the best storyteller.
And your father?
No, he was a good liar.
What a pity. Theo's stories
took people's breath away.
He was also the best car mechanic.
What does your father do?
He's in jail because of me.
Theo could repair a car
by looking at it.
It's a pity nothing happens
in the garage.
You don't do anything?
- No.
He stopped work a year after you left.
Now it all just rots.
My mother is very ill.
What did the doctor say?
Nothing, but I could see
it was serious.
And now he's doing tests.
We'll know more in a few days.
Christ almighty.
- Yes, you can say that again.
I'm glad I came back.
Why didn't you say
you had a twin brother?
I didn't?
No.
We're making a report about
a working woman in this area.
Don't you want photos
of me at work?
Yes. But that's for later.
What do you most
like photographing?
Animals.
Everything except people.
Why?
- Look what I have for you, Sandra.
I used to wear it myself.
Put it on.
It'll suit her.
That child dresses so badly.
- What makes you say that?
All that crap on her face,
just like Babylon.
Mum!
- Well, it's true.
Yes, lovely!
What do you think?
I don't know. Maybe
I have to get used to it.
Get used to it? It looks lovely.
Take a good look, Alex.
I want to go,
to take some photos.
I'll come along.
We'll have to walk.
- Try again.
I used to play here.
It's lovely.
- Yes.
Will you take pictures here?
They'd be postcard landscapes.
- Rubbish.
Maybe you're right.
There's a nice spot.
It's a lovely background, isn't it, Alex?
Very nice.
I'll stand there.
- But of course.
It's going wrong.
Did I do something wrong?
I can't take pictures of people.
It goes wrong if
a person crosses my lens.
How long has it been like that?
Quite a while.
Maybe I should do
something else.
Yes, maybe.
I could work in the garage.
Will you call him?
- No, not yet.
You have to call him.
We messed up.
- What makes you think that?
I...
I messed up.
Can I ask?
What happened?
I once photographed
a terrible accident.
By accident.
It happened while
I pressed the shutter.
I burned the film.
I didn't even dare develop it.
You trust me, don't you?
I have to pee.
I'll go with you.
- No, I want to pee outside.
I'll work on my car.
I could kick that jack away.
Aram?
- Since when do you repair cars?
Since today.
Maybe you should be a mechanic.
- Yes, maybe.
You never were a good photographer.
- And you know all about that?
Well the last session I attended
wasn't very impressive.
I don't want to talk about it.
It was your idea, damn it.
Mum, have you seen Sandra?
Did you set fire to that thing?
- No. Why should I?
Be nice to each other.
How long since you last met?
Not long enough.
Are you expecting a call?
You?
Will someone pick it up?
Alex speaking...
Yes, I'll be right there.
Who was that?
Just an acquaintance.
- Which acquaintance?
You don't know him.
- How d'you know?
Let it be, Aram.
The doctor called.
- And?
I have to come round.
It didn't sound good.
Does she know?
No.
Why are you so nasty to your brother?
- Because he's a fool.
He's a good photographer.
You don't win prizes for nothing.
Have you watched him
all these years, then?
You should be proud of him.
He wants to be a car mechanic.
- Oh yes? Since when?
Why d'you love him more than me?
He didn't call for years.
- He's busy.
Who stayed here?
Who took over the business?
For two years,
then you stopped.
And now you think Alex will
take care of it? I know you.
Alex could be a good mechanic.
- Rubbish.
Dad was proud of me,
you know that.
Your father is dead.
Do you notice people treating you
as a woman?
What do you mean?
- People think doctors should be men.
Sometimes.
But most male patients don't mind.
They may even prefer it.
That never causes tension?
Why are male doctors
never asked that?
There's something on your face.
- What?
A smudge. On your face.
It's your turn.
What do you do for a living?
You first.
- Car mechanic.
Hairdresser.
- God, that's nice.
Aram!
- Did you cut Alex's hair?
No? What's all this? Why not?
I'm really still learning.
- Aram!
One moment.
Aram!
Yes, what's up?
I'm thirsty.
- But there's no beer.
Where's your mother?
- What? Gone somewhere.
There must be something
to drink in the house.
To be honest,
I may have been exaggerating.
Really?
I only had a couple of lessons.
Then you need some more practice.
I only worked with the dummy,
not real people.
What are you doing?
I'm having my hair styled.
You're wearing rollers.
You don't say...
Shouldn't someone look at that?
Don't you mind me exaggerating?
- Of course.
But it's water under the bridge.
I have something to admit too.
I haven't been a car mechanic for years.
Honesty lasts longer.
My mother always said that.
- How sensible.
Shall we promise to be honest
with each other now?
No more lies?
- Nothing but the truth!
Ask me something.
Don't you ever wear shoes?
- No shoes, no socks.
Never?
- Not ever.
Why not?
Do you know Abbey Road?
- Who gave Wouter curls?
Aram.
Hello, Eugene.
I was about to call.
Of course not... Just a scratch.
I have to talk to you.
Of course you can.
My mother has cancer.
She only has a couple of months.
Christ.
How are you going to tell her?
She wouldn't believe it.
She always thought
she'd die of a heart attack.
And now?
I don't know.
I can't leave now.
Take a look.
That's cheeky.
Christ, what do we want
with an animal?
It's nice for mum.
A rabbit, like the old days.
The past is gone.
- The past never dies.
Big words from my little brother.
If you'd been that clever,
your father might still live.
It was an accident.
- Oh yes?
Yes, you know that as well as I do.
How lovely, a rabbit!
Guess what I won at bingo?
A trip round the world!
- It's only the village bingo.
You'll never guess.
- Tell us.
No, you guess.
- Something for the living room?
It's a cake. Who'd have thought?
Can I take out the curlers?
- Alex, did you think it was a cake?
Of course not.
- Can I take them out, or what?
I bought Chinese beer too.
Our father, who art in Heaven,
hallowed by thy name...
Amen.
More respect for the Word of God
would not be misplaced.
He was part of me.
- But not worth a dig?
We have laborers for that.
You want to be a laborer, don't you?
That's no way to be buried.
- It happens the way I say.
I didn't like it, the last time
I listened to you.
We wouldn't mention it again.
- Also your idea.
God, you have bad ideas.
You think it's so easy for me?
What d'you think it meant to me?
The poor boy can't take
any more pictures.
You were the one who left,
you bastard. Now dig!
You thought you could
get round Mum with a rabbit?
You think that's why
I captured the beast?
Dad mechanic, you mechanic.
Dad rabbit, you rabbit.
You're crazy.
Give that dirty mess to me.
I'll put it in the wash with
the rest of your clothes.
The rest? They weren't dirty.
They stank.
A microwave damages the health.
So does smoking.
My health isn't important.
Those microwaves
could make you impotent.
If you climb inside.
What will Sandra think if you stop taking
pictures and become a mechanic?
She'll understand.
- Oh really? You think so?
You think Sandra with her skinny
yet delicious body would agree?
Why treat the animal like that?
Your boyfriend has strange ideas
about rabbits.
Did you put it in, Alex?
- No, of course not.
I think I'll leave you alone
to sort it out.
You can quarrel in peace.
- We're not quarrelling.
Are you still mad at me?
Can you give this to Alex?
What is it?
- Open it.
It was years ago.
Alex gave them to me. I thought...
...he might want them back.
Aram gave me this.
Don't you want to see them?
Who's that woman?
She used to be our doctor.
And the man?
That's my father.
Aram said you gave them to him.
That's right.
I followed my father.
I thought something was going on.
Did your mother know?
No.
We never told her.
It would have broken her.
How long did this go on?
I don't remember exactly.
At a certain point it was all over.
She probably moved.
You think Aram was involved?
I don't know.
A little to the left.
It's still there.
Stop taking pictures
and do something about it.
Goodnight.
Have you been awake long?
All night.
What's worrying you?
Aram.
I think he's creepy.
He's changed.
Why is he always barefoot?
I don't know.
Things used to be different.
If I look in his eyes,
I can't feel anything anymore.
...Yours is the kingdom, the power
and the glory, for ever and ever...
...Amen.
I'm pleased you behaved this time.
There they are.
Aram!
Eugene!
Isn't Wouter here?
He didn't make it.
Eugene doesn't like that, Aram.
You know that.
I know.
Where is the corpse?
That isn't right, Aram.
I know.
That's not what we agreed.
Just creep in,
take the things and go.
That always worked out in the past.
A man in my position
can't tolerate this.
If I didn't have position, it would
be no problem. But I have a position.
You certainly have one, Eugene.
I shall never deny it.
I understand.
Piss on the grave, Esther.
I say, Eugene.
You say what?
You had enough to drink.
Let this be a lesson to you, Aram.
It certainly is, Eugene.
I have a respectable business
and want to keep it that way.
Now let's have a barbecue.
We're going to have a barbecue.
But we're just having dinner.
Delicious stew.
With all due respect,
I thought something more festive.
I have chickens in the car,
beef and wine.
Let's have a good time.
You'll have to change, Alex.
Would you like some wine?
- Oh, please.
I don't know if it's a good idea.
What does Aram do for a living?
He's always so vague.
Aram works for Eugene.
- Exactly. And usually very well.
I'll take you to bed, Mum.
You shouldn't drink too much wine.
It's not good for your stomach.
Nothing wrong with my stomach.
My mother died of a heart attack,
and her mother too.
That doesn't mean you'll have problems.
You have a healthy heart.
Thanks to the wine.
Go to sleep.
Alex?
Yes?
I'm glad you're here.
Yes, so am I.
Your father would be pleased
the garage is being used again.
Yes, I miss him too.
You're so like him.
You think so?
Come here.
I'm so proud of you.
I'm glad of that.
Dad loved you a lot too.
Your collar is wrong, Theo.
I'm Alex.
That took a long time.
- I had to take my mother to bed.
I was going to look for you.
Hide and seek!
- That's a good idea.
Don't we have business to settle?
- Aram, you're too serious.
The night is young.
Let's play hide and seek.
Now?
- Yes, hide and seek.
You know what it is?
You can use the whole house.
You have something of mine.
It's outside.
... 50! I'm coming!
Is that you, Theo?
- It's me, Alex.
I trust you, Aram.
- I know.
I won't look in the box.
I know what's there.
I wouldn't be insulted if you counted.
I trust you too, Eugene.
- That's good.
It's time to have a rest, Aram.
I'm tired.
- I know.
Found you.
I thought you'd never find me here.
I can't get down.
Are you stuck?
- I think so.
Do you still love me, Theo?
I'm Alex, mum.
Were you working late?
We're playing hide and seek.
Aren't you a bit old for that?
You're sweet.
Esther, let's go.
Our mission is completed.
Say thanks to Aram.
Thanks.
You don't have to go.
Don't you want to stay?
No, it's up to you now.
You're my favourite employee, Aram.
- I'm glad of that.
It's been such a long time, Theo.
Mum, don't.
What do you see in Alex?
- He's very kind to me.
What you think about his brother?
He's not bad.
I'm going to look for Alex.
- Just call out loud.
That'll wake your mother.
Theo... Theo...
Where could he be?
Alex is good at hide and seek.
Theo...
Jesus Christ.
I don't think this is normal.
It's just like a slaughtered pig.
But then without blood.
I did First Aid.
Sandra is a strange girl, Alex.
I think she's better now.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
You don't do things like that.
- Certainly not.
I think I should be punished.
No, just don't do it again.
- No, I have to be punished.
One hard blow should be enough.
Come on.
One hard blow.
Is that all?
- Yes.
I got off lightly.
- Yes, I think so too.
Failure is human,
forgiveness is divine.
It's all right.
It's nice and clean.
Do you understand greenfly?
What do you mean?
- There isn't a single greenfly.
But when it gets sick,
it'll be covered in greenfly.
They can smell a sick plant?
- That's the nice bit.
A strong plant is left alone,
a weak one is consumed.
I understand that much
about the greenfly.
So what don't you understand?
- Where are they now?
They must be somewhere.
When it's sick, you see hundreds.
Where do the greenfly come from?
Have you never thought about that?
- No, not really.
I have, boy.
Maybe they warn
each other with walkie-talkies.
Don't you take anything seriously?
Is everything a joke?
Why so serious?
- Your jokes made father commit suicide.
It was an accident.
- What do you know?
The police said so.
- Don't always believe them.
Why on earth should Dad kill himself?
- The man was unhappy.
So am I.
- But you're a coward.
A weakling.
You'd rather be eaten by greenfly.
Where were you this morning?
You were sleeping so soundly.
I got the fright of my life
when I woke up.
Ah, you did?
You're the one
with some explaining to do.
If you mean last night,
that was nothing.
My mother was confused.
You want me to hurt her
in her last few months?
You're mad at me,
aren't you?
No, I just don't know how to cope.
How long will you go on like this?
Like what?
When something happens,
you just stand there and watch.
You can't replace your father.
I'm not trying to.
You do his work,
you wear his clothes.
We have to leave here, Alex.
You're thinking of your mother,
but Aram isn't good for you.
I had a call.
Who from?
From a client.
You not saying you're going to leave?
- No, Alex is staying a while.
I'm afraid I have to go.
You promised.
- What do you have to do?
A job. Photography.
- Can't you do it here?
No. I have to leave tomorrow.
- Don't stay away so long this time.
You can't leave.
- I decide about my own life.
Your life is mine too.
We aren't finished, Alex.
You know that as well as I do.
Alex, we're leaving.
It was your fault too, Alex.
I didn't want it.
- Don't lie.
Who produced those photos
of her and Dad?
It was your idea.
Are you so sure of that?
I knew what you thought, Alex.
I always knew what you thought.
I didn't want it.
- Don't lie.
I did what you wanted.
You were too scared.
After that I didn't know
what you thought anymore.
You're just as guilty as me, Alex.
Say it.
Say it!
I'm just as guilty.
Same with Dad's death.
It was an accident.
- Really?
Yes, you know that.
- It was suicide.
You only say that to hurt me.
It was suicide.
- Stop it.
Dad did it because she was dead.
- I said stop it.
You really think he was stupid enough
to drive into the water?
Your father killed himself
because we made his life pointless.
You're lying!
You knew all along, Alex.
You always thought so.
- You're lying...
You're lying! You're lying!
Maybe.
I still wonder whether
it's high enough.
Of course it is.
I pushed.
I can't do it.