[DOOR E & M]
Timing and Subtitles brought to you
by 🎇The Blessed Team🎇 @ Viki.com
Is it done? Are you in?
Hey, Jaemin? Park Jaemin!
Yeah, I'm in.
Stop calling my name
out, it's distracting me.
This is harder than I thought. The
hash rate alone is similar to Ethereum.
A 51% attack won't work then.
Perhaps an old-school move.
What about cryptojacking?
Do you even know what that means?
Why crawl through all of
this to get here then?
Hey, I'm the one crawling here. Keep
me updated on external developments.
They haven't noticed yet but be quick.
I just have to plant the code.
Yeah?
Well, I have the day off tomorrow.
Come on now.
I thought it would be nice to take
the kids out for a drive for once
but you are being so difficult.
I'm tired too!
I want to do nothing
but rest on my day off.
It's nothing.
Wait, I'll call you back.
What is this?
These damn kids.
Leaving things behind.
Why are you out of breath?
What happened?
Did you lose something?
Like some loser in a movie?
Was that the sound of a door closing?
My palms are so sweaty. The tension is
like watching a Premier League game.
The North London Derby, the
Northwest Derby, and United vs City!
Calm down. It's just a routine patrol.
I got it. Just hurry up and
tell me how to get out of here.
Being stuck here is
making me claustrophobic.
Get out now, hurry!
Listen here, young man.
I wonder why you were
hiding out in the dark
doing something you shouldn't be?
- A corporate spy, perhaps?
- Do something.
- Just wait.
- Do what?
What shall we do?
I did it! I turned it off!
I turned the lights off!
It only buys us 60 seconds. Hurry.
We're toast if you're caught!
To the right.
- Not there.
- You aren't going to say our names, right?
[10]
[7F]
[4F Down] [5F Up]
[2/1]
[Entrance]
In this day and age,
we do have elevators you know.
You ungrateful punk! We saved you!
Who saved who?
The elevators were stalled,
I had no other choice.
We're in trouble.
What now?
Overtime sucks, right?
Ever heard of server
management with flexible hours?
A dream job that guarantees
a work-life balance.
Probably only at Google.
Just wait! This is a misunderstanding.
Backpack. Black clothes. Even I
think I look like a corporate spy.
We have a man wearing a mask
with a backpack and a black hat.
Hold on!
Is it too obvious that this
is a movie about hackers?
The story of a genius
hacker seeking justice.
Something like that?
Well.
My actual life is much less
exciting than that. [2018]
You know the type.
Your typical tragic hero.
We all have to eat to survive.
Let's eat first.
We'll talk afterward.
How can you eat right now?
Don't eat then, jerk.
Why are you so busy?
What about my calls?
I don't know why I have to
be so busy all the time.
My salary can barely cover my family.
Being a civil servant,
I can't even work two jobs.
Can you get me a new job?
Also,
you aren't the only person I talk to.
Don't call me on my personal phone.
Is it my father's case?
Here, take a look.
Look. See how many I have?
Take a look! See how many people there are?
Over 80 suspects, including
those without an indictment.
All of them are our cases.
I'm not your private detective.
How long has it been since
you promised to catch them?
You said hackers did that to my dad.
Isn't it your job to lock up
sons of bitches like that?
Was the investigation done right?
You rude brat, that's our team
leader you are talking to.
Are we your local police station?
Who are you to berate
us with your bullshit?
That's enough. Finish your meal.
But, Sir, this isn't right.
We've sat here listening for long enough.
My father died because you fuckers
couldn't catch the criminals.
That's enough.
Jaemin.
Those criminals are very organized and
their IP addresses are all foreign now.
So, we can't track down their location.
They had 12 proxy servers.
It's a long shot even with the
cybercrime unit and the others.
We need approval for that to even happen.
But things got quiet after that, so
we couldn't even issue a red notice.
That's our situation right now.
How about this?
We focus our investigation on
your father's acquaintances,
- and look for financial ties or grieva...
- My father never did anyone wrong.
My father was a good man.
- Right.
- Sir! You have a call.
I know. He was a good man but...
Finish your meal, okay?
It's good.
That's the day I realized
that the world has no regard for my pain.
No one had time for my pitiful tragedy.
Not one.
Someone once said,
"To protect your house from thieves,
you must think like a thief."
That's the truth.
To catch hackers, I must become a hacker.
That's why I decided to be a hacker.
[HEX - Twenty Hacker]
[Romantic Hacker: Black and White]
Oh no! I'm going to be late.
Where are you going?
I'm late for fencing practice.
- I'm losing my mind.
- Are you headed to the gym?
Yeah. You too?
Yeah. I'll see you there.
Hey!
Can I ride with you?
Two is too heavy, it will break it.
What the hell, asshole!
Hey!
So much for friendship.
Increase head and chest muscles!
That's it.
Com Sci Freshman, Lee Chanho.
(Computer Science)
179cm tall but looks 182cm
due to his great figure.
Admitted as a salutatorian. Valedictorian
would have been too perfect.
A gentle soul, who prefers a
warm glass of milk over coffee.
Always practicing fencing between classes.
Makes his cruddy fencing
uniform look like Dior Homme.
A hybrid of intelligence
and physical prowess.
He's good-looking.
He's single but he's very popular.
Mr. Perfect has one thing missing.
Me, Park Joohee?
- My 28th crush-
- I can hear everything.
You scared me!
Hey, Angry Joo. Are you a "Satorare?"
What's that?
It's when your inner
thoughts are heard by others
- regardless of-
- Woo! Lee Chanho!
Lee Chanho!
What's the big deal?
That's none of your business.
I don't take questions from those
without an ounce of
friendship in their body.
Number 28.
More like number never.
- Is it him this time?
- Not another word from you.
It's not like you've helped at all.
Don't make a scene like last
time, and just sit still.
You call that a "scene?"
As your fellow classmate, who
endured that wild rollercoaster
you called "crush," I'm
feeling underappreciated.
Listen, Angry Joo. Number
16 was a total fuckboy.
- Men know men best-
- Stop!
You're not my dad!
Heads!
Park Joohee, watch out!
- Oh, no.
- Are you okay?
- Is she hurt?
- That must have hurt.
Joohee?
Are you okay?
Why aren't you answering? Hey, Joohee!
You should see a doctor.
I'll give you a ride.
I'm glad it wasn't worse.
Where is this coming from?
Is this fine dust?
Who did that?
Who blew away my protein powder?
Come out. Is it you?
Come forward right now!
I'm going to do jump rope
with your spinal cords!
- What's his deal?
- Don't look. Let's just go.
It's him.
You son of a bitch!
Yes, that's it.
Let's go, let's go.
What the hell!
I was engaged in a life or death
situation on this minefield.
Until a loser with a land
mine for a face came along.
But this land mine looks very serious.
Did someone step on you?
You're not yourself.
- What? The school server?
- Who am I really?
It's time for revenge.
Revenge.
You look like someone
that has been cheated on.
That's why you shouldn't touch
other people's belongings.
I found the bastard!
What shall I do with him now?
I've seen him somewhere.
What's up with his calm demeanor?
What's with that devil-may-care attitude?
That son of a... I'm going to find you.
When I do find you, I'll break you.
Some things are meant to be.
A symbolic line like
that at a time like this
suggests that, in most cases,
there is a high probability
that our story revolves
around this gentleman here.
Hex.
He is the protagonist.
[OZ Couple Zone]
One, two, three, four, five. Okay.
That's the face of someone
arriving 15 minutes late
to this sacred establishment,
then sneaking out of the kitchen
to pretend that he wasn't late at all.
Upon seeing me, he then blabs, "Sir,
I didn't see you when I arrived."
With a sly wave to boot.
I was late. I'm very sorry.
- What happened?
- Nothing happened at all.
Wow, you've got some nerve.
The courage to adamantly tell your
boss you were late without a reason.
I would seriously pay good money for that.
You are going places.
Thank you, sir.
Jaemin, couldn't you
just make something up?
You have exams coming up.
That's a great excuse.
Just say you were late because
you were at the library.
I'm your boss, I'm the owner
of this fine internet cafe.
- Do you have to be that honest?
- I'm a little embarrassed but
I have a full four-year
Computer Science scholarship.
I'm fine as long as I don't get an F.
Studying? I don't need it.
Are you really embarassed?
Here we go.
The hacker's motto.
Every password can be cracked
and every gate can be unlocked.
Our world of information and profits
is like a 24/7 festival you
are always plugged into.
[stack based buffer overflow]
[Stack buffer overflow]
Low security means it's
a hacker's playground.
Places with high security
become a battleground for fame.
You don't need a strong castle
wall to defend their attacks.
What you need is a sharp spear
that's ready to attack at any time.
In other words, advanced hacking skills.
The survival of the fittest.
So,
if you've stored valuables
behind poor cybersecurity,
that's all the invitation I need.
[Corporate hacking]
["Cyber Robing Hood"?...Hacking a company
[Is bad boy hacker "HEX" a
war criminal or righteous?]
- I'd like to pay.
- Yes.
[TEAM: Together Everyone Achieves More]
Oh, accounting fraud.
What else do you have?
[BW> What's the difference you
between you and YOUKNOWWHAT?]
What?
[HEX>Who are you?]
[HEX>Do you know YOUKNOWWHAT?]
[BW> What's the difference you between you and YOUKNOWWHAT?]
[HEX>Who are you?] [HEX>Do you know YOUKNOWWHAT?]
The king is here.
Found it.
Found what?
What did you find?
Were you looking for these?
Huh?
A can of beer is just what you
need at this time of the day.
I brought some to cheer up at
your boring, lonely part-time job.
You are exploding with gratitude, right?
Who else but me?
This isn't like you.
Hey,
your friend just bought you some
beer and that's your reaction?
Can you pick up some food?
Something like fried chicken!
- It's tasty.
- Hey, Angry Joo.
By the way,
- why did you come all-
- There was hardly anyone at your work.
It's going to go under soon.
It's because it's the exam period.
You have exams too.
What is it?
This is definitely destiny.
Like a match made in heaven!
I don't know what you are saying.
What is your destiny?
It's Chanho.
Chanho is your destiny.
When did you start believing in destiny?
It just... came right at me.
- So destiny just came right up to you.
- Hey, I'm serious.
There's something
different about this time.
My heart is in knots.
All right then.
Another line for your crush notebook.
Oh, the notebook?
I lost it.
I dropped it somewhere.
I don't need it anymore!
No more crushes for me.
No more crushes?
I'm going to ask him out.
What?
It's finally time for me to be brave.
Or else, it will be one
crush after another.
You don't have to be that brave.
Chanho might like shy girls-
- Anyway!
- I'm counting on you.
- For what?
We've been friends for four years.
So, who else but you?
This is my "phone a friend" chance.
Look... We went to high school with Chanho.
He had no feelings for you
then, so why would he now?
I'm only saying this for your sake.
In case he says no.
Help me out? What are good friends for?
When will I ever ask you for
a favor like this if not now?
Just once. Come on. Just this once!
[28 - Lee JanHo]
My heart just sank to my stomach.
Is it because of you?
Or... is it this brave
face that I'm putting on?
This is an impressive resume.
Woosung Bio, Mega Corp, Bando Group.
Daegun Logistics' ransomware was also his?
This is interesting.
They are all under investigation for
corruption and hiring irregularities.
The fact that he only exposed
their servers and left,
tells me that he wasn't out
to extract personal info.
He's either a psychopath
crying out for attention,
or he's looking for someone in our field.
It's one or the other.
[HEX]
- Hey, Jaemin.
- Yeah?
Do you think... I'm...
a little lame?
Why?
Chanho is a bit
out of my league, right?
Hey!
Why are you talking down to
yourself so seriously like that?
That guy... Chanho...
was a bit popular when
we were in high school.
No, he was super popular!
He could have been a K-pop
idol with a face like that.
He was academically great too.
Wasn't I also cool when we were younger?
You are sobering me up.
Was that a serious question?
Woah, you don't have to burn me like that.
You were different from Chanho.
You were the kind of type
that attracted party girls.
You had this mint chocolate vibe.
Only liked by a certain group.
Definitely controversial.
Tasted like toothpaste or chocolate.
Neither one nor the other.
They were good kids. You only
judge a book by its cover.
Also, toothpaste?
If I was toothpaste, was Chanho mouthwash?
No, no, no.
He was a classic, luxurious chocolate.
From Belgium, like Godiva?
Everyone loved Chanho.
He was smart, kind, honest.
All the teachers really liked him, too.
I got along with some teachers, too.
Oh, yeah! Remember that teacher
that was only good to Chanho?
What's next period?
Hey, hey! This isn't a flea market!
Hey, you are running down the corridor!
Join the track team if you want to run!
Punks.
Chanho, could you get the mock
exam results from my office?
You came first again. Don't study too hard.
Spare some hope for the others.
Yes, sir.
Anyway, that kid.
Always looks like he's goofing off
but his test scores are always good.
He was second again. Just below you.
Your homeroom teacher must
be happy to have both of you.
I'm just lucky.
He's a rare breed.
You didn't have to walk me home.
Chivalry is it?
Hey.
I think you two look alike.
With who?
- Mr. Park.
- You asshole! I look like my mom!
What are you doing?
You don't.
You look exactly like the dean.
The long-faced version.
Ugh, Mr. Park.
- You're asking for it!
- Hey!
Lately?
Nothing.
My dad.
The dean?
You know my situation.
There's no need to send a car.
I'll be fine on my own.
So, there is no real pressure, right?
Okay. I'll see you then.
She better be home soon.
He's still his usual self.
Yeah.
Why is it so stuffy out here?
It's hot out, right?
Yeah.
Then, shall we go?
[hacker BW]
What the hell is this?
I didn't want to go down this road but...
When a citizen is in trouble,
you call on your government to help.
I believe in you, Cyber Bureau.
Damn it.
[New Message Arrived]
What is this?
[To. Hex, We welcome you to Better World.
Press "Yes" to accept.]
I didn't even have to
ask for an invitation.
[Come to Hwarang Hall B1, Room 4]
[Deletes in 3 seconds.]
What's that?
What is it? What's up with you?
You really snuck up on me. Are you a ninja?
Is it a movie?
What movie?
Weren't you watching a spy movie?
Right! The background music.
Chanho, Hwarang Hall is where all
our school clubs are gathered. Right?
I think so.
But most of them moved
into the new hall recently.
I see.
I'm not sure which clubs are still there.
That's where the old medical
school anatomy room used to be.
It's spooky down there.
People said there are ghosts down there.
This is nuts.
Who cares if they fucking come out.
Ghosts aren't real.
There was a moth in my dress!
What?
Spill it. I have class soon.
No ghost is going to touch us like this!
I'm definitely less scared now.
This isn't so bad.
Totally less scared.
Kyungshik, when have I
ever made a bad deal?
Then my name isn't Nam Hyungsoo.
A shrewd investor!
The contrarian strategist!
The emperor of risk!
I know. I'm just slightly worried
about that contrarian investing.
You're the most successful person from
our high school friends. I know that.
Yeah, yeah. Just come and listen, okay?
It will turn your head.
I don't have the money to invest right now.
Are you doubting me?
Don't you remember that I gave you
the most money at your wedding?
That was ages ago.
Come on now. How long are you going
to live like that? Come on, Kyungshik!
You have to try living it up for once.
If you don't want Joohee on your back down
the road, you have to start preparing now.
She's in art school. There
are tuition and living costs.
Soon, she will ask you for a year abroad.
After graduation, when she's job hunting,
you think she's getting married on her own?
Fat chance if you don't
have the money these days.
You even threw your pension
away on that fried chicken shop.
All right! I'll hear what they have to say.
Just stay for one coffee!
It will change your life.
You were a teacher for 30 years,
now is the time to plan for the
rest of your life as your own boss!
This opportunity is a game-changer!
[Check your login history... There is no login
history. Check your internet access history...]
[No internet access history.
Check your download history...]
[Overview and Summary: If you want to
collect events that have occurred since...]
Who are you?
Hello.
You're that fencer.
That's right.
You're the TA, can I ask you something?
Of course.
Is Hwarang Hall down on the basement floor?
Well, there was the anatomy room.
Ah right. Was there a
school club down there?
Was the name of the club, Better...
[To. Hex, We welcome you to Better World.
Press "Yes" to accept.]
What's that?
World? Was that the name?
Better World... Better World!
- Isn't that a retro game club?
- A game club?
Everyone avoids going
there because it's scary.
Anyhow, I'm not too sure.
Anything else you want to...
Do you have any que-
Nope.
What are you doing? Open it.
You sure?
Of course, I am. Just leave it then?
No, it's just... Can't you open it?
Come on! Hurry up and open it!
You don't have to yell.
I was about to open it.
I'm totally ready. I would have
opened it if you didn't yell.
Bond. James Bond.
That was quite the entrance.
What are you going to do
about my protein powder, huh?
Welcome.
Through hacking, we strive
to create a better world.
We are a white hacker group and
that is Better World's mission.
We're not only based in South Korea,
think of us as a global club alliance.
So, under the banner of "Better
World," we help people oppose crackers-
Oppose hackers? So, you two?
But why me?
Oh my goodness! Is someone after me?
Why would they? What are you?
Why you and what are you?
I am-
Stop! No, that's not what he's asking.
We aren't interested in you at all.
It's your friend.
You've got the wrong idea.
He's not that kind of person.
He's nothing, really.
What? What do you mean I'm nothing?
We need you. Your skills to be precise.
The very skill that made you reach
the top ten at Def Con as a junior.
The Korean team won thanks
to your skills, right?
What is this? A detective agency?
You've got the wrong guy.
Join Better World. You're
going to need us too.
It's a win-win.
Do we have to do it like this?
I don't like the way it looks.
Well, I don't either.
Thanks for the fun meeting.
Hey, you think we spent our precious time
on you because we liked your lousy resume?
Your little pet projects? They are nothing.
I wouldn't have even bothered if Oh didn't-
Shut your mouth.
Then tell this "Oh,"
that my lousy resume isn't
good enough to join this club.
That I don't fit in here.
Look at you Mr. Tough Guy. This
is not an easy place to get into.
Up for Chinese tonight?
Sounds good!
Seungjin Corporation, 2017.
Leaked confidential documents.
[2017]
[SmartCop Security]
A ransomware attack on
the company's main server
resulted in major losses.
Confidential files were released
and with the backup data encrypted,
the damage was too deep.
The company went bankrupt soon after.
CEO Park Junhyeong's only
son was you, Park Jaemin.
No, Hex.
You're his son. A high schooler?
Yes.
Your dad, where is he?
Any chance you might know where he is?
No, I don't know where he is.
Don't take it out on the kid.
Where is your dad? Where is
this son of a bitch? Huh?
You're Jaemin, right? Park Jaemin.
Where is your dad? Is he at the factory?
The Ansan factory?
They found Park Junhyeong at the Han River.
The fire department
just confirmed the body.
This is horrible.
What shall we do?
- What are supposed to do?
- How are we supposed to live?
Are you okay?
Yeah. Of course, I am! It just
brought back old memories.
You said you were late for class. Go ahead.
Oh, my class. That's right.
Since I'm already late,
shall we have a drink?
Hey, Angry Joo. I'm really okay.
It's an F if you miss another class.
Do you want a suspension?
I have to go to work soon anyway.
I'm really fine. So, hurry to class.
I'll call you after class. Okay?
Who the hell do you think you are? My
past is none of your damn business!
Don't mess with me unless
you have a death wish.
Death wish?
The shit you are doing right now,
is the same thing those financial
hackers did to your dad's company.
Hackers aren't crackers, you asshole.
It's assholes like you that make
people treat hackers like criminals.
There are people that have lost their
entire lives because of crackers.
You're not the only one in the world.
You know that better than anyone.
Is it really okay? With
assholes like that around?
Will you dangerously sway on
the tightrope in the dark?
Or will you come out to the sun?
You decide.
It would be nice if you joined our side
but... it's ultimately your choice.
When you're not sure what to do, take
action. Take the road less traveled.
Trust your instinct to give.
And when you're not sure about that last
slice of pizza, be brave, and eat it.
That's how you're meant to live life.
Be stress-free. For a better life.
Live minimally. That's all I'm saying.
Everyone and their dog
wants to better everything.
Dog? I'm your boss, you punk. Want a bite?
You eat it.
So rude.
The answer you seek is yes, just do it.
I already told you. When you're
not sure what to do, take action.
You don't even know my dilemma.
I knew it right away. Do I
go on that blind date or not?
That's not it.
Really? That's the biggest
dilemma in my life.
I have a blind date. The girl...
Wait, she is older than me.
She had been married before.
How old are you again?
Twenty.
Twenty...
In that case, Just do it.
Do everything you can do.
Then, worry about it later.
For now, just do it.
You can afford to. Why?
Because you're twenty.
Damn, that was so cool! An
explosion of awesomeness!
Hello? Oh hey!
Hey, Sis. Whoops, I mean Hyeseon.
Yeah?
My house is minute? How is it minute?
Ah, you mean is the house mine?
No, I don't own the house. It's a half.
So it's kind of half mine? Half mine?
Not at all!
Hey, Joohee.
Huh? What's...
Huh? What?
Well, when I got home,
my dad was intensely reading something.
What was he reading so intensely?
You know that feeling you get when
there is something suspicious in the air.
Okay, so what was so suspicious about it?
You know I have a sixth
sense for this stuff.
[REVOLBEAT COIN - Investment Contact]
[Date: 2020.7.13, Location:
Romeo Seoul Da Vinci Ballroom]
Thank you for coming. Please
register at the front.
Please take a leaflet
and make your way inside.
Please find a seat inside.
Hello, welcome.
[RevolBeat Coin: Meetup & Networking Party]
Hey, Park Kyungshik!
You made it!
Yeah.
This way, I have a front-row
VIP seat just for you. Hurry up!
There are many people here.
They are all busy bees.
Sniffing out money like honey!
Sir, our VIP has arrived.
You should get to that. I'll take my
seat and enjoy the seminar. Thank you.
Nam Hyeongsu really made it big.
The crypto boom! It has to start now!
However, you shouldn't
just buy any old coin.
Companies disappear without
a trace in this industry.
That's why I'm here with you today to introduce
you to Revolbeat Coin! Revolbeat Coin!
I would like to say we are different
to all those garbage coins out there.
We promise to thwart any market
manipulators! No scammers!
This is really important and
that's why we have five stars
- Through our very own security system,
- No, scammers.
Any trade with even a hint of doubt...
it's a 180-degree change in life. Right?
I can't promise that. People
saying that are liars.
A comfortable life. That's our motto.
Our dear investors, you've
worked so hard thus far.
Now is the time to sit back
and enjoy your retirement,
go travel abroad, and play some golf.
That's the life you deserve.
[A Few Hours Ago]
Hey, you. The banner is crooked.
Yes, sir. Hey.
Let's pull it together, everyone!
Vice-President, sir. We're almost ready.
- Manager Lee.
- Yes, sir?
You know today is a big day, right?
Be on your toes, got it?
Yes, Sir!
That's the spirit.
- Are you in?
- Of course.
I downloaded everything without a hitch.
I installed malware on their
server and set up a backdoor.
Make sure we're untraceable,
make it an Indian proxy.
Why are you suddenly so polite?
I can't get a read on you.
India. Got it, jerk.
Okay. I read you now.
I'll let that one fly.
It's so cramped in here.
Come out. There is no one here.
How did you do it?
I don't know. They all just left.
Shall we have some fun now?
Showtime!
Stocks always flow in one direction.
They only predict increases.
Revolbeat Coin is different. You
can profit in both directions.
We predict gains whether it's up or down.
Another thing about stocks, markets close.
We have no other way to access our stocks.
But our Revolbeat Coin is open 24/7,
so no one is forced out of our services.
That is why there are no scammers.
This is really important and
that's why we have five stars!
- No, scammers.
- Through our very own security system,
even a hint of doubt...
He's really jotting this stuff down.
My dad is a history teacher.
Excellent penmanship.
- A crypto boom!
- Ah, that's right. He was a history teacher.
History and crypto are like oil and water.
You know it's the best time to
invest, right? You are truly in luck!
Here on the screen, it shows
our Revolbeat Coin can deliver
a 1360% return on your investment!
My apologies, everyone. I think
there's a problem with the screen.
What's going on?
[LIAR]
[Can I really invest in "Revolbeat Coin"? The
reality of the nationwide coin fraud group]
[I Want To Know]
Thank you.
Phew, fucking hell.
Hey, guess what the VP said to me?
Once this job is done, he told
me to lie low in Southeast Asia.
While he is jetting off to Hawaii.
The water is better in Thailand anyway.
The losers on their way here today
have no clue what's going on. They'll just
wag their tails and applaud at the end.
They will probably hand
over their entire pension.
Fucking idiots.
I heard the VP graduated from Harvard.
Is it true?
- He didn't graduate from Harvard.
- He didn't?
He's merely a thief stealing from the deaf,
dumb and blind. He's a real piece of shit!
That's why he's a parasite.
This is a misunderstanding, let me explain!
Just listen! Let me explain!
This is very important to our customers.
We should emphasize this part.
Everyone is talking about
how well Bitcoin is doing.
Let's talk about our margins.
Phew, fucking hell.
Listen. I can explain!
No! That's not it!
Where are you going? Stop right there!
What the fuck?
[Password Decryptor]
Looks like they rerouted to Mumbai.
They did a good job.
Seeing how they deleted their
log files to bypass the dragnet,
they're no amateurs.
Hex.
Cheers! Welcome to the group.
Not bad for your debut performance.
- Cheers!
Everyone, if Better World...
Everyone, come together!
My heroes!
What is she doing?
What's up with her?
Let me give you a big bow.
Move over. I want a big bow.
Hurry up!
I'm, I'm, I'm
really,
really
grateful!
Do I have to bow twice?
Two is for the deceased.
All this praise is so uncomfortable but
I love it.
This corporate culture...
no, this club culture
should exist all over South Korea.
- Three is for Buddha.
- Hyesoo,
- give me some praise.
- Gautama
- Siddhartha.
- I need praises.
Please give me some praise, Hyesoo.
Okay!
Today's MVP, Park Jaemin.
Give us a speech.
You still like being a lone wolf?
I'm still not totally sure
what I need to do.
As soon I find the guy I'm looking for...
Anyway, it was fun today.
You are so sweet and sour.
- He's usually like that.
- Hey, everyone!
We have to take a photo.
Photo time. Gather around.
One, two, three!
Just one sec.
Sorry, I have to make a call.
A phone call.
Hey!
You're going to miss out on her.
Huh? You two aren't dating?
What are you on about?
Don't try to deny it.
Don't wait until it's too late.
Ask her out while you still can.
Oh... Really?
Okay.
But it was super fun!
A bit like "Ocean's Eleven"?
It felt like I was in "The Thieves".
I almost cried out, "I'm in!"
Also, thanks for screwing over those guys.
You were a bit cooler than usual today.
Oh, hey! We're already here.
I'll be going in now.
- Hey, Joohee-
- Anyway, thanks for the help friend!
Hooray to 16 years of friendship!
I'll buy you a fridge when you marry!
Get me a washer for mine, front load!
Yeah, a front-loader. Not top load.
Hooray... 16 years of friendship.
♫ I think about you every moment ♫
♫ I was so happy, I liked it ♫
♫ Your pretty expression
when you look at me ♫
♫ Because it's so precious to me ♫
♫ I smile when I look at you ♫
♫ My heart that I didn't know yet ♫
Park Joohee, you are going crazy.
Snap out it! Snap out!
You're insane. Insane!
Alcohol is the enemy.
♫ The way I love you... 'Cuz
we're not just friends ♫
"An unlisted company posing
as a leading cryptocurrency
was arrested after attempting to
defraud investors. [OZ PC Reserve]
The scammers held investment seminars
nationwide and the group responsible
for their arrest came from an
unlikely source. The police found
that it was a hacker organization.
Seoul's Cyber Bureau is currently
investigating the identity of the group."
They did something even
the government couldn't do.
I guess they did.
Isn't it amazing?
If it wasn't for them, people
would have lost millions.
In a way, we need more vigilantes
than centralized power.
Yeah, in a way.
But isn't it a bit dangerous?
How long until you fall off the tightrope?
Within the rule of law, you ought to
live with your feet on the ground.
Will you dangerously sway on
the tightrope in the dark?
Or will you come out to the sun?
You decide.
- Those hackers.
- Sorry?
Yeah, those hackers.
Our primordial instinct
is to live on the ground.
It might be the only thing stopping
them from walking down a dangerous path.
What do you think?
How will we know?
The same people on our side today,
might be on the other side tomorrow.
The other... side?
You're freaking me out, why are so serious?
I'll be going now.
See you later.
At a building located on
Tehran-ro in Gangnam, Seoul,
- CEO of Alt Coin, Mr. Kim,
- Sons of bitches.
Held a seminar to attract investors.
Why? Did you give them all of your money?
No way.
The only thing I gave was 28
years of my life as a teacher
and my idiotic attempt at
running a fried chicken store,
wasting 80 million won on the
basement floor of a run-down mall.
Don't be so negative.
It's not easy raising a daughter
as a single dad for 10 years.
I told you to remarry
to the laundromat lady!
- Joohee.
- What?
Do you want to study abroad?
That's random, what are you on about?
When you were in eighth grade
you wanted to study in New York.
- At Pass?
- Parsons.
That's a fashion school anyway.
I ended up choosing art, remember?
Be a more attentive father.
For six years during
middle and high school.
You changed your career path 22
times, same with your crushes.
And I'm not an attentive father.
Your crush in 12th grade must
have been an art student.
That's enough.
And you wanted to follow him to New York.
Have you heard of Covid-19?
Korea is doing well. Studying
abroad is a bad idea.
Do you ever worry
that your dad won't be able to
buy you a nice wedding dress?
- Do you?
- I'm only twenty years old!
I told you to be quiet
when we do our masks.
Your dad is still alive!
Don't worry about money
and do what you want.
Have I ever asked you to sell
the house for a start-up?
Or asked to borrow what's
left of your pension?
Is it andropause?
I, Park Kyungshik, am in the
second chapter of my life.
Luck! Fortune!
That's a man finally breaking after
being stuck in traffic for hours.
You know there are many bars around here.
The convenience store isn't so bad.
I really wanted to do this with you.
- What is "this"?
- You know,
cracking open some beers on
a nice night with a friend.
When will we do this again?
We have military duty soon.
Once that's done, we are back on
campus with freshmen crawling around.
Do you think we'll be able to?
The romance of youth!
Romance?
You haven't changed at all, Jaemin.
The same as high school.
Even though we weren't
close in high school,
"I have to drink with this guy,"
is what I thought.
Why me?
Dude, you were so smart in high school.
The thing is...
people want to experience a unique,
tight bond with the best of the best.
That's rich coming from you. You didn't
even study after school and you did great.
Guess I did.
In fact, I thought you were so arrogant.
Whom are you calling arrogant? You
were worse. Following around teachers,
like a teacher's pet.
No way, they were following me.
To them, I was the kid that chose
liberal arts over a science high school.
Their attention was too much.
I knew how the other kids saw me.
I understand.
You are way more arrogant than I thought.
Do you have a girl you like?
A girl?
Why?
You have someone in mind?
Well, I could introduce you.
You want me to?
Actually, I already have someone I like.
You do?
Who?
She must be a catch if you are into her.
- Do I know her?
- It's Joohee.
Joohee? What's her surname?
Park Joohee.
Well, it is a common name.
Is there another Park Joohee we know?
Our friend Park Joohee?
You seriously like her?
The same Park Joohee that
we went to high school with?
The very same Joohee that
studies art at Hankuk University?
Yeah.
That's one hell of a reaction.
Can I go out with Joohee?
Why are you asking me for?
Because you and Joohee are best friends.
Best friends?
Are we?
She's not some object needing approval,
whether you two should date,
that decision,
is between you two.
I thought you were interested in her.
Guess not, huh?
That's a relief.
Yeah.
I'm...
Can I go out with Joohee?
Why are you asking me for?
Because you and Joohee are best friends.
[YOUKNOWWHAT uploaded a new post.
Next Target: Songdo International Exchange]
Songdo International Exchange.
Recognized by FINMA from Switzerland as
Asia's first cryptocurrency.
Saw a meteoric rise on the back
of the crypto sector's interest
with record trading volumes.
Azilowon.
(Korean cryptocurrency/token: AWN)
[A Few Days Ago]
Park Jaemin, how are you?
- You're looking after Joohee, right?
- Of course, sir.
This is a pleasant surprise,
how can I help you?
You know, this and that.
Thought I'd ask how you're doing.
The last time you called, you asked
me how I was doing for 20 minutes.
And we had 20 minutes of small talk.
Let's skip to the bottom line, for both us?
We can definitely skip that part where we
engage in small talk to build a rapport.
You're an honest man.
You said you were
- a computer science major?
- Yes.
It's a little weird calling
you out of the blue like this,
but you really know your stuff
when it comes to things like this.
Do you happen to know
- anything about blockchain?
- Ah, you want to talk about crypto.
- Wow, exactly!
- I do know a thing or two about that.
What about cryptocurrencies are you...
Azilowon?
What? How much?
3,000?
Damn it, Mr. Park!
Just, why?
Don't you get it?
We are totally known now.
We're finally on the radar of
those attention-seeking hackers.
- We're not saying you're wrong.
- Then why stop?
After all this way.
- What did you recruit me for?
- We're a team.
A group. You're the only one mad about it.
We're not talking about
closing down Better World.
There isn't a shadow of
a doubt about your skills
For our last job,
you definitely pulled
more than half the weight.
But, Jaemin, why do we hack?
Look at all of our achievements,
aren't they amazing?
With our inconceivably
superior hacking skills,
we'll solve any cybersecurity problems,
including those the government can't.
We are Better World!
Do you want to go and
tell everyone in town?
- Is that why we exist?
- We have to be more famous and be known!
That's how we get them to the surface.
If we want to strike,
- we have to be more famous than them.
- Is one of those people,
YOUKNOWWHAT?
Let's all calm down, okay?
Jaemin, we promised to
help you avenge your dad.
So, let's take a short break and recharge.
This kind of exposure is not
ideal for us in the long run.
All right, fine.
Let's assume we managed to draw
out YOUKNOWWHAT to the surface.
They laid low for one year
after your dad's company.
It was a year and a half
after Taegun Finance.
That asshole ran circles around all those
security experts, evading their efforts.
Yeah, he's really going to fall
right into our unprepared hands.
No, no.
Let's say he did.
We got lucky and got into his backdoor,
and tore up all of his
timestamps and checksum values.
There is no way the three of us
are getting out of there alive but
let's say we did!
Anyway, despite all these hurdles,
your revenge plan succeeds.
You think we are going to
"live happily ever after?"
Our real names will be
all over the internet.
And the Cyber Bureau isn't going to
sit idly like they are doing now.
I chased him for three years
but I couldn't find anything about him.
That fucker has finally started moving
after being dormant for three years.
I was crying and begging for
them to catch that fucker
and they just stood there with
their hands in their pockets.
They are worse than that fucker and I
have to be scared of what they'll do?
We're saying we need a better plan.
Disrespectful punk.
It's not a gym!
Grow your muscles somewhere else!
Dumbass.
- Are you with Jaemin?
- What? No.
- What's up?
- Call me if you two get in touch.
Why? Is there a problem?
- It's not my problem if he goes crazy
- Would you shut up?
Hyesoo? Hyesoo?
Are you okay?
Jaemin is not answering...
What? Why him all of a sudden?
He's not a kid and he'll call you
once he knows you are looking for him.
Don't worry too much.
I guess you are right...
You are right. He's not a kid.
I'm a little disappointed that you
mentioned Jaemin as soon as met.
No, I'm really sorry.
I just had a strange call.
I knew this would happen.
He's going to explode.
Explode?
- Is Jaemin angry?
- No, I must sound crazy.
- What do you want to drink?
- No, it's on me. I'm Sorry.
We've known each other for a long time.
That's true. A long time.
You, me, and Jaemin...
Ever since 9th grade.
So it's been four years already.
- Time flies.
- Yes.
It's been already 4 years.
Time really flies.
We were all in the same class in 9th grade.
We went our separate ways after that.
Yeah, right. We were in the same class.
- You and Jaemin were really close.
- Yes, right.
We were best friends...
No! Me and him?
No way, we weren't that close.
We weren't that close, we even
lived far apart. Barely friends.
Really?
[Found Jaemin! He's in Songdo.]
I thought you two were best friends.
I'm really sorry, Chanho.
Let's do this another time.
Jaemin is going to be in trouble.
What's going on? Jaemin is
going to explode and all that?
I'm really sorry. I'm so worried.
I'm sorry.
Where is a cab?
I need to hurry...
♪ The door is opening! ♪
♪ Love at first sight ♪
- Are you crazy?
- I didn't recognize you.
What's with the suit?
Were you at a funeral?
He went to his ex-girlfriend's wedding.
- We ruined your date, huh?
- Yes.
Threw away a once in a
lifetime opportunity.
Total fail.
I guess I'm destined to
have crushes forever.
You're slower than I thought.
What?
Play the C51 camera.
He passed through the
Geumcheon toll gate at 3:45.
Seeing as he's headed to Dangjin...
It's Songdo.
That's too easy.
So, I'm just curious.
How do you change your voice?
I don't see a mic around your mouth.
I'm just asking because it looks cool.
Too personal, maybe?
Let's respect each other's privacy, right?
All right then.
Let's keep it professional.
[Withdrawal completed: 30,000 AWN]
[Withdrawal completed: 250,000 AWN]
[Withdrawal completed: 280,000 AWN]
[Withdrawal completed: 120,000 AWN]
[Withdrawal completed: 2,000,000 AWN]
[Loading...]
While an internal investigation team is
identifying the scope of the
attack and retracing the source.
Meanwhile, dozens of large electronic
displays in Seoul and the capital area
are simultaneously playing a video
file allegedly planted by hackers.
According to an official,
the alleged hackers wanted
to demonstrate their skills
by performing a defacement attack.
Further away in Yongsan...
[LOADING...]
Hello, everyone! We are Crackers!
Not the eating kind!
Do you remember the crypto craze
that blew up in Korea recently?
New Year's cash, part-time work, tuition!
Everything in crypto!
Did you go all-in with
your precious savings?
The money kept piling on!
While you went through hell!
Keep working like dogs. We'll
keep spending it like water.
[You Know What?]
[What can you do?]
[Rainbow Glide Moonshine]
[17 Hours Ago]
First, go and see where the CCTVs are.
I'll ask Senior Oh about hash functions.
Senior Oh? Is he getting involved?
Senior Oh was the one
who told us he was here.
Why does he care about him so much?
He's one of the greatest hackers,
He can go head-to-toe
with the Honker Union,
Damn, your slaps sting. It hurts!
You made me so worried.
I had a good reason, okay?
You don't know anything!
How dare you raise your voice at me!
Did you see the post on the site?
YOUKNOWWHAT reveals his next
target to other hackers in advance.
He's not short on confidence.
Those bitches.
We can't say no after such a
considerate declaration of war.
I'm going to hack the
exchange before YOUKNOWWHAT.
The security guards start
their patrol at 11:00 p.m.
I'll enter the server
room after 40 minutes.
The parent company is called Smart Cop,
they're an IT security firm so
it's hard to hack them remotely.
We have to directly go to the server room,
and plant malware in the main server.
You are going inside the building?
Well, I have the day off tomorrow.
Come on now.
I'm tired, too!
I want to do nothing
but rest on my day off.
It's nothing.
Wait, I'll call you back.
What is this?
These damn kids.
Leaving things behind.
Listen here, young man.
I wonder why you were
hiding out in the dark
- doing something you shouldn't be?
- Do something.
My goodness, the light went out...
[10]
[4F Down - 5F Up] - [7F] - [2/1]
[Staircase Entrance]
Calling all guards.
We have a man wearing a mask
with a backpack and a black hat.
He's making his way to the parking lot.
Overtime sucks, right?
Ever heard of server
management with flexible hours?
A dream job that guarantees
a work-life balance.
Probably only at Google.
Just wait! This is a misunderstanding.
Backpack. Black clothes.
Even I think I look like a corporate spy.
We have a man wearing a mask
with a backpack and a black hat.
And he's making a run towards the
back entrance of the parking lot.
Wait! This is a misunderstanding.
Sounds like Jaemin is having
his spinal cords readjusted.
What? Oh no. I'm going in.
I can't move...
You bitch...
What should we do?
It'll be fine. Manguk
is a good punching bag.
- He can take all the hits.
- No,
I'm not talking about Jaemin.
What?
Come on.
Do you know what his
nickname was in high school?
The wiper.
The wiper?
- He wiped his nose a lot?
- It's because he can wipe out anyone.
Oh yeah. He said he was on varsity.
Bring it.
Bring it!
That felt good.
You know those kids
that are super athletic and super smart.
That's right. Just the
type you can't stand.
All he did was fight and try MMA
moves during middle and high school.
Until he wised up and started studying
really hard, then boom! Great SAT scores.
Of course, he did.
He's the typical comeback kid?
It's such a cliche.
[B4 > Entrance]
[Career counseling report]
Listen.
It's great that you're
finally studying hard,
but why suddenly choose computer science?
You were on the podium at the nationals.
Athletics...
won't help me catch those
assholes that got my dad.
[ETH Wallet: 28,000,000,000;
AWN: 420,000,000,000]
Hey!
Stay focused!
- Why do you look worse than he does?
- He's an animal.
Did they get you in the head?
Hey, snap out of it!
And why are you drooling?
Did you kill them?
- Did you bury them?
- What is this, a crime movie?
You should stop watching Netflix.
So, what's next?
We have to let YOUKNOWWHAT and other
people know we attacked the exchange.
As you are our leader, could
you write up our statement?
Wait.
Wasn't I the leader?
Were you flower watching
in the middle of summer?
- Looks like you were on a date.
- Who cares.
I'm in a good mood so don't ruin it.
I haven't been to the beach in a
long time so I was just taking it in.
The alcohol is making me feel cold.
I should go inside.
What's this?
I've never seen you
show any manners at all.
Not at all, I'm full of manners.
I have so much that it's spilling out.
Whatever.
Wait.
Why don't we stay a little longer?
Why?
There's a historical moment
happening inside right now.
You mean, those two?
That's why you're outside?
Of course, I can take a hint.
Oh my god!
It's cold.
It's because I'm cold.
It's my jacket anyway.
Don't misunderstand.
I'll have my hands clenched.
Okay.
Hey.
What?
It's the middle of summer.
We're in "Major Heat," it's the hottest
time of the year in the solar term.
Okay, that was a good one.
The number you have dialed
is currently busy right now.
Please call again another time.
The number you have dialed...
The number you have...
He's not answering. What should we do?
We only have 20 minutes left
before the announcement.
What is it?
What's going on?
[Back To Present]
Do you really want to know who I am?
Then bring the USB.
I'll give you the answer
you're looking for.
[Angry Joo]
You are one impressive kid.
Coming alone like this.
I know that's your character, but
don't you think you're too confident?
No, wait.
This isn't confidence.
Is it you?
You're YOUKNOWWHAT?
So, 28 billion AWN is inside this thing?
Everything is so convenient these days.
Hey, Jaemin.
Let's see those famous moves of yours.
Give it a try.
The best fighter in high school.
You can do better.
Jaemin.
Jaemin!
What should I do with you.
All right.
I admit you're good.
Compliment accepted.
I know I'm good.
Hey, Jaemin.
Look at you.
Still trying to be so cool.
Stop trying so hard!
You're making it worse.
I predicted you'd be reckless
because it was for Joohee.
But don't you think this
was too much of a risk?
Is it because you like Joohee
or is it because of your dad?
Hey, Chanho.
It was really you?
You killed my dad?
Yeah.
Right.
I also told Joohee's dad about Azilowon.
I knew that already.
You bastard.
Stop acting like you know everything.
It's disgusting.
Did you also imagine this?
Being betrayed by a
friend from high school?
Hey, Chanho.
I didn't realize...
you wanted to be my friend that badly.
You should have just told me.
You asshole!
You think you are all that?
You think you're so fucking great?
You confused meatheaded jock.
You're parading around town
thinking that you are a real hacker?
[1st: Lee Chanho, 2nd: Park Jaemin]
Being second place is a skill, too.
You play futsal with us until 11:00 p.m.
and you still get good scores.
- You should buy us snacks to celebrate!
- You're like a cheat code.
Let's go.
He has a sad face for being
the smartest kid at school.
Jaemin is the best fighter here,
imagine if he got better test
scores, Chanho would kill himself.
I think Jaemin is going easy on Chanho.
Chanho is studying day and
night trying to stay at the top.
Jaemin eats, sleeps, and does whatever
he wants, and he's still second place.
There's not a big difference
between their average scores either.
Poor Chanho.
I should have just done nothing.
Then it would have been less painful.
Everything was easy for you.
Beg.
It wasn't for me.
Beg for your life.
All you have to do is beg, just once.
If you beg me,
I might let you go.
You disgust me.
You lost.
You lost, asshole!
Think again.
Think what again?
You really think I lost?
You're delusional.
Chanho, you bastard!
Do you think I ransacked
the administrator's account?
Do you really think I
spear-phished Azilowon?
Stop your bullshit.
I did hack the administrator's page.
I sent a bunch of emails
with their member's data.
Hot wallets, it lets you
withdraw tokens directly online.
Well, I sent one each to all of
Azilowon's 1.2 million members.
I just planted a Trojan
horse in your mobile.
- You lose.
- You son of a bitch!
YOUKNOWWHAT called me.
He said he'll give me the answer I'm
looking for if I bring this to him.
Really?
- Then take it.
- What?
He's got your answer.
Plus, I'm really curious about who he is.
- What's this?
- A fake USB.
It has a tracking device.
But it needs electricity to work.
So it needs to be plugged in like this,
- for us to identify the location.
- Can this
record too?
Of course.
Of course, it records
everything in real-time
and will be broadcast across the
nation, just like in the movies.
Psych.
If you want to mount a
camera, we would need MI6...
I have another plan.
Do you know what YOUKNOWWHAT is?
What is it?
It's...
no one.
With Chanho's profound parting words,
an unusual summer for a
twenty-year-old came and went.
The Seoul Cyber Bureau was at
Songdo International Exchange...
The hack of the century, which could
have erased millions of cryptocurrencies,
did attract the public's
attentions for a while
but the news died down and was remembered
as the act of an attention-craving hacker.
YOUKNOWWHAT, the man I
hunted for three years,
was forgotten by the
public in just three days.
[NOTICE: As of August 10, 2020, "Better World" club
will be converted into a "Fine Dust" research room.]
"Better World"?
Is it a name of a club?
Never heard of it.
It's a weird name. "Better World," huh?
Maybe it's a volunteering group?
So, if we're out,
who's replacing us?
What's so great about them?
They're sponsored by Samsung,
collaborating with MIT students on
atmospheric engineering research.
Kids that can save the
world from fine dust?
I heard KBS is going to interview them too.
Massachusetts...
Then, what about us?
- Where can we do our club activities?
- You guys...
should meet in the virtual world.
Your club failed to meet the
member's requirements anyways.
You're making me look like a
bad landlord expelling tenants.
I have no power.
I have no power to help you.
Do you want me to make an
appointment with the president?
My honorable TA,
you can't do this to us!
It's not like I'm a pearl lacquerware
master trying to pass down the torch
or noodle pulling master from China.
I have no plans to accept any disciples.
I just want to be the owner of an
internet cafe for the rest of my life.
I heard you were a reverse engineer,
one of the top three engineers at the
Ministry of Science and Technology.
If you accept me as a
disciple, I will do my best.
Who would have thought?
That the boss at my part-time
job was a genius hacker?
That he's one of the very few
Wizard Experts in the world.
This is not Hogwarts, okay?
Wizards? Are you a wizard?
Gryffindor or Slytherin?
Why do people always say,
"Gryffindor or Slytherin?"
Ravenclaw, known for their
cleverness and creativity,
and the protectors of morals
and character, Hufflepuff.
But I am... a Gryffindor.
- Such a nerd.
- Could you not bring her here anymore?
Hey, she didn't even pay for that.
He will pay for it.
That will be deducted from your wages.
Stop eating the expensive
snacks, take the bagged ones.
- May you travel safely, my master.
- Get lost!
All my favorites are in this!
Nothing but the best.
I'm a better cook than your number 28.
28?
I totally forgot about him.
It's okay, I'll just
have to find number 29.
Right.
Eat.
Wait.
My dumb dad.
Thanks for saving him twice.
It's not a big deal.
Your dad was kind to
me in high school, too.
Just tell him to stop going to
those weird investment seminars.
You make sure he doesn't, okay?
So pretty.
- Do you want water?
- Yes.
Finally finished eating.
You're looking good, Joohee.
[Better World invites you]
[If you accept, please
come to Bugak Hall B2-4.]
[The location link below]
[The password is]
[Romantic Hacker]
Channel Manager: maga_coco
Chief Editor: kakashiandme.
Chief Segmenter: miss_rochester.
Segmenters: plc_958 & porkypine90_261.
Thanks to all our moderators
and subtitle teams.
[Twenty Hacker: Black&White]
Wait!
[I have to take a dump!]
[Hyesoo: You're so gross.]
[It'll be 15 minutes.]
[Hyesoo: Everyone is are here.
You better hurry.]
Right. I'm on my way.
That's what happened.
What are you going to do?
You shouldn't try to save
the bait when you're fishing.
Everything has a role to play.
Lee Chanho...
has been expelled.
What do you think YOUKNOWWHAT is?
It's...
no one.
It's no one but...
it is everywhere.
[Twenty Hacker: Black&White]
Timing and Subtitles brought to you
by 🎇The Blessed Team🎇 @ Viki.com
♫ I think about you every moment ♫
♫ I was so happy, I liked it ♫
♫ Your pretty expression
when you look at me ♫
♫ Because it's so precious to me ♫
♫ I smile when I look at you ♫
♫ My heart that I didn't know yet ♫
♫ With little conviction,
I feel the change ♫
♫ I'm not going to hide it anymore ♫
♫ The way I love you... 'Cuz
we're not just friends to me ♫
♫ I'm afraid I can't stand it any longer ♫
♫ 'Cuz we are not just friends to me ♫
♫ It's a little more to me ♫
♫ I'm coming, hold my hand ♫
♫ Take, take my hand ♫
♫ 'Cuz it took a long time, oh baby ♫
Thanks for watching!