This could be the room
of any small boy,
but it just happens to belong to
a boy named Christopher Robin.
Now, Christopher Robin had
many toy animals to play with,
but his very best
friend was a bear,
named Winnie the Pooh.
Together, Pooh and his friends
shared many grand adventures.
But one of their most unusual
began on an early
autumn morning.
lt was that time of year again.
That magical time
when leaves fall,
and pumpkins grin,
and Spookables roam free.
Halloween had come to
the Hundred Acre Wood.
-Boo!
-Oh, my!
A very, very small Spookable.
Whatever shall I do?
Don't be afraid, Mama.
It's only me!
-See?
-Oh, Roo.
Thank goodness. I'm saved.
Sorry I scared you so bad.
I was just getting
ready for Halloween.
Aren't you starting a
little early, dear?
I can't help it. I'm excited. It's
Lumpy's first time trick-or-treating.
Well, that is exciting.
We're going to
Piglet's to practice.
-Bye-bye, Mama!
-Bye, dear.
Have a good time.
-Treat-or-Trick!
-Lumpy!
How was that, then? Did I
do it right this time?
-Did I?
-Almost. But not quite.
It's "trick-or-treat"!
Trick-or-treat!
Got it.
-Roo?
-Yeah?
-I don't get it.
-It's simple.
We knock on any door, and
say "trick-or-treat".
And they give us candy
and cider and cookies.
What? Just like that?
Don't worry, Lumpy, you'll
get the hang of it.
I'll help you.
This is gonna be the best
Halloween ever because it's...
...our first
Halloween together.
Come on, let's go practice
at Piglet's house.
This is gonna be the most fun
you've ever had in your life.
Trick-or-treat.
Boo!
Would you look at that.
We frightened them so much
, they forgot to scream.
Oh, bother.
I don't think we
frightened them, Piglet.
Oh, dear. Didn't we
scare you at all, Roo?
Maybe a little bit.
Right, Lumpy?
Oh, sure.
Scary.
Why are you wearing
those funny faces?
What? Why, these are
Halloween masks, Lumpy-boy.
I guess the kid's not
from around here.
-This is his first Halloween.
-No kidding?
Don't Heffalumps have Heffaween.
.. I mean, Halloween?
Well, we have
Trumplet-Trumpet Day.
Flapadoodle Eve.
-But that's it.
-Well, then,
we must make this a very
special night, indeed.
Well, what're we waiting for?
Somebody get this
Heffalump some candy.
No! No candy for anyone.
Not until the proper time
to go trick-or-treating.
Now, if you'll follow me
inside, I have all the fun
meticulously planned out.
Now, gather round, everyone.
As you see, I've collected all the candy
to be found in the Hundred Acre Wood,
and divided it into equal
, easy-to-carry sacks.
Tonight, each of you
will take your sack home
and dispense it for
trick-or-treating.
Pooh Bear, you'll be
trick-or-treating with Piglet.
Roo, you'll be with Lumpy.
And I'll be with Tigger.
-What about me?
-You, Eeyore?
Forgot about me, didn't you?
lt figures.
The point is to get organized.
If we follow the plan, we can
make this the best Halloween ever.
Oh, boy!
Trick-or-treating begins promptly
at the stroke of sunset.
But I don't think my tummy
can wait that long, Rabbit.
lt wants a treat now.
Well, your tummy will
just have to wait, Pooh.
We need to save all the
candy for tonight.
See, Lumpy? This is gonna be a
great night of trick-or-treating.
I think I'm gonna like this Heffaween.
.. Hallow...
The word is "Halloween".
And it's time we
showed our new friend
what my favourite night
of the year is all about.
Now, a Halloween-y night is good
When we're trick or
treatin' through the woods
I'll be sneakin' up and peekin'
While my tippety toes are creakin'
Boogity Boo-in' like a
Super Tigger should
Well, a sweet treat
is just my cup of tea
And a tricky-trick is
just the treat for me
Oh, everybody pay attention
'Cause I really hate to mention
That the ghoulie ghosts
are howling up a tree
We are daring to be scaring
Who's behind that
mask you're wearing
We can "Boo!" a spooky greetin'
Then we'll share the
sweets we're eating
When we're home from
trick-or-treating With our friends
Oh, the Spookables crawl
out from where they hide
Do you think they might
be hiding here inside?
-Well, together we're more clever
-We go places they would never!
And a boo-hoo-hoo will
send 'em for a ride
We are daring to be scaring
Who's behind that
mask you're wearing?
We can "Boo!" a spooky greeting
Then we'll share the
sweets we're eating
When we're home from
trick-or-treating With our friends
We are daring to be scaring
Who's behind that
mask you're wearing?
We can "Boo!" a spooky greeting Then
we'll share the sweets we're eating
When we're home from
trick-or-treating
With our friends
Bravo, Tigger.
You've succeeded in
terrifying poor Lumpy.
Lumpy, please come out.
Halloween isn't that scary.
-Right, Tigger?
-You said it, Roo, old pal.
Not scary is just what it is.
As long as we don't run into
the Gobloon, of course.
No! Not the Gobloon!
-What's a Gobloon?
-Well, I'm glad you asked.
I didn't wanna leave
you in the dark.
The Gobloon is the
scardiest fraidifier
that ever scarified
on Halloween night.
And he lives in the eeriest
part of the Hundred Acre Woods.
His lair lies beyond
the Creepy Cave...
-Dear.
-...down the Slimy Slide,
and in the Tree of Terror!
There, there, Lumpy.
Don't listen to that lunatic.
There's no such thing
as a Gobloon.
You are so wrong, Long-Ears!
-Tigger...
-Rabbit...
-Lunatic.
-Long ears.
Wrong you are, Long-Ears.
Every Halloween,
he roams the woods
for poor victims to turn
into jaggedy lanterns.
Jaggedy lanterns!
Lumpy!
I'm sure the Gobloon
isn't all bad.
Right, Tigger?
As a point of factin', Roo-boy,
there is one good thing
about the Gobloon.
If you catch him, you
get to make a wish.
Did you hear that, Lumpy?
What kind of wish?
Well, only the wish-iest wish
that you could ever
wish about wishing for.
Meaning, anything at all.
-Wow!
-Oh, fiddlesticks and nonsense.
There's no such thing as a Gobloon
and that's all there is to it!
Lumpy? Please come out.
-Please?
-No, thanks.
Don't want to get turned
into a jaggedy lantern.
Lumpy won't come out.
What do we do?
This is going to require thought,
planning, concentration.
Quick, everyone. "Operation
: Extract the Heffalump."
Everyone grab hold. Heave ho!
We have to get organized.
All together now.
Put some muscle into it.
But I don't wanna come out!
Come on, pull!
Watch my tail, Piglet.
Easy on the stripes back there.
Somehow I don't believe
they thought this through.
Come on, little Lumpster,
don't be scarified.
The front of me's
not coming out.
And the back of me's
And neither is my middle.
Who turned out the lights?
-It's a Spookable! Help!
-Spookables! Run!
-Help!
-Oh, my!
Ah, well, that's more like it.
I guess I taught him
a lesson or two.
Please come out, Lumpy.
I thought we were gonna
spend Halloween together?
You can come under
here if you want.
You guys go ahead.
I'll stay here with Lumpy.
It's OK, Lumpy.
I was just really looking forward
to trick-or-treating together.
Lumpy! You're not
hiding anymore.
-Aren't you afraid?
-Oh, I still am.
But as long as we're together,
I can be brave.
-Hooray for Lumpy!
-Good for you!
That's what I'm talking about!
Well, this calls
for a celebration.
Piglet, fetch some candy.
Yes, sir. Rabbit, sir.
Yes, I know.
You're all surprised.
"No candy until
tonight," I said.
But special occasions
call for sweets.
So, Piglet, one piece
of candy each.
-Rabbit?
-Yes, Piglet. The candy, if you please.
Oh, dear. That's just it.
Well, what is it, Piglet?
Spit it out!
Well, there's no candy
left, Rabbit, sir.
What do you mean,
"no candy left"?
There's sacks and sacks
of it over there.
Pooh Bear? You ate
all our candy?
Mighty impressive for
one bear, though.
I don't know how it happened.
I only wanted one, but...
...my tummy kept
asking for more.
There's gotta be some
left here somewhere.
We can't have Halloween
without candy.
Well, I'll betcha Rabbit has
a few sweets tucked away.
Don't ya, Long-Ears?
I'm afraid not, Tigger.
You see, I've collected
every bit of candy
from the Hundred Acre Wood.
I'm afraid...
...there will be no trick-or-treating
this year. Oh, dear.
Oh, bother.
My tummy says it's sorry.
I wish there was some way
we can get more candy.
"Wish"? Maybe there is a way.
Remember Tigger's story?
If we catch the Gobloon,
we could wish for enough
candy for everyone.
Yeah! We can save Halloween.
But if the Gobloon caught us,
we'd be jaggedy lanterns.
Don't worry. I'll
be right there.
I won't let him hurt you.
OK, Lumpy,
let's just go find some
costumes for tonight.
Yes, Roo, let us do so.
That's the spirit.
We can still have
fun without candy.
And don't forget, be back
promptly at the stroke of sunset.
We will!
Now, what did Tigger say again?
Oh, yeah.
First we gotta find
the Creepy Cave,
then the Slimy Slide and then.
..
-The Tree of Terror.
-Oh, right. The Tree of Terror.
Thanks, Lumpy. Come on!
We're gonna make this the
best Halloween ever.
Take that! And that! And that!
I proclaim Lumpy and Roo
to be the floundering
members of the...
Bravest of the brave?
The Bravest of the Brave
Gobloon Catchers' Club.
Brave together! Brave forever!
Conquerors of the Gobloon!
Now shake.
No, no! Shake hands.
That means we stick
together, no matter what.
What are we waiting for?
Let's go!
We're friends forever
We'll be brave together
We can weather
whatever comes along
One can do it Two is better
You and me together forever
Braver than brave
Stronger than strong
Brave together Singing our song
-We're friends forever
-One can do it, two is better
-We'll be brave together
-You and me together forever
Braver than brave
Stronger than strong
Brave together Singing our song
Rumple de doodle Rumple dee dee
We'll rumble and tumble
like bumbly bees
Two together Together we're one
Rumple de doodle
De doodle de dum
-You're my buddy
-You're mine too
-If I get scared
-I'm right behind you
lt would be super if we could be
the bravest friends in history
We're friends forever
We'll be brave together
We can weather
whatever comes along
We can weather whatever
Comes
Along
No prizes for guessing
where the Gobloon lives?
Oh, don't worry.
Gobloon catchers, ho!
Lumpy?
Come on!
All right.
Know what I'm gonna wish for
when we catch that Gobloon?
Assuming the Gobloon
doesn't catch us first?
I'm gonna wish for
a million cookies,
and then a million candies,
then three more wishes.
-How 'bout you?
-Gosh.
I've already got my best friend
and a lunch box full
of rumpledoodles.
What else do I need?
What was that?
lt sounded like it
came from over there.
Look!
That's gotta be the Creepy Cave,
just like Tigger said.
The Slimy Slide
can't be far off.
Come on, Lumpy.
Whoa!
Let's go!
It's OK, Lumpy. It's only an echo.
Listen.
Gobloon!
Roo, please don't
do that again.
I'm sorry.
Roo! Something's following us.
-I don't see anything.
-I heard it.
I don't hear anything, either.
My ears are bigger than yours.
Lumpy, it's all in
your imagination.
It's right behind me, Roo.
lt kicked me in the bottom.
Lumpy! Stop!
It's only your lunch box. See?
I don't care. This is too scary.
I don't want to go on.
But we can't stop now.
I'm sorry, Roo.
I'm not taking another
step and that is final!
We're almost through the cave.
All we have to...
... find is the Slimy Slide!
Lumpy? Are you OK?
I think so.
OK, we got through the
cave and down the slide.
But where's that Tree of Terror?
Wonder which way we should go?
Smell anything?
Nope.
See anything?
-Nope.
-Maybe he's not home.
Well, only one way to find out.
What are you going to do?
Don't worry. I have a plan.
Lumpy!
You know what? He must
be out Goblooning.
He could be back any minute.
He could turn us into
jaggedy lanterns.
I don't think I
can do this, Roo.
I want to go home.
If we leave, we won't catch the
Gobloon and we won't get our wishes
and we won't have candy and
I won't get to show you
how great Halloween is.
I'm sorry.
I'm just so scared.
Gosh, I wish Piglet was here.
-Piglet?
-Yeah.
He was so afraid of Halloween once,
it almost was a Hallow-wasn't.
-But then he got un-scared.
-Really?
Say, maybe if I told
you the story, Lumpy,
you might be un-scared too.
All right.
lt happened before Mom and I
moved to the Hundred Acre Wood.
lt was Halloween,
and everyone was really excited
to go trick-or-treating.
They all had funny costumes
and Pooh Bear's was the
bestest of them all.
Look, there he is now.
Hi, Pooh Bear. What
are you up to?
Practicing.
For Halloween.
Which happens to happen soon.
So I must be prepared.
Though I'm not
fond of tricking,
I do enjoy treating,
because treating means...
...eating.
Bother. I've smackled every
smackeral of hon...
Happy Halloweenin'
to ya, Pooh-boy!
Not late, am I? Didn't
miss any anythin', did I?
Halloween's what
Tiggers like the best.
Trick or treat!
Hello, Pooh. Hello, Tigger.
Nice costume.
You make a good yak.
I'm not supposed to be some
yakkety-yakketin'-yak!
Now I gotta get a new outfit!
'Cause I'm gonna win
that Best Costume Prize.
You wait and see!
But, Gopher, I don't think
there is such a prize.
Fine with me!
Cuts down on the competition.
Night'll be fallin'
any minute now,
and I still haven't pulled
any warm-up tricks!
But, Tigger, we can't go yet.
What do you mean?
Halloween night
won't last all day,
and we gotta be ready for it!
But our very dear friend
Piglet is not here.
And I would have thought he
should have been by now.
I hope he is all right.
Yes, Piglet, you're gonna
be quite all right.
Because this year is
going to be the year.
This Halloween, you're
going to enjoy yourself.
Nothing is going
to frighten you.
There! If I'm not scared
of something as frightful as this,
I'll be unafraid of anything!
I hope.
Ghoulish goblin Ghastly ghost
Everything scares me the most
All I really want to do
ls be with Pooh,
Eeyore and Tigger
Kind of creepy, sort of scary
Yes, but maybe not so very
Well, in order to be brave
I tell myself that
I am not afraid
No, not too much
And if I am not afraid
Not more than a touch
I can be around my friends
And being with them
is much better
We might be more brave together
Then I can say that
I am not af...
What if some spook
comes up to me
When it's dark and really gloomy
How very grand to stand up tall
But could I even stand at all?
I don't have one scary feature
A timid, small and
frightened creature
Dear, oh dear, I'm
just not brave
I want to tell them
I am not afraid
No, not too much
And if I am not afraid
Not more than a touch
I can be around my friends
And being with them
is much better
We might be more brave together
It's Halloween I'll face my fear
'Cause it's the spookiest
night of the year
What a very grand
thing to be so brave
To show myself that
I am not afraid
Trick or treat. Or not.
Why, Piglet, where
is your costume?
Oh. I...
Actually I haven't entirely
decided, exactly,
just what I want
to be, precisely.
Gasp! Look at the time.
Half-past a quarter of sunset.
And I still haven't done any
warmin'-uppin'! Come on!
I gotta try some
trick-or-trickin' on old Rabbit.
There is a trick to
pullin' tricks, you know.
Storm brewin'.
Oh, dear.
Piglet.
If you were I and I were you,
would you think my costume will
get me plenty of treats tonight?
Namely, honey.
I should give it a
trying-out to be sure.
Oh, Pooh, I really don't know.
Say, where y'all buzzing
off to, buddy boys?
I shall know I'm all
the bee that I can be,
if the bees see me
and see a bee instead of me.
See?
Oh, Pooh Bear!
Perhaps it would
be best, Piglet,
if you didn't call me by name.
lt might make the bees curious.
I'm sorry, Pooh Who Isn't.
A trick? Or treat?
Oh, bother.
Each precious pumpkin a
picture of perfection!
No, no, no!
Not this way. That
way, to your left.
No, your other left!
Oh, my!
My poor pumpkins.
Are you all right, Pauline?
Oh, speak to me, Pietro.
Oh, don't you know me, Petunia?
Trick or treat!
Not now, Gopher.
And why are you dressed
like a muskrat?
Muskrat?
That guy wouldn't know a rabbit
from a hole in the ground!
Look at all the
pretty pumplekins!
Jackie-lanterns just
waitin' to happen!
Oh, dear!
Tigger, stop that!
I have no time for this
Halloween nonsense.
I have work to do. I have
pumpkins to protect!
How's this one?
Of all my favourite holidays,
Halloween isn't.
A stormin'-good storm.
This is gonna be the
bestest Halloween ever!
With loads of lightnin'!
And thunderous thunderin'!
And windiferous winds
breaking everywhere!
Oh, dear.
Why, we're gonna be creepin'
and crawlin' with Spookables!
Oh, dear.
You don't suppose there
will be any Spookables
of the honey-hungry sort?
-Do you?
-At least half a dump of Spookables.
And bug-eyed Woozles and
saw-toothed Jagulars!
Oh, dear! Deary dear dear!
Piglet.
And then Piglet
ran for his life.
Hey, Lumpy, is the story
making you feel any better?
-I'll take that as a "no".
-What happened next, Roo?
Did the Spookables get Piglet?
Well, let's see.
Piglet was all alone,
lost in the woods,
on the ookiest-spookiest
night of the year,
which really wasn't
the best place to be.
There. Now you're
safe and sound.
Who is it?
It's me, them, and
, of course, us.
Oh. But wait.
Perhaps if you'd say something
only you would say,
I'd know you're you.
A very good idea, Piglet.
But what should I say?
Well, possibly..
. "I am Pooh"?
You are? Well, then who am I?
It's Pooh.
Are you quite all right, Piglet?
Yes.
You will be joining us for
Halloween, won't you?
Well, to be perfectly honest.
..
What I mean to say is...
To put it another way...
The truth of the matter is...
As a small and timid animal,
I'm afraid I'm
really too afraid.
Oh, but Piglet,
Halloween without you
would be like...
Like last year, and the
year before last year.
And the year before that year.
And all the years leadin'
up to and includin'
every last Halloween ever.
I'm very, very sorry indeed.
Oh, that's quite
all right, Piglet.
We shall simply not
have Halloween.
Oh, you mustn't do
that, Pooh Bear,
-only because of me.
-Oh, no.
This Halloween shall
be a Hallo-wasn't
and you shall have no
reason to be frightened.
Thank you, Pooh Bear.
Would you like us to
stay with you, Piglet?
No, I'll be quite all right now.
I had hoped it wouldn't
happen this year.
Everyone was looking
forward to Halloween so.
I've let down Pooh and Tigger
and Gopher and Eeyore
and most of all... me.
I do so hope this blusterous
and rather stormish night
will not be too frightening
for poor Piglet.
I suspect something
should be done.
But what?
I don't know either.
Think, think.
Why, just because Piglet can't
have Halloween with us,
there's no reason we can't
have Hallo-wasn't with him!
I like the way you think.
No way, no how, am I gonna miss
out on another Halloween!
I'll have my own
Hallo-wasn't all by myself.
If only Piglet was more
like me and less like him.
I love surprises and wearin' disguises
A horribly hideous costume'll do
Better be wary, be spooky and scary
I'll bounce from the shadows and "Boo"
I wanna scare myself
and everyone else
Those thrilly and chilly
old willys will rise
Cover your eyes, little buddy beware
I'm twitchin' and itchin' to scare
Myself
Unspeakable Spookables
Awful unlookables
Galloping ghosties
and goblins galore
What if they find you
Oh, look out behind you
A terrible Tigger-type roar
That would be me, hoo-hoo
I wanna scare myself
and everyone else
Those thrilly and chilly
old willys will rise
Cover your eyes, little buddy beware
I'm twitchin' and itchin' to scare
Myself
Now Tiggers I figger
make scares even bigger
They dress up and scream "Who am I?
Can you guess?"
And tricks always happen
when ghosts are a-flappin'
And tricks are what Tiggers like best!
I wanna scare myself and everyone else
Those thrilly and chilly
old willys will rise
Cover your eyes, little buddy beware
I'm twitchin' and itchin' to scare
Myself
And who better?
Oh, by the way. Boo!
Spookables!
Trick-or-treat, again.
We're on our way to Piglet's
to have a Hallo-wasn't,
-if you'd like to join...
-What're ya waitin' for?
Come on!
What was that?
Someone's coming!
It's a three-headed, bug-eyed
, saw-toothed Spookable!
I must find Pooh!
Perhaps we'd better
take off our costumes,
so as not to frighten him.
Piglet? Piglet?
Don't you know what this means?
He's been pignapped
by Spookables!
Hup, two, three, four.
Pooh wasn't at Eeyore's either,
and neither was Eeyore,
and no one was at Tigger's.
Hello, Rabbit?
Oh, no one at all is
where they should be.
Oh, dear.
Was that you, Eeyore?
Wish I could say it was.
But it wasn't.
If I didn't know any better,
I'd think you fellas
was all scaredy.
We are.
Well, I'm not!
Now quit climbin' all
over me, buddy bear!
We got piglets to find!
I think I have had a thought.
If we put our costumes on,
when we find the Spookables,
they shall think we're them and
we shall think they are us,
so we can save Piglet
and no one will be the wiser!
I know I got it this time!
Oh, an infestation of ghosts
and goblins and ghouls!
Piglet!
Excuse me, but could someone,
anyone really, help me?
Oh, dear! Pooh Bear!
Oh, they have Pooh Bear!
Two very fierce and
savage Spookables!
I must save my friend Pooh!
Boo! Boo, I say.
Boo!
Spookable!
What? Who's that?
Oh no, not this way!
Oh, dear!
Why, Piglet, you scared
the Spookable away!
I did?
You did and what you
did saved us all.
I did!
Three cheers for the bravest
little timid guy ever!
Hip-hip! Hooray! Hip-hip!
Hooray!
Dagnabit!
Why, Gopher, what a
wonderful costume.
lt is? lt is!
By dingy, it's the best!
That's what it is.
Of all the Halloweens
I can remember,
and I can't,
this Hallo-wasn't has been
the most unforgettable of all.
And I got a super, grade-A,
lollapaloozin' good scare!
Not that I was frightened by it.
And this year Piglet has made
it all the way through,
so our Hallo-wasn't
truly was a Hallo-was.
Hey, wait a half a segundo.
You never did figure out what
you're gonna be, Piglet!
Actually, Tigger, I did.
I've decided I'd like to
go as Pooh's very best,
and very bravest friend.
That, Piglet,
is the thing I should
most like you to be.
So, with just a little bit of
help from his very good friend...
-Pooh Bear?
-That's right.
Piglet became un-scared.
And he stayed un-scared
for a while.
'Cause he had his friends
to keep him company.
Lumpy, did my story
un-scare you?
I think so.
If someone as small as
Piglet can be brave,
-I can be twice as brave.
-At least.
You would never leave me
alone, would you, Roo?
Never, Lumpy. I promise.
-Brave together.
-Brave forever.
Conquerors of the Gobloon!
Come on, Lumpy.
Come on!
All we have to do now is
wait 'til he comes home.
Then I pull the rope, the trap
door slams down and wham!
-We get our wishes?
-Yep!
Now...
Don't make a sound.
Whoa!
What was that?
Maybe it's the Gobloon.
You stay here. I'll
go check it out.
If it's him, I'll
chase him here.
And when I give the signal
, you spring the trap.
What signal?
I'll hoot like Owl. Only
instead of "hoo hoo",
I'll hoot "Roo hoo".
On second thought, why
don't you come with me?
Good idea. That way I'll know
when you give the signal.
Come on.
It's coming from the bridge.
Follow me.
Lumpy, come on!
Lumpy, quiet!
Run, Lumpy! Run!
The Gobloon's gonna get us.
Help!
Roo!
Roo?
Roo, where are you?
You said you'd never
leave me alone.
Lumpy?
Where are you?
Help! The Gobloon's got me!
The Gobloon's got me!
Hold on, Roo. I'll save you!
Help!
Roo hoo!
Where are you, Roo?
Please answer me.
Roo?
Help! The Gobloon's got Roo!
Brave together, brave forever.
I'll save you, Roo.
If Piglet can be
un-scared, so can I.
Brave together, brave forever.
Conquerors of the Gobloon.
Oh, no, you don't.
-Boo.
-Oh, hello, Eeyore.
How'd you know it was me?
-Hello, Piglet.
-Hello, Pooh.
Look at me, Piglet.
I'm a little honey pot.
Oh, very nice, Pooh Bear.
Oh, hi, Tigger.
Tigger is my
mild-mannered alter-ego.
I am Super-Tigger.
I can leap over a house or something
really big, in a single bounce.
And then... And I...
I'm not kidding anyone.
lt just doesn't feel like
Halloween without any candy.
lt feels more like Hallow-almost
or Hallow-Not-Quite-Right.
-Or something.
-I know what you mean, Tigger.
Even my tummy can't be fooled.
Cheer up, everyone.
Halloween is saved.
I knew you could
do it, Long-Ears.
So, what did ya bring?
Popcorn balls?
Candied apples? Cookies?
-Even better.
-Honey?
-As long as it's candy.
Sure is.
Nature's candy. Vegetables.
Carrots. Radishes. Rutabagas.
Oh, they're tasty, juicy,
and most important,
good for you.
Well, I suppose we could go
trick-or-treating with these.
Well, I'll take
the trick, please.
Oh, nonsense. This is
going to be the best
and healthiest Halloween ever!
Finally, as it should be.
Hey, I just thought
of something.
If we're all here to go
tricking and treating,
then none of us are home
to be treated or tricked.
You're right, Tigger.
That is a bother.
But what should we do?
Think, think, think.
I have an idea!
Let's take turns.
We can practice
here at my house.
I don't know, Piglet.
What if you don't
answer the door?
Oh, I will! I
promise, I will!
Well, it's risky.
Oh, my head hurts.
But it's just crazy
enough to work.
-Let's give it a try.
-Goody-goody!
Who's there?
It's us! Who else could it be?
-"Us" who?
-"Us"!
Rabbit, Tigger and Pooh Bear!
Forgot me again.
Prove it.
Open this door at once!
-Rabbit! lt is you!
-Trick-or-treat!
Hooray!
I can't wait to try my place.
Wonder if I'm gonna be there.
Lumpy?
Where are you?
Oh, no! The Gobloon got you!
And he's turned you into
a jaggedy lantern.
Say something, Lumpy.
Oh no, Lumpy.
Don't worry, I'll find help.
It'll be OK.
I won't leave you again.
Let's give Rabbit the
old trickety-treatment.
Knockety knock knockety.
Guess who!
"Guess who," he says.
Gee, I don't know.
Pooh Bear? Tigger?
Oh, he's good.
Very good.
Anyway, let's see, where
are those treats?
Oh, here we go.
A nice juicy rutabaga
for Pooh Bear.
Prunes for Piglet,
celery for Eeyore,
and for you, Tigger.
.. spinach.
Roo-boy and Lumpy are
missing all the fun,
and the spinach.
I told 'em to be here at sunset.
I'm sure they'll be by any minute.
-Help!
-Roo-boy.
Help!
We tried to catch the Gobloon
, and we found his tree
but I got scared and ran away.
Then the Gobloon turned him
into a jaggedy lantern.
Could you start again
from that first Gobloon?
-Gobloon!
-Oh, dear.
The story's true. There
really is a Gobloon.
Quick, everyone, panic!
-Poor Lumpy.
-Oh, this will never do.
Wait a second. I got it.
We gotta catch the Gobloon.
-What?
-Well, if you catch the Gobloon,
-you get to make a wish.
-That's it, Tigger.
We can wish Lumpy back.
Tigger's right. Wait a minute.
Tigger's right? That
can't be right.
Hurry! There's not
a moment to lose!
-Hurry!
-Come on.
We're gonna save him.
-We're coming, Lumpy.
-Don't worry!
We'll have you back
to normal in no time.
I'm sorry I left you all alone.
Lumpy, we're coming for you!
We're coming, Lumpy!
Remind me again, Pooh Bear.
How did I ever become un-scared?
Listen, everyone.
The tree is making noises.
Maybe it has a bellyache.
That's the Gobloon!
The trap worked.
We caught him!
-Hooray!
-Hooray for us!
-I knew we could do it.
-Hooray! Yay!
Now what?
-Knock and shout "trick-or-treat".
-I could offer him some honey.
I don't think
Gobloons eat honey.
Well, he could sure
have all of my spinach.
Um, Mr Gobloon?
I don't want candy.
All I care about is Lumpy.
I wish my friend back.
You hear me, you
mean old Gobloon?
I want my friend back!
Roo? Roo! I'm in here!
Lumpy?
-You're OK!
-lt worked.
-Things couldn't get better.
-Roo wished Lumpy back!
-lt worked!
-Oh, yes!
Now, that's what I
call a happy ending.
I'm sorry I ran away, Lumpy.
I was just so scared.
Would you...
Could you... forgive me?
Gosh, Roo, you
came back for me.
That was brave.
I guess thinking about being
with you made me brave.
-Brave together?
-Brave forever.
Conquerors of the Gobloon!
-Hooray!
-Hooray for us!
Who needs candy to have
a great Halloween?
When we've got each other.
You know, it seems to me
there's only one
thing left to say.
I know, I know.
Trick-or-Treat.
-Gasp!
-Happy Halloween, everyone!
Trick-or-Treat.
Mama!
Come in.
I baked cookies and
rumpledoodles for everybody.
And I made a special
jack-o'-lantern
for each and every one of you.
Hello, gorgeous.
Doesn't look like me at all.
Why the long face?
Oh, look, Piglet. It's me
and my very best friend.
Oh, mine too!
Look, Lumpy. There's
even one for me.
-Wow!
-But where's yours?
I'm so sorry, Lumpy.
I did make one for you,
but it must have fallen
off my wheelbarrow.
See? I told you.
Halloween is the most fun ever.
You were right. I
love Hallowoon.
Hallow-woo... Hallow...
Oh, whatever.
As long as we're together.
We are daring to be scaring
Who's behind that
mask you're wearing?
We can "Boo!" a spooky greetin' Then
we'll share the sweets we're eating
When we're home from
trick or treating
With our friends
We're friends forever
We'll be brave together
We can weather
whatever comes along
One can do it Two is better
You and me together forever
Braver than brave
Stronger than strong
Brave together Singing our song
-We're friends forever
-One can do it, two is better
-We'll be brave together
-You and me together forever
-We can weather
-Braver than brave stronger than strong
-Whatever comes along
-We're brave together singing our song
Rumple de doodle Rumple dee dee
We'll rumble and tumble
like bumbly bees
Two together Together we're one
Rumple de doodle
De doodle de dum
-You're my buddy
-You're mine too
-If I get scared
-I'm right behind you
lt would be super if we could be
the bravest friends in history
We're friends forever
We'll be brave together
We can weather
whatever comes along
Whatever comes along