Yes, I swear that everything I say
is the whole truth.
Margarete Himmler.
No, my daughter Gudrun is with me.
Heinrich Himmler.
In the beginning
he was only the head of the SS.
Then he became Police Commissioner too,
and later, Minister of the Interior.
Yes.
There were papers and documents in it.
Yes, of course,
if the house is still standing.
October 8, 1900.
From Gebhard Himmler,
royal Bavarian teacher.
Your Royal Highness, Prince and Lord,
after speaking
with the parish priest of St. Anne's,
I humbly inform you
that the priest
will baptize our little Heinrich
on Saturday, October 13.
I feel grateful and thankful to you,
Your Royal Highness,
for agreeing to be
godfather to this child.
It might interest you
that our little son weighed
on his second day on earth,
seven pounds, 200 grams.
He measured 52 cm.
Thank God, he's very lively
and always hungry.
September 4, 1906. Heinrich started
grade one at the Cathedral School.
Heinrich was often ill with mono,
measles, pneumonia, mumps,
but he caught up,
with the help of Miss Rudelt
and passed with a B.
March 12, 1910.
I must admit I was lazy
and neglected my diary.
My elder brother Gebhard and I
attended the Passion Play at church
with Mom and Dad.
The actors playing Christ and Judas
and their costumes
were very enjoyable.
The orchestra and singing were pretty.
August 5, 1913.
Morning with Mom at Holy Mass.
At 5:45 Princess Arnulf
and Prince Heinrich came for tea.
We were photographed by Prince Heinrich.
I lost 10 million.
Thursday, July 28, 1914.
Played Shield and Sword
with Falk Zipperer.
I have 40 battalions this time.
Russia, France, and Belgium
against Germany and Austria.
I lost 10 million.
The game is fascinating
and won't be over for a while.
August 1. Mobilization in Germany.
August 2. Germany declares war on Russia.
August 5. England declares war.
French and Russian border crossings.
Victory of German crown prince
north of Metz.
Germany's dignified response
to Japan's ultimatum.
Played piano. Glued stamps in the evening.
I went to see the bulletin boards
before breakfast.
Big victory! 26,000 prisoners.
8:00 am. School. Speech by headmaster.
We sang Deutschland Uber alles
(Germany Above All) and another song.
Hindenburg captured another
50,000 men in Masuria. Hurray!
Falk and I want to join the brawl.
At 5:00 pm, Mom and Dad
drove to the train station
to hand out refreshments
to the wounded soldiers.
Gebhard was allowed to go with them,
which made me jealous.
It's not 70,000 Russians
captured in East Prussia but 90,000.
They multiply like vermin.
Images from the Western Front.
Had a bad day at school.
Trouble with Pro)'. Wurmsee.
He still doesn't believe me.
I Went home with a headache
and didn't go back in the afternoon.
Instead I went' to bed.
People in Landshut
are so dumb and cowardly.
Even the idea
of the troop withdrawal from Paris
made them shit their pants.
I would have expected that
least of all from the Bavarians,
since they are usually so rowdy.
Even a wounded soldier said so.
Gebhard turns 17 today
and joins the Landsturm (militia).
I wish I was the right age.
I'd have gone ages ago.
I look forward to joining them.
I can be useful
to the fatherland out there.
People don't like me.
Citizens! Gather to protest
the shame of Versailles!
Germany must give up its colonies!
Germany alone
must accept guilt for the war!
Germany must pay billions in reparations!
Germany must eliminate its army!
Citizens! Gather to protest
against the shame of Versailles!
September 4, 1919.
Sick. Fainted this morning.
Horrible night.
Cramps. Stomach pain.
I was moody and depressed.
I never reveal my troubled thoughts
and my struggling soul.
I'm pessimistic about politics,
very pessimistic.
MUNICH UNIVERSITY STUDENT ID
November 10, 1919.
I don't know
who I am studying for right now.
I study because it is my duty.
Today I started to regain my equilibrium.
I was accepted into the Apollo fraternity.
It has a very decent national attitude.
Father was also a member.
At the gathering
I sat at the leaders' table.
Conversations about
land reform, degeneracy,
homosexuality, the Jewish question.
I volunteered for special activities.
I drank two mugs of beer
and thanked the chairman.
He said, in a farsighted way,
that it wouldn't be
the last time I'd speak.
7:00. Went to a fencing match.
I wasn't nervous.
I fought quite well,
and technically, I fenced fine.
It turned out
I had five cuts that were bleeding.
I didn't even twitch.
Now I'm happy-
At 3:00 pm We Went for a useless drive
with the other students.
We went to the Reich's Eagle Bar.
It was crawling with Jews.
A dancer came up to us.
She was quiet and simple,
not vain or snobbish.
She's from Vienna, but Jewish.
Still, there was nothing
Jewish in her behavior.
I made some remarks about Jews,
not thinking she was one.
She teased me a bit,
but in a delightful Way.
In a word, that girl deserves respect.
The girls were generally pretty.
Some were even beautiful.
Slutty but stunning.
The horrible thing
about Germany today is
that women don't want
to be mothers anymore.
February 22, 1922.
At 9:00, Apollo voted. I wasn't elected.
Bad feeling in the pit of my stomach.
A terrible feeling of
dissatisfaction and disgust.
People don't like me.
Why? Because I talk too much.
I'm such a chatter-box,
I can never shut my mouth.
Thoughtless and immature.
When will I get a grip on myself?
Last night
I was very somber and depressed.
I wanted to get up at 5:30
to fire a machine gun, but overslept.
I didn't hear the alarm.
I'm ashamed! Is that soldier-like?
I'm so weak-minded.
You star?' to think,
“If only there was a war again,
if only I could put my life
on the line, fight,
it would be a pleasure.”
I went to visit Hugo.
His little daughter Irmgard
jumps around naked before bed.
I disapprove of a three-year-old
behaving like that.
Children should be taught modesty.
Hugo pinched me because I said
I never flirted, and called me a eunuch.
The young, undisciplined generation
is a serious threat to Germany.
Dear God, turn it back
to how it was before.
Got books. They give me peace of mind.
Read Rudolph Stratz's
The Light in the East.
Everyone has the urge to grow,
but our space is limited.
So, the fight to breed begins,
the fight for space.
When there's another campaign in the east,
I will join it.
The east is most important for us.
We must fight for it and settle it.
Tacitus' Germania,
new translation by Dr. Ludwig Wilser.
An admirable picture: how great,
how morally pure our ancestors were.
We should be like that again,
at least some of us.
Read Oscar Wilde's
The Priest and the Acolyte.
Sunday evening, 70:30.
I'm in a terrible mood.
Odd.
The idealization of a homosexual.
The pictures are disgusting.
Knight, Death and the Devil,
Hans F.K. Gunther.
He is not only the most talented man,
the man of the Nordic race
is also the most beautiful man.
The slender figure of the man,
standing tall,
a victorious expression
in his bone and muscle structure.
Both men and women have a glowing skin,
well supplied with blood,
blond hair, light, victorious eyes.
Both have the perfect movements
of a perfect body.
They are a royal race among mankind.
April 2, 1923.
Ire-ad Struggle and Death by Karl XII,
the tale of a man of steel
who stirred a nation with his spirit and will
until the last day of his life
and encouraged every one
of those brave men to be heroic,
a man desperately needed nowadays.
MEIN KAMPF
BY ADOLF HITLER
I believe in the revolution.
But the general opinion is that
it will result in a bloody fight.
I'd be glad if history started right now.
JOINED THE PARTY:
8. 1. 1923
SS BADGE OF HONOR, NSDAP
August 22, 1924.
Dear old comrade,
I had an inhuman amount of work today.
I had to lead and restructure
all of Lower Bavaria.
It is an act of selflessness
serving a great idea, a great cause.
Yesterday I drove to Vilsbiburg.
The coachman picked me up.
On our way I taught him
our national philosophy.
Then to the castle.
Castle. Torture chamber. Very interesting.
In the castle and the inner city
you feel the spirit of the Middle Ages,
its honor, great', severe, calm,
the spirit of times gone by.
How detached us men of culture
have become from our ancestors' knowledge.
If only we were like
the old Germanic people
with their customs
and their healthy attitude.
The goals of the SS of the NSDAP are:
A: protecting gatherings
of local NSDAP groups,
B: strengthening Hitler's personal escort
in case our Fuhrer
speaks near some local group.
I can predict the horrors of the future.
A woman is loved by a real man
in three Ways:
as a beloved child
that one must argue with or even punish,
as a wife who shares your struggle
without shackling you,
as a goddess, whose feet one must kiss.
My dearly beloved,
before we met on that train,
I'd lost faith in humanity,
especially in the honesty and truth
that a man shows a woman.
I can believe and trust again.
You don't know what that means.
I've received the precious gifts
of you and your love.
I kiss you.
Yours, Marga.
Letter no. 4.
Dear Marga,
I know that fate treats me kindly
when I see your pretty face
and your lovely, loyal blue eyes.
I've numbered this letter.
I think it is quite useful.
I have a feeling we 'll be
writing each other very often.
The numbering starts on our December 18.
Arrived at Berlin Central Station
at 5:23 pm.
Yours, Heinrich.
Under the linden trees
Walks the maiden
If you want to find one
Then stroll after them
If you start at the Café Bauer
She still says, "Fm sorry”
Once you are at the Paris Square
Whoosh!
She is already your sweetheart
She still says, "Fm sorry”
Once you are at the Paris Square
Whoosh!
She is already your sweetheart
Munich, February 28, 1928.
Letter no. 65.
Dear Marga,
how nice to know
that after the service
I'd meet my little woman for a few hours
to chat and share things
we wouldn't tell anyone else,
because they wouldn't understand us,
and because we are too proud
to show a part of our souls
to people who could mock us.
With love.
Yours, Heini.
Berlin, letter no. 73.
My beloved, your letter found me
in not such a good mood.
I was in more trouble
than I thought possible.
Four operations and one death.
It is tough to own a clinic.
I am returning from the city.
I had a beer with Mrs. Reifschneider.
She has strongly advised me
against seeing a man
seven years younger than me.
We women are the weaker sex.
I don't want to impose on you.
Yours, Marga.
Munich, letter no. 74.
My pretty little woman.
Please do me a favor
and don't bother yourself anymore.
I can promise you one thing:
I will never change.
Here we call the good woman as a witness,
and a ceremonial pact will be signed
like Jews do.
1) The rascal cooks every day
for the well-behaved man
a bowl of soup.
2) The naughty man eats the soup.
3) The rascal exercises a few minutes
every morning and might.
Your naughty man.
My dear love! I laughed so much.
I can't imagine such a man for myself.
Never again write “1, 2, 3.”
It's like a typical bureaucrat.
Are you a bureaucrat?
The good woman
isn't able to exercise alone,
so she treats her legs with care for stairs
and all the other naughty things.
My naughty man,
it means revenge when you're back.
Revenge! Revenge!
Our revenge will be wonderful.
Soon the good woman
will be with her naughty man
and plucked and twitched
and flayed and scolded.
A trick, and the naughty man
is totally well-behaved,
because he is so fond of his little woman.
Yours, Marga.
Dear rascal! I know you well now.
You 're so incredibly sly.
Darling, “1, 2, 3” isn't a bureaucrat
but a military man.
I have six meetings
over the next three days:
Munster, Passau, Memmingen.
On Tuesday in Landshut, I assume.
Now I have to pick up the boss.
He is speaking tonight.
An endearing kiss.
Yours, Heini.
My good, wild beloved!
You're a real travel agency.
Why are you going to a Hitler rally
when you know what he will say?
I must go to Hitler's rallies,
because I organize them
and I am jointly responsible for them.
A few more months,
and the naughty man will be yours forever.
Think of your revenge.
With love. Yours, Heini.
My dear beloved,
how can I like a movement
that doesn't give you any time to visit?
I understand so little about politics.
I prefer practicing revenge.
Harsh revenge!
Let other people work for you.
I kiss you. Yours, Marga.
Leading means
always doing more than others.
Only then can you demand
maximum efficiency.
Yes, dear child,
What a naughty man you have,
with such an evil, naughty movement.
Yes, I know I am harsh,
but it has a good side.
HEINRICH HIMMLER, LICENSED FARMER
MARGA HIMMLER, BORN BODEN
MARRIED
July 16, 1928.
Darling, I was at Hanomag-Auto.
h' costs 2,300 in total,
While a Dixie, which is better,
costs 2, 500.
Dear, that is too expensive.
Let us stick with the Hanomag.
Hanomag are evil thieves
and a Jewish company.
The Dixie two-seater
is a wonderful little car.
Darling, you will have great fun with it.
Order a Hanomag immediately.
Women also belong to the SS.
They are part of the SS,
since we're not just a military organization,
but a community, an order.
Women must also obey.
NATIONAL SOCIALIST PARTY MEMBER
NO. 97252
MARGA HIMMLER
APPROVED BY:
HEINRICH HIMMLER
Dear Marga, I once told you
that I'd never disappoint you.
What I can't vouch for is my fate.
I always worry about
whether I have a right
to cause bitter distress
to the person I love endlessly.
I can never disregard my duty,
and I may drag you down with me
in a whirl of worry, agony and fate.
We are German mercenaries,
fighting for liberty,
and should remain alone.
Dear, dear child,
I don't write these words carelessly.
I can predict the horrors of the future.
My mercenary will never improve,
but he is loved the way he is,
and your love, if it belongs to me,
gives me the strength and courage
to suffer through everything.
I shall proudly endure my destiny.
I love you very much, Marga.
How marvelous our life will be.
My dear, pure, gracious wife,
this morning I had a meeting
with a party member about the SS'
and the financial opportunities.
When the Jew gives you
the money for the clinic,
please send it to me.
I need it to expand the house.
Hauschild hasn't paid me
for the clinic yet.
A Jew remains a Jew.
Sometimes I worry about
how crass those people are.
ls everyone as bad as my pack of Jews?
My charming, cute little wife,
money is such a necessity.
How nasty and cursed it is.
Don't be annoyed by your Jew anymore.
Letter no. 145.
You good, sweet little wife.
Dear darling, how lovely our home will be.
How fine.
The trees and shrubs have grown.
I'll handle the details
with the painter and electrician tomorrow.
I left you a note
with the windows' measurements.
The kitchen I specified yellowish,
the stairs, blue-gray,
the bedroom, fright green,
the maid's room, a lighter color,
and the guest room, a lighter color too.
How marvelous our life will be.
Our pure, deep love of body and soul.
Dearest wife, how I love you.
All filth will be kept
out of our home, our castle.
Your husband.
As per the order of our Fuhrer
on January 6, 1929,
I have taken over the leadership
of the SS of the NSDAP.
When recruiting SS members
I demand the following criteria:
The minimum age will be 23,
minimum height, 1.70m,
one year of party membership,
written testimony of two witnesses
willing to vouch for the man.
He must also be a good and decent person.
Out of 100 men,
we can take no more than 10 to 15.
We demand a report
on the family's political affiliations.
We require a family tree
going back to 7750.
We will gather as many people as possible
who have the desired bloodline
of the German nation,
and discipline them as soldiers.
Through the land of Germany we march
We fight for Adolf Hitler
The Red Front, beat them to a pulp
The SA is on the march
Beware
Clear the road
So comrades, come rally
And the last fight let us face
The Internationale
Unites the human race
Letter no. 152.
Dear Marga,
I went to my parents
to explain the dire need
for street fighting to my father.
Fighting and working
never caused me any harm.
We strive for the revolution.
That's our goal.
I read in the papers about
the street fights in Brunswick.
Why do you want to pick up
the bloodthirsty knife?
Dearly beloved, are you good and decent?
There is one thing you cannot ask of me.
I can? always be as good
as you want me to be.
You should always remain honest.
You nasty man with the black soul.
Gudrun Margaret
Elfriede Emma Anna
was born on August 8, 1929,
by cesarean section in a Munich hospital.
She weighed 3,625 grams
and was 54 cm long.
Blond, blue-eyed, with rosy little nails.
Our good child sneezes just like
her daddy every day, twice in a row.
January 12, 1930.
She now raises her head
on her own and tries to laugh.
She loves baths
and she splashes water everywhere.
All in all, she's very lively.
Before each even)',
the SS lines up in two rows by height'.
SS evenings are followed
by obedience exercises
for at least 45 minutes.
They drill:
standing at attention, turns,
counting, Salutations, et cetera.
Singing is to be practiced as well.
I expect all commands
to be obeyed at all times.
Gudrun's birthday party.
August 8, 1930.
Her grandparents came by bus at 2:30,
as did the Schonbohms.
Gudrun's hand on her first birthday.
She didn't stop moving as I drew.
April 13, 1931.
She likes to visit the chickens.
She's not afraid of them,
not even of the big turkey.
She plays with the livestock
and feeds them happily.
She has learned a lot lately.
She understands most of what she is told.
She likes to work and to help.
She loves her daddy above all.
She always asks, ”Where's Daddy?”
then sadly says, “Daddy is away.”
June 2, 1932.
Darling, your evil husband
can't write you often.
The time until the elections will be terrible.
Don't get angry.
Darling, we will fight for our love,
and everything will go well.
Our paradise,
the one we built for ourselves,
cannot be destroyed by anyone.
Must Uncle Hitler also die?
Chancellor Adolf Hitler.
The leader of young Germany.
Our nation,
our fatherland,
and our fuhrer!
It was already 10:30 pm,
and Gudrun wasn't asleep yet.
Suddenly she said,
“Must Uncle Hitler also die?”
I calmed her and said,
“Uncle Hitler will live for a long time. ”
Delighted, she called out,
”100 years! Very long!
No, Mommy, I know. 200 years!”
When I said, ”Of course,”
she was satisfied.
She lay down quietly and soon fell asleep.
That is why
you are doing a good thing
by putting the demons of the past
to the flames.
It is a powerful, great, symbolic act.
My dear son,
you finally gained ground in the fortress.
You too shall receive our heartfelt
and sincere congratulations
for the success and victory
of the movement
to which you have given so much.
Your dear mother is quite overwhelmed.
My dear son,
I take joy in congratulating you,
now that you
and all your ambitions have been fulfilled,
and our Fuhrer
has won the longed-for victory.
May he continually be granted luck
and God's blessing.
And for you, my dear son,
I wish from the bottom of my heart
that with all the hassle
and stress of work, you stay well.
With tender and loving care,
with warm greetings and kisses,
your mother.
Dear Heinrich,
may we ask you to forward
our most intimate
and joyous thanks to our Fuhrer
for his picture
with the gracious dedication,
as we are not allowed
to thank him personally?
How pleased we are with
every picture of you, my dear Heinrich,
and for the reports on the radio
and in the newspapers.
I cordially greet and kiss you with love.
Your mother, Heil Hitler.
I know that there are some people
in Germany
who get sick
when they see our black uniforms.
We understand
and don't expect to be loved by many.
All those who cherish Germany
will and should respect us.
Only those
with the slightest pangs of conscience
for acting against the nation
and the fuhrer need to fear us.
Reichsfuhrer-SS H. Himmler.
THE JEWS ARE OUR MISFORTUNE
DON'T BUY IN JEWISH SHOPS
It is a small international group
without any roots
which sets nation against nation.
Jews!
They are the only group
that should be called international,
because they do business everywhere.
We don't have enough children.
A good, racially pure nation
that is short of children
is doomed to extinction.
A nation that has many children
has the benefit of world power
and world domination.
For a good and healthy marriage,
a minimum of four children is required.
h', due to unhappy circumstances,
a married couple fails to give birth to children,
every SS leader
should adopt
racially, hereditarily healthy children
and raise them in the spirit
of national socialism.
May 10, 1933.
On Friday, our foster son
Gerhard von der Ahé came to live with us.
He is a handsome, lively boy.
Puppi wanted to fondle and mother him,
but he disliked it, so he hit her,
and the big fight started.
Unfortunately, they quarrel often.
The boy wants to have everything,
and, although Puppi
gives him some of her toys,
she is quite jealous.
What I demand of you is order,
order in big things,
and order in small things.
Order creates the nation, the culture,
and order creates the state.
The soldier whose uniform is disorderly
will no longer be obedient,
like the soldiers of Bolshevism are not.
We will teach all these things.
Even decent eating,
we will teach the commanders.
I also demand to persevere with education.
No reward without effort.
I expect human kindness.
See yourself as helpers
not as dictators.
BLUEPRINT:
DACHAU CONCENTRATION CAMP
The Reichsfuhrer-SS proclaims
the first concentration camp
has been built in Dachau.
The new home for 5,000 Communist
and Social Democrat nuisances.
Dear Heinrich,
as an old man I didn't have the heart
to chase away this desperate mother,
a war widow whom I've known for years.
She is running from
one department to the next,
sobbing and pleading for help.
I am forwarding her request to you.
Forgive my softness.
Please try to help her son.
EMSLAND HOUSE
ARCHITECT: ALBERT SPEER
Dear Parents,
of course I'll hear the plea
of that war widow.
In a hurry, Heil Hitler.
Yours, Heinrich.
Dear Heinrich,
you must be thinking,
“It's my father again.”
Dr. Weber, my successor,
spoke to me on Saturday
about a personal matter.
I know for sure that he and his family
always had and still have
a nationalist worldview.
Only his eldest son Franz,
a lawyer, strayed.
His parents worked hard
so that he doesn't starve.
He was probably misled by his wife,
to earn some money,
and Went to defend Communists,
though he is not a Communist.
His poor mother was shocked
when, early this Sunday,
six people, and three more later,
showed up at her door
to search the apartment
for weapons, documents, et cetera,
and to interrogate the family.
I'm asking you to do what you can.
Dear Father,
thank you very much
for your letter of November 23.
lam attaching a copy
of the response to Mr. Weber,
so you can see how it was handled.
Thank you very much.
You were merciful.
Dear Heinrich,
all these petitions are a burden
to an old man like me.
They depress me.
Today at noon
I found this letter from my good friend,
the senior teacher, Dr. Brunner,
concerning the arrest of his son.
Please help this respectable man.
Father, the arrest of Brunner's son
was essential.
Dear Heini, on his name day
your good father
received lots of congratulations.
Only yours, dear Heinrich, was missing.
DEATH NOTICE FOR GEBHARD HIMMLER
H. is absolutely right.
Better to aggravate others than yourself.
Today we are having dinner with 25 guests.
Everything is done poorly.
Heini is livid.
The staff here is terrible.
There are still people like that
in the Third Reich! God, those people!
Heini is absolutely right.
Better to aggravate others than yourself.
Heinrich had to leave early.
He works day and night.
How does he manage?
He is so tired and tense
from all the troubles.
I always think he's not fully appreciated.
All sexual matters
are no longer private.
They are a matter of life and death
for the nation.
Here's a real life example.
Department Head X is homosexual
and is looking for an assistant
from the young clerks.
He won't choose someone
based on his merits.
He won't look for the best legal mind.
He will select another homosexual.
Those people can recognize their kind
across a room.
Homosexuality undermines
the states achievements
and destroys its foundations.
Sadly, we don't have it
as easy as our ancestors.
They only dealt with
a few cases of this perversion,
and homosexuals
were drowned in the swamp.
I've decided.
They will be sent to a concentration camp
per my order,
and shot on the spot
as if they attempted to escape.
IN THE VALEPP
March 11, 1938.
As of yesterday,
10 of us are in the Valepp.
Puppi and Riischen
saw a deer for the first time
and were so happy.
Time passes quickly with the children.
They switch from sweet to nasty,
from bickering to getting along.
Lately, the boy has been well-behaved.
RECIPES
SOUPS, VEGETABLES,
MUSHROOMS, FISH, ROAST
We invited the Wedels, the Oswalds,
and Berta and her husband.
We ate dinner
to the strains of Gypsy music.
March 12, 1938.
Heini went hunting today.
We listened to the radio till 2:00 am.
Heini was the first to enter Vienna.
Now Austria is part of the German Reich.
Heini called. He is doing well,
but he is overwhelmed.
During the night Puppi got ill
and had a fever. I couldn't sleep.
I sat by her bed
and told her it is already 2:30
so she should try
to get some sleep.
She said,
“At this time yesterday, Daddy went in!”
She meant Vienna.
Obviously the girl
is strongly connected to her father.
As long as there are people on earth,
humans and sub-humans will be at war.
Biologically, the sub-human
seems to be the same kind of creature,
with arms and legs,
some kind of a brain, eyes and mouth,
but emotionally and spiritually
inferior to any animal.
The sub-human hates the work of others.
He rages against it secretly like a thief,
and publicly
like a blasphemer and murderer.
The sub-human's desires are eternal:
That everything will turn to wasteland,
and the light of knowledge will turn dark.
Regarding the Jews,
when will those scoundrels finally leave,
so we can enjoy life again?
JEWS ARE NOT WANTED IN THE
COASTAL RESORT OF RAUSCHEN!
THE SYNAGOGUE IS BURNING!
- I swear.
- To Adolf Hitler -
I can assure you of one thing.
As long as I run the SS,
during this war
there will be no draft dodgers
or individuals
who even think of starting a revolution.
A master race
must be able to eliminate individuals
who are harmful to society.
We must show no mercy.
It doesn't matter if 7, 000
must be eliminated in one town.
I will certainly do that.
People will speak of this
a thousand years hence.
Berlin, September 4, 1939.
Now there is war.
Puppi has a map of Germany
and tracks everything her daddy does.
Gerhard has a delinquent streak.
He stole some money
and is lying through his teeth.
The German Red Cross assigned me
to the field hospitals in Military District III.
lam glad to be a par?' of this.
GERMANY - POLAND = 1:0
Heini was so happy on his birthday.
The Fuhrer promoted him
to the settlement commissioner of Germany.
It feels so good
that he is finally being recognized.
I was in Poznan, Lodz and Warsaw.
Muhlenhavel and its surroundings
look terrible.
All is falling apart.
During the Polish era,
nothing was done.
There is so much to do.
These Jewish scoundrels, the Pollocks,
don't even look human.
Pollocks don't die as easily
from diseases.
They are immune.
It is an enormous task
to establish order there.
Heini has too much work.
People will speak of this
a thousand years hence.
State police regulations:
You are hereby notified
that within seven hours
you mus)' leave your apartment.
Tie all your keys together
and label them
with your name and address.
You may take one suitcase,
no bigger than 100 x 80 x 80.
You may not take
cash, securities, foreign currency,
savings, books
and valuables of any kind,
gold, silver, platinum,
and no livestock.
You must follow all orders
without objection
or be subject to severe penalties.
GHETTO
NO ENTRY FOR GERMAN ARMED FORCES
RESIDENTIAL AREA FOR JEWS
ENTRY PROHIBITED
Today we visited
the SS concentration camp in Dachau.
POETRY
Your parents' home
should be your home.
Your mom.
Gmund, Tegernsee.
You must always be decent,
brave and kind.
Your father. Gmund, May 18, 1941.
The Lindenfycht home in Gmund.
My parents' house.
All of the SS men address me now
formally as “Miss Gudrun.”
It sounds so strange.
When peace returns,
We will probably get a farm in the east.
That would bring in more money.
Maybe we can even get
a house in Obersalzberg.
The Lindenfycht home
will someday be mine.
Yes, when peace comes,
but that will take a long time,
a very long time,
two to three years.
Today we visited
the SS concentration camp in Dachau:
Mommy, Aunt Lydia, Aunt Frieda,
Roschen, Inge Hammer! and me.
We saw everything.
The vegetable patch, the mill, the bees.
Then we saw the books,
from the 16th century until today.
Then, the pictures that the prisoners painted.
They're beautiful.
Then We ate, a lot.
Then everyone got a gift.
h' was so nice.
A very large operation.
Aunt Lydia and I are alone again.
Daddy is in the east.
Mommy is in Paris.
Yesterday I sat in the last row
in biology class.
During a test,
I copied from a note I had.
Mrs. Zimmer saw it but said nothing.
I thought it was very decent other.
June 15, 1941. My wonderful Mommy.
Before I leave
I wanted to send you a note
and some flowers.
The next time I write,
it will be from Russia.
Here are five chocolate bars
I promised for the children.
Lots of love and kisses.
Yours, Daddy.
My dearest love,
Puppi is only 12 years old,
so she cannot even imagine the war.
She mentions her birthday every day.
With love and kisses.
Yours, Marga.
My wonderful Mommy,
the trip to the Baltic states
was very interesting.
I also think it is good
that our Puppi doesn't fully grasp the war,
but you should tell her about it.
There are huge tasks ahead,
and, as far as distance,
we are only at the beginning.
I sent a package today for Puppi,
our sweetheart.
Lots of love and kisses.
Yours, Daddy.
My dear, beloved Daddy,
I'm so sad you left again
to fight the war.
I hope that you are well.
It is terrible that we are at war
with the Russians.
They were once our allies.
Please be careful and be safe.
You do not need to send us more chocolate.
The postman brought so much.
Thank you.
How the Russians feel,
how the Czechs feel,
does not concern me at all.
Whether other nations
live in prosperity or die from hunger
interests me only insofar
as we need them as slaves for our culture.
If they dare harm one of us,
they and all Polish men
in their village will die.
We will never be cruel
when it is unnecessary.
We Germans
are the only nation in the world
with a decent attitude toward animals,
and we will have a decent attitude
toward these human animals.
Ten or 20
or 100 years from today,
the current German border
will be left far behind.
We will create pure Germanic areas,
just like our ancestors did.
August 8, 1941. My birthday.
We lit 13 candles and the Yule lamp.
Every SS man should have one.
From Daddy I got pictures
of all the German emperors,
stilts, turtles,
a book of traditional costumes
and a basket of roses.
Elke gave me a Shetland pony.
Daddy won't let me keep it
because Elke's parents
want to benefit from our friendship.
Daddy says I 'll get a horse
when there is peace.
Here I am in all my glory!
No tree has leaves like me!
It is evening.
The Jew walks through the forest
with his long beard, carrying a sack.
He picks all the leaves,
puts them in his sack,
and leaves the poor tree naked.
Despite all the work
lam doing fine and I sleep well.
Household expenditures:
salaries, 90 marks,
donations, five marks,
stationery, 1.25 marks,
Puppi, 2.25 marks,
flowers, 5.40 marks,
miscellaneous, 1.40 marks.
My dear Mommy,
I am so sorry that I forgot
our wedding anniversary for the first time,
but I was so busy these past few days.
I wake up at 9:00, and at 10:00
I get dressed, eat breakfast
and shave while Dr. Brandt
reads the morning mail to me.
8:30-9:30, wake up, tidy up,
stroll through the garden,
discuss all the work
that must get done.
Crafts.
Then working and governing
by phone, radio and telegraph.
In the afternoon, Puppi and I
read the books you sent us.
Every other day at 1 :00 pm,
I drive to the Fuhrer,
arriving at 2:00, and eat.
4:00-5:00pm, work on train on the way home.
Saturday to Tuesday
I visited the training sites
and saw very interesting
new shooting procedures.
In between,
trips of three or more days
to Lublin, Lemberg,
Dubno, Rowno, Luzk.
My dear Mommy,
enclosed please find
a very interesting report
in which our Gerhard plays a role.
He probably can? help it,
but his willingness to lie is typical.
When I write to Gerhard,
should I still sign, “Mother”?
For now I wouldn't sign with "Mother?
If his behavior improves you may again.
He'll be going to Kovno, Riga and Minsk.
Despite all the work,
lam doing fine and I sleep Well.
Lots of kisses.
With love. Yours, Heini.
Thank you for your lovely letter.
Look, in this picture
you're making a funny face.
You look so, so sweet in h'.
When I look at the picture,
you look straight back at me.
Daddy, come back to us soon.
Letter no. 99a
to the Reichsfuhrer-SS.
I send the following interim report
regarding General von den Bach.
He suffers from hallucinations
related to the shooting
of Jews he conducted
and other harsh experiences in the east.
The severe exhaustion,
and the nerves in particular,
seen in this patient, coming from
the Eastern Front is apparent.
His bowels had to be emptied manually,
as is common when the intestine
has been immobilized with opium.
My dear Mommy,
I had a bad stomachache,
but I'm feeling well again.
These intestinal issues are so disgusting.
Dozens of people on the front
also suffer from it.
Yours, Heini.
Orders to all commanders:
The sacred duty of commanders
is to personally ensure
that none of our men
charged with this grave duty
ever suffers from it,
mentally or emotionally.
This is to be achieved
with the strictest discipline
when performing official duties
and through friendly gatherings
in the evenings.
The nights should be devoted
to German customs,
with the men gathered around tables to eat,
enjoying music, lectures
and the beautiful world
of the German intellect,
to fill their leisure time with joy.
Secret Affairs of the Reich.
To the Reichsfuhrer-SS.
The inspection of the cars
in Group C and D is completed.
Killing with gas was not done correctly.
To complete the action faster,
they push down on the accelerator.
This way,
the prisoners die of asphyxiation,
rather than being slowly put to sleep.
It is now proved
that, when done this way,
death occurs faster,
and the prisoners fall asleep peacefully.
The distorted faces and excretions
are no longer evident.
I'd like to draw your attention
to the following.
The cars are now recognized
and referred to as “death cars.”
It is a horrible slight
for a German to watch.
That's how it is,
and, if it were not so terrible for us,
we would not be Germans,
or even Germanic.
If we lack the nerve now,
our bad nerves
will be passed on to our sons
and our grandsons.
If only they knew how bitter life is.
Dear Sister,
unfortunately, the exceptional circumstances
caused by this war
make it impossible to discuss
the content of this letter in person.
Christmas 1938.
Heinrich and I had a talk
in which we confessed
that we love each other deeply.
ll ls very unlikely that he will divorce.
His daughter is only 13 years old.
His wife can't give him more children.
She is already 48.
The only ones who know our secret
are the Fuhrer,
Martin Bormann and Karl Wolff.
Your sister, Hedwig.
My beloved bunny,
you gave me your dear beloved heart
and your entire self.
I have just one wish.
Despite the obstacles,
may you be as happy as you made me
and make me every day.
I kiss your dear, fine hands
and your sweet mouth.
Yours, H.
My dear, good husband,
I attach Puppi's Christmas wish list.
You can check off what you plan to buy her
and send it back to me.
Now the Christmas gifts
for the SS are being bought.
10,000 bars of chocolate.
Do you know what I want
from you this Christmas?
Yours, Marga.
This year We will celebrate
our first Christmas without Daddy.
Gerhard is coming too.
Daddy called us.
Previously, when I asked Daddy
for my Christmas present,
he said he got me a block of wood
so that I wouldn't be cold.
Will the war be over by next Christmas?
God, keep our daddy safe.
My dear,
I received a package from E. Lorenz.
It was a giant bird.
At first I was shocked by the sight of it,
because I saw myself eating it
for the next eight days.
When I went to thank Erika for the gift,
she told me that it was from you.
Yours, H.
Midnight, and again I cannot sleep.
Thoughts, thoughts.
Mops Wedel died in battle.
Eighteen years old, SS.
His poor mother.
I have not heard anything from Heini
in the last two days.
Mrs. Berkelmann wrote me today.
She's getting a divorce.
Her husband is having a child
with another woman.
Every young girl longs for a husband.
If only they knew how bitter life is.
Well, Sister, the important thing
is that since late June
I'm sure that our wish is fulfilled.
Our child is growing inside me.
How satisfying it feels when it moves.
I love imaging myself holding it in my arms,
and how I will care for it.
I can't even describe it to you.
The way he takes care of me
is so touching.
Sometimes ifs too much,
not even pleasant.
Your sister, Hedwig.
BIRTH CERTIFICATE
CHILD: HELGE POTTHAST
MOTHER: HEDWIG POTTHAST
FATHER: UNKNOWN
My dear bunny,
soon I will call you
so I can hear your sweet voice.
The package does not contain any valuables,
but everything in it was carefully chosen.
I hope our child
will not hurt itself with the rattle.
I love you endlessly.
Yours, H.
Heini was nearby for two days
and didn't even call.
I will suffer and endure everything
for my child.
She is only 13
and should not know how serious life is.
She hears enough things
she doesn't need to know.
Can you still trust and believe a person?
Time will tell.
Secret Affairs of the Reich.
Letter no. 122a.
Dear Mr. Reichsfuhrer,
it is my obligation to report to you
on the progress of my research.
The method I created
to sterilize the female body
without surgery
is just about done.
This method will enable us
to sterilize hundreds,
if not thousands, of Jews per day.
Out of the 10 million Jews
living in Europe,
two to three million should be sterilized,
and kept alive for labor.
Secret Affairs.
Honorable Herr Professor,
the Jewish females are to know nothing.
As part of a general examination,
you could administer
the appropriate syringes.
About the effectiveness of the sterilization,
in-depth tests are to be performed
in which a female Jew
is locked in with a male Jew.
We can then observe the outcome.
Heil Hitler.
Dear Sister,
I wanted to find a new job
and try to achieve a certain independence.
King Heinrich commented on my plan
that the very thought of me
earning my own bread
was intolerable to him.
Once the war is over,
he wants to buy us a country home
that will always be a warm refuge for us.
He thought of installing a small nursery
or breeding small animals
to make it profitable.
Your sister, Hedwig.
Our good little daughter
should get the gold bracelet.
On the evening of May 20
we were sitting on the terrace,
playing cards and listening to the news.
Someone honked loudly.
”Who has the nerve to do that?”
we wondered.
It was Daddy.
We spent three nights together.
Puppi was ecstatic.
Daddy brought us plenty of fruit,
vegetables, and 150 tulips.
They were striped and jagged,
in two colors.
Mommy showed Daddy the whole garden.
I hadn't seen Daddy
in civilian clothes for so long.
h' was beautiful.
Daddy left this morning.
Headquarters, July 1942.
I order the deportation
of the entire Jewish population
of the General Government.
As of December 31, 1942,
no one of Jewish origin
is allowed in the General Government.
These measures are necessary
for the reorganization of Europe
by its people's ethnic distinctions,
in the interest of safety
and cleanliness in the German Reich
and its areas of interest, as necessary.
Requests from other departments
for amendments and exceptions
must be submitted to me personally.
Heil Hitler.
Signed, H. Himmler.
We have taken the wealth they had.
Obviously, this wealth
was transferred to the Reich,
not to ourselves.
We have a moral right,
an obligation to our people,
to take the people who want to kill us
and kill them,
but We have no right
to enrich ourselves with a single fur,
a watch, a single mark,
a cigarette, or anything else.
August 10, 1942.
My dear Mommy, with the package
you will receive a short note.
The belt is for you.
The basket is for you.
You may like the silver tray,
the bowl, and the silk cloth
in black, blue and white,
and the blue handbag.
Our good little daughter should get
the gold bracelet and the sports dress.
A fur coat is on its way,
as is a cabinet and blue wool fabric.
With love. Yours, Heini.
Over the next few days I'll be in Lublin,
Zamosch, Auschwitz, Lemberg.
We were at the gates of Stalingrad,
and now we are behind Kiev.
What a difference.
There is a shortage of Weapons
and ammunition everywhere.
The air force is still terrible.
Goring cares about nothing.
That flashy guy.
Goebbels is doing a great deal,
but he is so condescending.
Soon I will be 50 years old.
I've experienced so much trouble.
The war has entered a serious stage.
Stalingrad was the warning sign.
What else is going to happen?
I believe in the fuhrer.
Our people are not supposed to die.
They won't,
even if the internal situation seems harsh.
We have no allies in Europe.
We are entirely on our own.
Just imagine what will happen if we lose.
Some high ranking officers
have already been killed.
If Daddy -
No, don't even imagine that.
My dear Mommy, a few quick lines.
Enclosed are two packages
and a piece of fruitcake.
Over the next few days
I will be in Lublin, Zamosch,
Auschwitz and Lemberg.
I wonder if I will be able to call.
I'll be around 2,000 km from Gmund.
All my love. Have good days
in Gmund with our dear daughter.
Many warm greetings and kisses.
Yours, Daddy.
Dear party member Himmler,
in the wake of my visit
to the Auschwitz camp,
I am willing to allocate the following
on a one-time basis only:
1,000 tons of structural steel,
about 100 tons of water pipe.
This steel is for the expansion
of the concentration camps only,
Auschwitz in particular.
Heil Hitler!
Yours, Speer.
Dear party comrade Speer,
thank you very much for your letter
and for the allocation
of additional amounts of steel,
particularly for the expansion
of the Auschwitz camp.
Your words have strengthened
my conviction
that there is still justice in the world.
Heil Hitler!
Yours, H. Himmler.
My dear husband,
there were air raids.
Thank you.
Please order at least
four food coupons for us.
We are entitled to them.
We have alarms almost every day,
once every four hours.
Here is a silver stripe
which fell into our garden in Munich
during the last air strike.
Everyone is getting medals and decorations,
except for Daddy.
He should be the first to get one.
If not for him,
so much would be different.
Dear Mommy,
I always feel sorry
when I sleep well
and hear in the morning
that there were air strikes.
The food coupons are included.
Be assured, all will be fine.
I'm working more than ever.
Try to recuperate,
you and our dear daughter.
Lots of love and kisses.
Yours, Daddy.
But everyone believes
firmly in victory (Daddy).
June 1944.
The invasion started
on the night of the 5th
in Normandy, by the Channel.
We have already given up Cherbourg.
The Russians
want to take over the Baltic Sea.
The way they treat people is unspeakable.
Dear party member Gieseler,
I am definitely not the anxious type.
Still, I decided
to build the bunker in Gmund.
I believe it may be that the enemy,
who knows the location of our houses,
will launch an air strike
in order to destroy the house
with its residents,
including me.
I highly appreciate the fact
that you abandoned all formalities to help me.
I express my deepest gratitude.
With regards and Heil Hitler.
Yours, H. Himmler.
FOR FREEDOM AND LIFE
PEOPLE'S ARMY
A telegram came yesterday.
A place was found for Gerhard.
Whether he can come by
before he is sent to the front is questionable.
He is very brave
and likes it' in the SS in Brunn.
I think he has become nicer.
The fuhrer cannot believe
that the German soldier
doesn't want to flight anymore.
Daddy believes firmly in our victory.
It is impossible to imagine
that we could lose the war.
Whenever the situation gets serious,
he needs to help.
All of Germany is looking up to him.
Yet he is happy and in good spirits
when he calls.
My dear, good Mommy.
My dearest Puppi.
Despite the overwhelming
and severe situation,
I am convinced we will win.
I am attaching a beautiful poem
called Redemption.
Puppi should read it too.
Redemption.
From the Metz Cathedral,
it echoed four times from the clock tower.
Redemption.
Redeemed is the ancient,
the old mighty imperial sword.
Germany again holds sway,
the respect you once held.
Redemption,
and the German resumes his old post.
The evening mist still glimmers in the west.
On the Moselle, day breaks in the east.
And the future, German people, is yours.
SURRENDER?
NO
Baumert wanted to persuade Mom
to go to Valepp under a false name.
Wherever we go
must be kept completely secret.
I'm still here because Heini wants it.
I worry about my work and my reputation.
If you don't perform your duty
in the face of danger,
people despise you, and they're right.
Today I stayed in bed until noon.
Mommy doesn't like it when I lie down,
but I still do it anyway.
There is a lot going on in the world,
and especially at home.
In brief,
on the 24th in the evening.
April 17, 1945.
My love, dear Mommy.
My love, dear Daughter.
Mr. Baumert is driving down
so I have the chance to send you this letter.
He will tell Mommy a lot in person.
Still, he should bring a note
with this little package.
Times are tremendously hard
for all of us and yet,
it will, I firmly believe,
still turn out right.
But it is hard.
You, my loved ones, stay healthy.
The Ancient One will protect us,
especially the good German nation.
He will not lea' us fall.
I am sending you, my beloved Mommy,
and you, Puppi, my dear,
much love, kisses and greetings.
Heil Hitler.
With love. Yours, Daddy.
I think, gentlemen,
that you know me long enough
to know that I am not a bloodthirsty man
and not someone who
takes pleasure in difficult duties.
But on the other hand,
I have such strong nerves
and such a great sense of duty,
I might say,
that when I recognize something
as being essential,
I execute it without compromise.
Most of you will know
What it means
when a hundred corpses lie side by side,
whether there are 500 or 1,000.
And...
to endure that
and, apart from a few exceptions,
to remain decent,
has made us tough,
but it is never mentioned,
and will never appear
in the glorious annals of history.
We can have but one desire
as to what is said about us.
These German officers,
these German soldiers,
these German generals,
they were decent.
I think that for the camps,
it was my husband.
Sure. We talked about the war.
No, never.
No. We never talked about that.
Well, I knew nothing about it.
I don 't know.