HIDDEN DIARY
Audrey!
Are you well?
Your mother couldn't come.
- A pleasant journey?
- Yes.
You look wonderful.
Martine Laurencin
General practitioner
- Everything ok?
- Fine.
- Is Audrey here?
- Yes, she's out in the garden.
What have you made for dinner?
Hold on, l just finished work!
- Ok, forget it.
- l'll go out.
l hurried things up.
Had a good journey?
You must be tired.
No, l slept on the plane.
- Longer hair suits you.
- Thanks.
He's a funny dog.
Yes, he's young.
l took your things up
to your room.
Thank you.
Here we are...
lf you had told us
that you were coming
a little sooner
we'd have taken time off.
lt's a miracle
l managed to get away.
But l have to work too.
- To your visit!
- Can't you take 10 days off
No, just before l lea,
they gave me a great project.
l'd have cancelled.
l didn't want to.
l wanted to see you.
This is for you both.
l don't take photos.
Your father can have it.
ls it a digital one?
Yes, it's very easy to use.
The definition is wonderful.
l don't understand a word.
You could take photos
of the garden. It's beautiful.
The garden's your mother.
No, if you feed him,
we'll never get any peace.
l can't believe that...
That's enough!
No, Tiger, come here!
Michel, you could
try training him.
We could have him put down too.
- You can't sleep?
- No.
- Want a sleeping pill?
- No thanks.
Everything ok?
l can't concentrate in my room.
There's a lot of bronchitis about.
l passed Grand dad's house earlier.
It's empty, isn't it?
lt's uninhabitable.
l can't get anything done here.
You just got here!
Relax for a couple of days,
then get back to your work.
You always asked me
to go to Granddad's with you,
as if to avoid being
alone with him.
l took you
because he wanted to see you.
He was fond of you.
He always asked about you.
You know that.
So he'd be happy to see me
in his house.
l couldn't come to the funeral.
l really couldn't get away
and I’m sorry that l wasn't with you.
I’ve worked a lot
these last for years. Sorry.
This wasn't planned either.
The engineer just found
a clever way
to save even more water.
lt's a really great project.
Sorry, but l need quiet.
You sound like an old maid.
Right, l'll get back to work.
The keys are in the kitchen,
the ring with Tintin's rocket.
- We'll deliver tomorrow.
- Thank you.
You scared me!
Aren't you working?
Yes, but l close at seven.
lt's already seven?
l haven't stopped.
l came to see
if you were comfortable.
You don't waste time.
- Want a coffee?
- No thanks.
Will you have room to work?
Are you making fun?
No, I’m glad to see
someone living here.
Even if l'd prefer to see you
staying with us.
ls life good?
Of course. Why?
l don't know.
You seem like
you want to avoid us.
Got problems?
Not at all.
l came here to see you, l swear.
But l have to work too,
make phone calls at night...
I’ve been in Toronto 10 years
and you've never been over.
lf it were up to me,
we'd have come long ago.
lf you insisted,
maybe she'd fly for once.
No, l don't think so.
Last year, l got us tickets
to go to Florence by train.
At the last minute,
l found her sitting next to
her bag, refusing to leave.
With her father's illness,
even going to Bordeaux
stressed her.
Apart from work,
nothing interests her.
- You can't leave it here!
- Suzanne...
Don't shout.
It's a delivery for me.
Hello. l won't take long.
l couldn't have known.
lt holds for you too, you know.
Parking here
is strictly forbidden.
All right.
Mind out.
This is no good at all.
There's no hook-up.
The pipes need changing.
The dish washer
was a bad idea then.
lt'll take years to redo it,
right?
lt's a day's work for a plumber.
l could try to help out
but this needs a professional.
Thank you. l'll manage.
I’m sorry.
Let's go.
Roast pork with prunes
A new school year
Suzanne, thank you for the fruit.
There's far too much of it for me.
And l prefer to pick it
before the birds gorge on it.
lf someone can use it...
That's kind.
You live in America, l hear?
ln Canada.
Quite a success.
Do you want some sugar?
No.
lt's nice to have family photos.
I’ve always liked them.
My parents have taken very few
and l think my grandfather
burnt his after his wife leave.
l don't know what he did.
You and Louise were neighbours.
Maybe you didn't talk much?
We'd say hello.
No one's ever told me much
about her.
All my mother told me
is that she leave just after
a new kitchen was put in for her.
That's possible.
He used to spoil her so much.
He loved her, l think.
Do you know why she leave?
No.
She certainly was rather distant.
She was a beautiful woman.
She came
from a very modest background
and marrying your grandfather was
a wonderful opportunity for her.
He'd make her outfits...
You should have seen them.
l often wondered
what could have become of her.
lt was rare
to see someone leave like that.
''The new kitchen has been made.
''lf only he could understand me,
''_e re_sesto Jet me work.
I hate him for it.
''A fee_in9 ofemptinen.''
''Gilles has omered me a suit,
a model copied
mom a Dior design,''
''There is dangerous,
it makes my head spin,''
''My darlings,
''I’ve decided to go away
for a while
''to think...''
''My loves, I’m leaving this house,
l feel so bad...''
''My darling children,
I’m going away or a whole
''to try to find a new life
where we will be happy at last.''
''A mother isn't necessary happy
''with the father ofher children.
''That doesn't mean she isn't happy
with her children,''
Let's see... StuMng...
A quarter pound
of father bacon...
A quarter pound of father bacon...
Hello.
Goodbye, doctor. Thank you.
- l just wanted a quick word.
- Come in.
- Are you well?
- Yes, very well.
Just a second...
l just told a woman she has cancer.
And l have patients with nothing
who moan all day long.
They're more depressing.
They confide in you.
It's important for them.
Sometimes l get tired
of all this misey.
Have you managed to rest a little?
A little.
You look a bit off-colour.
Yes, l worked late.
ls it going well?
Slowly.
Your skin is blotchy.
Do you use sunscreen?
Yes, always.
At your age, you should be
more careful. Here.
Thank you.
Come to dinner tonight.
Not tonight.
We're going to my brother's.
l said you might come.
They'd like to see you.
Why don't you all come over?
The least l can do
is invite Gérard, right?
You're impossible...
''Chop half pound of a liver
''and a quarter pound
of bacon.''
''Put the bacon and liver
in a lime boiling stock,
''Boil it for 5 minutes.''
''Chop neatly and place
the mixture in a mortar.''
lt's us!
Thank you.
- You're alone?
- Mum's on the beach.
- They're not here yet?
- No.
They won't be long.
l just put the duck in the oven.
Duck...
l found an old recipe book
that belonged to Louise.
Really?
lt's a sort of diay too.
Maybe l should give it to them.
No, l don't think
that would be a good idea.
Your grandfather's death
upset your mother
and l don't think this is the time
to remind her of Louise.
- How's the shop doing?
- Fine.
lt's a pain when people buy
more ugly pairs of specs
instead of one
but l have loyal customers.
Your friend Samira
came to see me today.
Really?
She has lovely daughters.
Sorry.
Audrey, don't move!
lt's so beautiful!
Hurry, we'll be late
for mass again!
A photo!
A photo, please!
Come on, children.
Smile, Martine, please.
Martine, please,
we haven't much time.
Ok, let's go.
That'll do, won't it?
That smells so good!
lt's a fairly old recipe.
Does it remind you of anything?
No.
What's this dishwasher?
- It doesn't work?
- No.
You messed the kitchen up
to put this in?
The plumbing's rotten.
l can't hook it up.
And you need a dishwasher
just for you?
l wanted to improve the kitchen.
The layout is perfect.
lt just needs
some modern appliances.
l don't want you
touching anything here.
lt's a hand-embroidered cloth,
we can't use it.
Want to hang it on a wall?
Help me
instead of contradicting me.
Martine, Cédric got his diploma.
He had good marks.
The Grand Hotel has taken him on.
Really?
Tell me, Audrey...
- Do you have someone?
- Me?
No.
A man or a woman
can blossom alone.
Nonsense.
You know, Audrey,
l met my wife
at the age of 40.
For years l drifted
from one affair to another
until the right person came along...
And she's the right person!
Until the day you're ready,
when desire wins.
l'd had my eye on him for years.
But he was so way of women.
His mother abandoning him
didn't help.
Let's finish setting the table.
She was brave to leave like that.
lt was a real scandal.
Our mother didn't agree
because she was heartless,
not to be free.
A mother doesn’t just abandon her kids.
She has to be crazy.
l think she love for a man.
lt devastated her husband.
You didn't get over it back then.
Maybe.
lt's delicious.
lt's duck 'a la paulus'.
Here's to Audrey...
for coming to see us.
Thank you.
Here's to you
and to freedom for women...
And to Paulus!
We can talk normally at this table
for once.
As kids, we weren't
allowed to say a word.
Could you at least
respect Dad's memory
in his own home?
Say what you like elsewhere.
He's not doing anything, Martine,
he's not saying anything.
Do you like the Grand Hotel,
Cédric?
Yeah.
Yes, congratulations.
His money helped set up
your restaurant.
Admit that at least.
Cut it out, Martine,
it wasn't easy
accepting that money.
l only took it because the bank
refused our loan.
He ended up giving me
a little cash.
l was almost 40 then.
l don't hassle you
about the house.
lt's good Audrey's here.
No one uses it otherwise.
lf it's empty year round,
it will deteriorate.
We agreed we wouldn't sell it.
Maybe we could decide
to do it up and rent it out.
Yes, it needs a little work.
Who can afford it?
We can always sell the furniture.
l'd rather sell the house instead!
Whatever, l don't care.
That's settled then.
More duck, anyone?
Cédric, you could
bring friends here this summer.
And enjoy all night!
Sorry, l have a headache.
I’m going home.
Martine, listen...
Darling...
Mum, you can’t just leave.
Enough. You're starting
to get on my nerves!
lt's delicious, Louise.
Too bad you don't cook more oAen.
He won't let me help at the shop.
He won't let me work.
Soon, he won't let me speak.
These models are lovely. Look.
This suit is gorgeous, isn't it?
Use it as inspiration.
You know what l'd like, Gilles?
To help at the shop,
I work behind the counter
receive the customers,
choose the fabrics with you...
Many couples run shops.
l'll make this model for you.
l hear that in big cities,
a woman doesn’t always need
her husband's perminion to work.
Thank you.
You've lost weight.
Forgive me.
Still no kids yet?
No.
This world's too harsh.
I’m not brave enough.
Are you afraid of
being alone later?
No, I’ve never thought of that.
l hadn't thought of it either.
But after Paul went away,
l realized that l had my daughters
and they had me
and that we were strong together.
lt's silly.
No, l understand.
I’m pregnant.
I’m mo months gone.
I’m totally lost.
Only natural.
It's such a weird condition.
But once the baby's there,
you'll wonder
why you waited so long.
Personally,
l'd have had more
if my man hadn't walked out.
l wish l could be that simple.
First off, I’m not simple.
And why is it
more complicated for you?
Without my work, I’m lost.
I’m horribly self-centered.
And the father?
We're not together.
He's just a friend..
- Is he married?
- No.
To be honest,
I’m not made for this.
And neither is he.
''Night is too short.
And what if l abandoned it''
''This sniveling baby''
A Japanese poem l came across
just before leaving.
lt gets easier
after the first months.
We're hungry, Mum, we're going.
All right,
give me a minute or mo.
They're waiting.
Keep in touch.
Got all your things?
l'd like Martine to study,
to get an education.
She has to learn.
She’s so stubborn, she can succeed.
I'd like her to be me.''
Women have always worked
in my family, even for a pimance,
ls that Dad's dress?
Yes. So?
You don't wear it to the beach.
You don't know anything.
You're mad!
Don't talk to your mother
like that!
You hurt me.
You have such a character...
A character like that
will take you far.
What does that mean?
You can study, work,
fulfill yourself. It's important.
You have to study, Martine.
You too, Gérard,
but it's easier for boys.
You're a good student.
You have to carry on like that.
You promise?
Yes.
People are so disgusting.
A few weeks back
l found a pair of bride.
Can you believe it?
Come in for coffee. l have decaf.
Back when she was around,
l never had much opportunity
to come in here.
That's right.
She had a camera.
She had even decided
she wanted to be an assistant
to Mr. Lebedel, the photographer.
The fuss that caused!
She had an affair, you mean?
She spent a lot of time there
but no one really knew.
But people talked.
First, it was photography,
then English lessons...
A woman like that
is a real plague...
She was learning English?
l think so.
She went by bus. That wasn't done.
Can you say,
''He's gone for a walk''?
Of course.
You can't say it!
- l can.
- You can't.
That's not the right word.
You can't say it.
l'd like a word.
l can't let you go
to your lessons by bus.
You don't trust me?
l do.
But my customers gossip.
They're real chatter boxes.
l can't lose custom
because of your English lessons.
l just can't.
l understand.
You didn't continue?
No.
l took up photography,
more or less by chance.
lt's for my husband.
He wants a photo for his shop.
l can see why.
lt's hard being away from
a pretty wife.
ls a camera like this expensive?
Yes, fairly expensive.
But l can lend you one
if you want.
l could never accept.
l can even teach you the basics.
The look on your face...
lt was a big funeral.
He was very popular.
He was a good tailor.
This plant matches the stone.
We chose pink granite.
lt's brighter than black.
Yes, it's more colourful.
What's wrong?
lt's the heat.
Have you called a plumber
about the dishwasher?
A plumber, you mean.
He's busy until next week.
That's the problem.
Everything's so complicated.
And they complain about the Poles!
What Poles?
lt's funny, this old love of yours
for kitchen things.
You always said technical progress
had helped to liberate women.
You had
all the housewife's paraphernalia.
You used to call it your dowry.
l may have it
stored away somewhere.
When Granddad died,
did Louise get in touch?
What are you saying?
Hold on.
We'll put them on this.
It's handier.
She could have...
What?
Come back.
That's absurd!
Didn't you find anything
in the house?
Your grandfather threw
her things out when she lea.
Audrey, you're annoying me.
Why bring this up again?
Thanks.
I’ve found an exercise book,
with rough copies of letters
and things she wrote
about herself,
about you, about her life...
Really?
- Do you want to see it?
- No.
You're not interested?
No, but l think Evelyne will love it.
l found it in the kitchen,
behind a dresser.
She wasn't as insensitive
as you think.
l don't care. She lea.
It's not my problem now.
ls that why you're at the house?
To nose around...
You should look to the future.
At this rate,
you'll end up alone and that
really upsets me, you know.
l came across it by chance.
You can spend your life
Looking back.
Time stretches out to infinity...
What will it get you?
- Are you still in therapy?
- No.
You're making progress.
That's good.
l'll start again after this.
To go and cy some more
about your wicked mother
who preferred her patients
to her daughter?
You enjoy that?
Wallowing in misery...
Why do you attack me?
It's unbearable.
You're the one
always looking for a flight!
l can see you can't stand me.
I’m not blind!
lt's not that, Mum, but it's tiring
being unable to talk normally.
l come home and l can tell
everything's a problem.
Being in the house annoys you!
lf l buy stuff to make you happy,
that annoys you!
Dinner annoys you,
even the table cloth!
Everything! It's all wrong!
l cross half the world to see you
but you're still as hard
and authoritarian.
It's a real pain!
You're incredible!
l can't believe I’m hearing this
from a daughter who abandoned me.
You're insane!
No wonder you're alone.
Who'd put up with you?
Okay, I’m going.
l think it's for the best.
We've never got along anyway.
You've always held me responsible
always blamed me!
lt wasn't easy moving so far away.
lt was an opportunity.
l took it and l don't regret it.
You didn't decide my life.
It doesn't revolve around you.
Your mother leaved
because her life was killing her.
Not because of you.
Guilt is just a human emotion.
l don't consider you guilty.
l feel guilty too but
you've never given me any choice.
The same again?
No, thank you.
Could you pay then?
I’m finishing my shier.
Yes, of course.
Thank you.
What are you looking for?
A dress for Mum.
l haven't seen her for a while.
l don't really know
what she'd like.
This one's different.
It would suit her.
You think so?
With the Eiffel Tower...
She hates big cities.
She never likes my gift anyway.
So treat yourself instead.
l'd like to make her happy one day.
l don't want to get it wrong.
lt's beautiful.
Do you have any looser clothes
that a pregnant woman could wear?
Here, try this.
Thanks.
Even as a girl,
it was hard making her happy.
She was sad to see me unhappy
and its didn't help.
Why didn't you come back?
To cancelled it all out
to start a new?
No, forgetting was impossible.
But staying wasn't possible either.
Your mother never forgave me.
l think l'd have to leave too.
l tried to reason with myself.
You don't need to flee.
You're free.
Me? It's different for me.
I’m scared.
l'll just take the dress.
Are you ok, Audrey?
l feel a bit weird.
You have a really pretty shop.
No one tells me
what to put in my window.
l work with young designers,
l try to support them
and there's a market for it.
The prices are the problem.
We can't compete with
the chain stores.
My grandfather
thought like that too.
He tried to resist ready-to-wear,
he worked all the time...
Hi.
How are you?
Great, thanks.
Who's that?
A sort of cousin.
She lives in America.
How do you mean, sort opt
She's Gérard's sister's daughter.
She's loaded but she's still single.
She's kind of weird.
She's a beautiful woman anyhow.
Have a good evening.
The look on your faces!
There was no letter when she leave?
No.
- Can l keep this?
- Of course.
What is it?
Old recipes...
ls Martine ok?
Yes, l think so.
Your mother's so tough.
She chills my blood.
But l hear she's a good doctor...
Yes.
- Can l keep it?
- l just said you could.
lf only l could do something
to make my children proud.
I like to know, like those women
whose books l read.
They're intelligent
and independent.
My life is at home,
I’m not even a good housewife.
Other women seem happy.
They smile in any case,
Gérard has grown a lot lately.
Martine too.
My daughter is as reactionary
as the others.
She judges me and hates me,
Me-too, end up hating her.
She defends her father against me,
My loves, I’m leaving this house,
l feel so bad.
My darling children,
I’m going away for a while
to try to find a new life
where we will be happy at last.
l would like some tomatoes.
These aren't bad.
The trouble starts when you
hesitate bemeen mo pairs.
Sorry.
That's right. Unless...
l think these are ideal for you.
Try them on again.
They're both serious and playful.
intelligent glasses.
I’m not saying she has an excuse
but you're being a pain too.
Why? Is tying to find out wrong?
Her mother walked out
50 years ago. What of it?
Why pester her?
I’m sure she knows stuff.
Why are you so obsessed by Louise?
Because she was a mother
yet leave anyway?
So you think your mother
hasn't been maternal enough
and so on...
You're starting to piss me off
with all this.
Because...
if her father had leave,
no one would have given a damn!
What are you so upset about?
No one gives a damn
about the father!
l stayed at home
while your mother worked.
l cooked for you,
l helped you with your homework...
You've forgotten all that.
The father doesn't count.
Even having a kid without a father
wouldn't be a problem for you,
l bet.
What are you talking about?
You're pregnant, right?
Look at the state you're in.
Your mother has realized.
You turn up here and say nothing.
We have to bring things to a head
to find out a little about your life
and what you're going through.
Personally,
I’m hurt that you haven't told us.
Something smells good.
lt's a new recipe.
You're turning into
a real cordon bleu
in your new kitchen.
Gilles.
Things are getting better.
l feel good, l keep busy...
But...l'd like my own bank account.
What for?
You spoil me
but l was a bit short yesterday
and l hate having to ask
each time.
l manage the budget well
and l'd like to have
my own account
but l need your agreement.
l'll think about it.
l could give you surprises too.
l'd like to be able to spoil you.
What l'd really like
is to see you have friends round
and organize gatherings,
the way other wives do.
We have a beautiful home,
you should be proud of it.
You're right.
She writes well
for someone without an education.
That's true.
But what she says is so sad.
She shouldn't have married him.
But we can't help that.
isn’t it odd
that she lea without it?
And without the money?
She was probably upset
and forgot it.
What could this money be?
She probably had money
for the week.
Money to do the shopping...
This is too much.
Have you shown your mother?
She doesn't want to know.
l understand that.
Martine suffered a lot over it.
No more than you.
l was younger.
l guess she protected me.
She was a second mother to me.
ln my memories,
they merge together.
Was Louise hard with you?
No.
She was tender
but she was sad too.
But may be l imagined her
as being sad
After she leave.
The way she writes...
l tried to find her.
l went to the cops, in vain.
Certain songs make me
think of her now.
She dressed well.
She always dressed well,
l remember.
l found her beautiful.
lt doesn't matter, dear.
Hurry up now.
Let's get to work.
- Hello, madam.
- Hello.
l'd like to empty my account
to buy my husband a new car.
The whole amount?
Yes, please.
He's dreamt of it for so long.
- Can you give me a minute?
- Of course.
l handle such amounts myself.
l understand. Thank you.
You went to the bank?
l wanted to buy you a new car.
What an idiot l was to trust you.
Leave this house now, Louise.
Leave immediately.
You're not happy,
you want to work,
so leave.
Keep the money.
But never try to come back,
you hear.
l don't want to see you again.
l'll demand custody
of the children.
l won't let you take my children.
You're incapable of
Looking after them.
You're right.
Maybe they're better
with you for now.
I’m really sorry.
l'll get some napkins.
lt's all right.
I’m soaked but it's all right.
Do you want to borrow a sweater?
Yes, please.
Thank you.
lt's sweet of you.
Don't worry, it doesn't matter.
You're really kind too.
l could lose my job over this.
Shall l get you another?
No, thank you, l have to go.
l'll bring your sweater back.
lf l forget, I’m on Avenue
de la Mer, number 15.
- Are you married?
- No.
- You don't have a guy?
Your skin's so soft.
You smell good.
l'd like it to be functional,
for a reasonable price.
Good morning.
l rang the bell.
l thought you'd gone out.
No, l was sleeping.
lt's late to be getting up.
I’m resting. l need it.
- We won't be long.
- Take as long as you like.
Changing the kitchen?
l know you like it
but if we may do it
along with the plumbing.
- You spoke to Gérard about it?
- No.
Evelyne decides.
Their place is absolutely hideous.
You're renting it out?
This house causes
no end of needless tension.
We'll do it up and then we'll see.
Don't tell my brother.
l'll pay for it.
- You should let him know.
- Yes.
l think l have everything.
l'll send you an estimate.
See you soon.
Goodbye.
- Are you well?
- Yes.
The work won’t begin right away.
When are you leaving?
ln mo days.
- You must be pleased.
- Why?
lt's natural to be pleased
to be going home.
l'll go now.
l have something for you.
l hope you'll like it.
Thank you.
Shall l open it?
Maybe not.
Right...
lt's silly,
l forgot it in the car.
Thank you...
Right, l'll let you work.
ls something wrong?
No, not at all.
But l have a lot to do
and you have your consultations.
No, I’m free all day.
What's wrong?
I’m bleeding.
- A lot?
- A little.
All right, that can happen.
Don't panic
but it's best to check.
Get dressed. l'll wait for you.
Everything's fine.
Thanks for taking me.
l feared it might be
an entopic pregnancy.
You lose the fetus
and you end up in hospital.
lt can leave you sterile too.
We can be happy it's not that.
l feel so tired, Mum.
Don't move. What do you need?
l'd like my thick sweater.
It's up in my room.
Dad?
What time is it?
Yes, she was with me.
l don't know. l fell asleep.
Where did you find it?
Behind the kitchen dresser.
lt's Dad.
He's looking all over for you.
Yes.
Everything's fine.
l won't be long.
Are you ok, Mum?
Just leave me alone now.
Yes, Mum.
What's happening?
Where are you?
You know, Audrey, I’ve tried...
to pass on a taste for freedom
to you.
lt's what my mother wanted too.
When Gérard and l went anywhere,
people would whisper about us.
l became hardened.
l wanted them to know
we were managing without her.
But, inside, l tried to be someone
she could be proud of.
l also wanted you to be strong,
independent...
Mum, why did she leave the money?
Why did she leave it?
l don't know.
He called her a thief,
said she took his money...
But she didn't take it.
He said she had vanished,
that he'd looked for her...
But he didn't call the police
and her family
didn't hear from her either.
He should have called the police.
He said he'd looked for her
all day.
But why did he look for her
since her suitcase was
in her room?
What suitcase?
When Gérard and l
got home from school,
the door wasn't locked.
There was no one home
but the door was unlocked.
lt was Suzanne's son's
birthday party
but l didn't want us to go.
l was ashamed
my mother wasn't there.
l felt so ashamed of her.
l thought that she might be
asleep, so l went to their room.
The suitcase was there
with her things.
isn’t it strange
she took nothing with her?
Without a word
and without taking anything.
l was in the kitchen.
My father got home late.
He seemed very odd.
He said she'd robbed him.
He asked why l wasn't in bed.
He didn't ask
if she had come back.
He was filthy,
covered in mud...
He had dirt on his hands.
They were filthy.
And his eyes...
scared me.
He looked mad.
The next morning,
he said she'd called...
to say she wouldn't be back.
And he burnt all her things.
We have nothing.
l didn't lie to you,
we have nothing of hers.
He took the secret to his grave.
- Walk me home.
- Of course, Mum.
- Martine, what's wrong?
- Nothing. Nothing's wrong.
What happened?
He killed her.
Gilles killed Louise.
That's not possible...
You should go up and see Mum.
Want to sleep here?
No, l'd rather go back.
Her blood pressure is low.
Make sure she eats
and stays nearby.
All right.
At first, he was always barking
and never obeyed.
You've trained him well.
l haven't finished yet
but I’m pleased with him.
She's strong, you know.
l won't take them.
They ease the pain.
I’m just tired.
l had considered it, of course.
Not seriously.
ln any case,
he never mentioned her.
We can never prove it anyway.
l'd never seen
my sister cry before.
l have to be going.
Love to Evelyne.
All right.
Mum, it's me. Can l come in?
Yes.
Let me help.
- Has Gérard gone?
- Yes.
He's gone to work.
Evelyne will worry.
lf he's away more than an hour,
she gets frantic.
l'll lock the house up.
I’m going to stay here a while.
You see, she put the dress on.